[音乐播放]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
大卫·J·马兰：好的
DAVID J. MALAN: All right.
这是CS50的S介绍用PYTHON编程
This is CS50'S Introduction to Programming with Python.
我叫大卫·马兰
My name is David Malan.
在过去的许多周里 我们专注于
And over these past many weeks have we focused
关于函数和变量 然后是条件句和循环
on functions and variables early on, then conditionals, and loops,
和异常、一些库、单元测试文件
and exceptions, a bit of libraries, unit test file
布局、正则表达式、面向对象编程
layout, regular expressions, object-oriented programming,
真的 诸如此类
and really, et cetera.
事实上 这就是我们今天关注的地方
And indeed, that's where we focus today, is
关于您可以使用Python和编程做的更多事情
on all the more that you can do with Python and programming
更广泛地说 也超出了这些基本概念中的一些
more generally beyond some of those fundamental concepts as well.
事实上 如果您开始浏览有关Python的文档
In fact, if you start to flip through the documentation for Python
以及它的所有形式 所有这些形式都可以在docs.python.org上访问
and all of its form, all of which is as always accessible at docs.python.org,
您将看到有关Python自己的教程和库的其他文档
you'll see additional documentation on Python's own tutorial and library,
它的参考 它的使用方法
its reference, its how-to.
在所有这些不同的文档以及其他更多的在线文档中
And among all of those various documents as well as others more online,
你会看到有一些我们没有完全触及的花边新闻
you'll see that there's some tidbits that we didn't quite touch on.
事实上 尽管我们在过去的几周里
And indeed, even though we themed these past several weeks
围绕着相当广泛的主题 这些主题对做
of around fairly broad topics that are rather essential for doing
事实证明 Python中的典型问题类型
typical types of problems in Python, it turns out
还有相当多的其他功能 我们不一定
there's quite a number of other features as well, that we didn't necessarily
涉及到 这不一定适合在任何
touch on, that didn't necessarily fit within any
这些首要概念 或者可能有
of those overarching concepts, or might have
如果我们在课程太早的时候做 那就有点太早了
been a little too much too soon if we did them too early on in the course.
所以 在今天 我们的最后一堂课 嗯 我们
And so, in today, our final lecture, well, we
真正关注您可以使用Python做的更多事情
focus really on all the more that you can do with Python
希望能激发你自学的胃口
and hopefully whet your appetite for teaching yourself all the more to.
例如 在Python的各种数据类型中
For instance, among Python's various data types,
还有另一个我们还没有机会使用的 那就是一套
there's this other one that we haven't had occasion to yet use, namely, a set.
在数学中 集合通常是值的集合
In mathematics, a set is typically a collection of values
其中没有复制品
wherein there are no duplicates.
所以这并不是一份完整的清单
So it's not quite a list.
它比那更特别一点 因为不知何故 任何复制品都是
It's a bit more special than that in that somehow any duplicates are
为你淘汰了
eliminated for you.
实际上 在Python中 这是一种实际的数据类型
Well, it turns out within Python, this is an actual data type
您自己可以在代码中使用的
that you yourself can use in your code.
通过这里的文档 您是否可以
And via the documentation here, might you
能够发现这是一个有用的问题
be able to glean that it's a useful problem
如果您想以某种方式自动过滤掉重复项
if you want to somehow automatically filter out duplicates.
所以让我继续 转到VS代码这里
So let me go ahead and go over to VS Code here.
让我继续向你们展示一个我之前创建的文件
And let me go ahead and show you a file that I created a bit of in advance,
我们在这里有一个名为house.py的文件
whereby we have a file here called houses.py.
在House.py中 我已经开始准备了
And in houses.py, I already went ahead and whipped up
其中的一大份学生名单是
a big list of students inside of which is
一些词典 每本词典代表一个学生的名字
a number of dictionaries, each of which represents a student's name
和豪斯分别
and house respectively.
现在 这是一本相当大的词典
Now, this is a pretty sizable dictionary.
因此 它适合于对相同的东西进行迭代
And so, it lends itself to iteration over the same.
假设这里的目标很简单 就是找出
And suppose that the goal here was quite simply to figure out,
那么 在哈利波特的世界里 霍格沃茨有哪些独特的房子呢？
well, what are the unique houses at Hogwarts in the world of Harry Potter?
也许 如果不需要知道这些细节就好了
It would be nice, perhaps, to not have to know these kinds of details
或者上网查一查
or look them up online.
在这里 我们有一组学生 尽管不是详尽的 所有的房子
Here we have a set of students, albeit not exhaustive, with all of the houses.
但是 在这些在座的学生中 他们居住的独特的房子是什么？
But among these students here, what are the unique houses in which they live?
嗯 我当然可以 作为一个人 看看这个
Well, I could certainly, as a human, just eyeball this
告诉你 是格兰芬多、斯莱特林和拉文克劳
and tell you that it's, well, Gryffindor, Slytherin, and Ravenclaw.
但是我们如何才能开始为这些学生编程呢？
But how can we go about doing it programmatically for these students
也是?
as well?
那么 让我们先采取一种方法
Well, let's take one approach first here.
让我到房子里去
Let me go into houses.py.
让我提议我们首先创建一个空名单怎么样
And let me propose that we first how about create an empty list
所谓的房子 我将在其中唯一地积累每一所房子
called houses in which I'm going to accumulate each of the houses uniquely.
所以每次我重复这一系列词典的时候
So every time I iterate through this list of dictionaries,
如果我以前没见过一栋房子 我才会把它加到这个名单上
I'm only going to add a house to this list if I haven't seen it before.
那么我该怎么表达呢？
So how do I express that?
好 让我重复一下所有的学生 在学生中
Well, let me iterate over all of the students with for student in students,
就像我们过去所做的那样
as we've done in the past.
现在让我问你一个问题
And let me ask you a question now.
所以如果现在学生的房子--
So if the current student's house--
注意我正在索引当前学生
and notice that I'm indexing into the current student
因为我知道它们是字典或字典对象
because I know they are a dictionary or dict object,
如果那个学生的房子不在我的房子名单上
and if that student's house is not in my house's list,
然后 缩进 我要说房子 附加
then, indented, am I going to say houses.append,
因为房子也是一个列表
because again, houses is a list.
我要把那栋房子加到名单上
And I'm going to append that particular house to the list.
在最下面 让我继续
Then at the very bottom here, let me go ahead
在这里做一些有趣的事情
and do something somewhat interesting here and say, for each of the houses
我可以说是房子
that I've accumulated in, I could just say houses.
但是如果我只说房子 那么一下子积累起来有什么意义呢？
But if I just say houses, what was the point of accumulating them all at once?
我可以循环做一遍
I could just do this whole thing in a loop.
我们至少去把那些房子分类吧
Let's at least go about and sort those houses
sorted 也就是按顺序进入字符串
with sorted, which is going to the strings alphabetically.
让我们继续打印每一栋房子
And let's go ahead therein and print each of the houses.
让我在我的终端窗口
Let me go ahead now in my terminal window
运行houses.py的Python并按Enter键
and run Python of houses.py and hit Enter.
这就是了
And there we have it.
格兰芬多 拉文克劳 斯莱特林按字母顺序排列
Gryffindor, Ravenclaw, Slytherin in alphabetical order,
即使在这上面的字典列表中
even though in the list of dictionaries up here,
从技术上讲 我们看到这些的顺序是格兰芬多 格兰芬多
technically the order in which we saw these was Gryffindor, Gryffindor,
格兰芬多 斯莱特林 拉文克劳
Gryffindor, Slytherin, Ravenclaw.
因此 我的代码似乎已经正确地对它们进行了排序
So indeed, my code seems to have sorted them properly.
所以这完全没问题
So this is perfectly fine.
这是解决这个问题的一种方法
And it's one way of solving this problem.
但事实证明 我们可以使用更多内置在Python语言中的东西
But it turns out we could use more that's built into the language Python
自己解决这个问题
to solve this problem ourself.
在这里我是在重新发明一个轮子 一个集合的概念
Here I'm rather reinventing a wheel, really the notion of a set
在那里重复的东西被我消除了
wherein duplicates are eliminated for me.
所以让我继续清理我的终端窗口
So let me go ahead and clear my terminal window
或者改变我在这里使用的对象类型
and perhaps change the type of object I'm using here.
而不是一个列表 这也可以写
Instead of a list, which could also be written
创建一个空列表 让我继续
like this to create an empty list, let me go ahead
并创建一个空集 借此我调用一个函数
and create an empty set, whereby I call a function called
它将返回Python中的某个对象
set that's going to return to me some object in Python
它表示集合的概念 其中重复项自动
that represents this notion of a set wherein duplicates are automatically
被淘汰了
eliminated.
现在 我可以收紧我的代码
And now, I can tighten up my code.
因为我自己不需要使用这个如果条件
Because I don't have to use this if condition myself.
我想我可以做这样的事情
I think I can just do something like this.
在我的循环中 让我来做房子
Inside of my loop, let me do houses.add.
所以它不是集合的追加 而是列表的追加
So it's not append for a set, it's append for a list.
但它是根据文档添加到一组中的
But it's add to a set per the documentation.
那么让我继续添加这个在校生的房子
Then let me go ahead and add this current student's house.
现在 我认为我的其余代码可以是相同的
And now, I think the rest of my code can be the same.
我现在信任的是在Python中设置的文档
I'm just now trusting per the documentation for set in Python
它会为我过滤掉重复的内容
that it's going to filter out duplicates for me.
我可以盲目地把这些房子都加到布景里
And I can just blindly add, add, add, add all of these houses to the set
任何已经在那里的复制品都将消失
and any duplicates already there will be gone.
Pythonofhoues.py并回车
Python of houses.py and Enter.
瞧 我们又回到了和这三个人的生意上
And voila, we're back in business with just those three there as well.
让我在这里暂停一下 看看现在是否有任何关于set的用法的问题
Let me pause here to see if there's any questions now on this use of set, which
只是您可以使用的另一种数据类型
is just another data type that's available to you,
您可以在以下情况下接触到的另一个类：
another class in the world of Python that you can reach for when
解决一些像这样的问题
solving some problem like this.
学生：我们如何在一组中找到一件物品
STUDENT: How can we locate an item in a set,
例如 在那一组中找到格兰芬多？
for example, find Gryffindor in that set?
大卫·J·马兰：你如何在一套中找到一件物品？
DAVID J. MALAN: How do you find an item in a set?
您可以使用与我们以前针对列表所做的非常相似的语法
You can use very similar syntax as we've done for a list before.
你可以像If Gryffindor in House Then那样使用语法
You can use syntax like if Gryffindor in houses then,
你可以按照这样的思路回答一个问题
and you can answer a question along those lines.
因此 您也可以使用in和not in以及类似的函数
So you can use in and not in and similar functions as well.
片场还有其他问题吗？
Other questions on set?
学生：看 如果你有一个相似的房子名字 会发生什么？
STUDENT: Look what happens if you have a similar house name?
比方说 可能不是斯莱特林 而是
Let's say instead of Slytherin, it is maybe
O而不是I 将循环For循环
an O instead of an I. Will the for loop loop
在房子名字里的每一个字母里吗？
throughout each of those letters in the house name?
大卫·J·马兰：它会比较这些字符串
DAVID J. MALAN: It would compare the strings.
所以如果斯莱特林不止一次出现 但
So if Slytherin appears more than once but is
略有拼写错误或大写 如果我没记错的话
slightly misspelled or capitalized, if I heard you right,
这些看起来像是截然不同的字符串
those would appear to be distinct strings.
所以你会在结果中得到两个版本的斯莱特林
So you would get both versions of Slytherin in the result.
然而 我们在过去已经看到了如何清理用户数据
However, we've seen in the past how we can clean up users' data
如果它确实可能会变得一团糟
if indeed it might be messy.
我们可以强制一切大写 或全部小写
We could force everything to uppercase, or everything to lowercase,
或者我们可以利用STR中内置的功能
or we could use capitalize the function built into strs,
或者是可以帮我们处理一些清理工作的书名
or title case that would handle some of the cleanup for us.
在本例中 因为数据不是来自使用输入的人类
In this case, because the data is not coming from humans using the input
函数 我提前写了代码 比较安全
function, I wrote the code in advance, it's safer
假设我把房子弄对了
to assume that I got the houses right.
但如果它来自用户 那么这绝对是一个风险
But that's absolutely a risk if it's coming from users.
请允许我将我们的注意力转回到其他一些功能上
Allow me to turn our attention back to some of the other features
在这里 如果我们进一步深入研究文档 我们可以在Python中利用它
here that we can leverage in Python if we dig further into the documentation
并阅读有关其功能的更多信息
and read up more on its features.
嗯 在一些语言中 有这样一个概念
Well, in some language, there's this notion
全局变量 因此您可以定义符合以下条件的变量
of global variables, whereby you can define a variable that's either
函数的局部性 正如我们多次看到的
local to a function, as we've seen many times,
或者 如果您将一个变量放在所有函数之外
or if you put a variable outside of all of your functions,
可能接近文件的顶部 这通常会
perhaps near the top of your file, that would generally
被认为是一个全局变量
be considered a global variable.
或者 在Python的世界中 它可能特定于模块
Or in the world of Python, it might be specific to the module.
但无论出于何种意图和目的 它都将针对给定的程序运行
But for all intents and purposes, it's going to behave for a given program
就好像它是全球性的一样
as though it is global.
然而 事实证明 如果你这样做
However, it turns out that if you do this
当你解决一些问题时 你有多种功能
when solving some problem down the line, whereby you have multiple functions
你确实有一个或多个在这些函数之外的变量
and you do have one or more variables that are outside of those functions,
您可能无法像您想象的那样轻松地更改这些变量
you might not be able to change those variables as easily as you might think.
所以 确实 让我回到VS代码这里
So indeed, let me go back to VS Code here.
稍后 我将继续创建一个新文件 如何
And in just a moment, I'm going to go ahead and create a new file, how about
名为ban.py
called bank.py.
让我们继续并实现银行的概念
Let's go ahead and implement the notion of a bank
在那里我们可以用各种形式存储像钱这样的东西
wherein we can store things like money in various forms.
让我继续做这件事
And let me go ahead and do this.
让我们继续并实现一个非常简单的银行
Let me go ahead and implement a very simple bank
这只是记录我的总余额 即美元或美分的数量
that simply keeps track of my total balance, the number of dollars or cents
或者我可能在这个银行里存的任何东西
or whatever I might be storing in this bank.
我将在顶部给自己一个称为Balance的变量 它
And I'm going to give myself a variable called balance at the top, which
是一个整数 设置为零
is an integer, a set to zero.
现在让我继续定义一个主要函数 就像我们经常做的那样
Now let me go ahead and define a main function as we often do.
在我的主要函数中 让我继续打印出来 引用引号
And inside of my main function, let me go ahead and print out, quote unquote,
余额 然后打印出余额本身的值
balance, and then print out the value of balance itself.
传递给印刷品 就像我们经常做的那样 不止一个论点 所以他们得到了
Passing to print, as we've often done, more than one argument so that they get
由一个空格隔开
separated by a single white space.
现在 既然我有一个主要的功能 真正的搭建舞台
And now, since I have a main function, really setting the stage
为了很快做更多有趣的事情 让我们
for doing more interesting things soon, let
如果这个文件的名字是这样的 我会继续做我们的惯例
me go ahead and do our usual if the name of this file
等于等于下划线Main 然后继续调用Main
equals equals underscore underscore main, then go ahead and call main.
这是一个非常短的程序 但它可能
So this is a terribly short program, but it's perhaps
代表您可能如何在Python中解决一些未来的问题
representative of how you might solve some future problem in Python.
这样你就有了一个主要功能 它最终会做
Whereby you have a main function that's going to eventually do
一些有趣的东西
some interesting stuff.
在文件的顶部 您有一个或多个变量
And at the top of your file, you have one or more variables
放在那里很有用 因为这样你就知道它们在哪里了
that are just useful to keep there because then you know where they are.
也许不只是Main 其他函数也可以访问它们
And perhaps not just main but other functions can access them as well.
让我们来看看
So let's see.
当我运行这个程序时 BANK.PY的PYTHON
When I run this program, Python of bank.py,
到目前为止 我希望根据我自己的直觉 我会去
I would hope based on my own intuition thus far that I'm going
以确保我目前的余额为零
to see that my current balance is zero.
也就是说 即使在第一行定义了余额变量
That is to say, even though the balance variable is defined on line one,
希望我还能在Main内的五个地方在线打印出来
hopefully I can still print it online five inside of main,
即使在我的主要职能中没有定义平衡
even though balance was not defined in my main function.
我们开始吧
Here we go.
按Enter键
Hitting Enter.
好了 平衡为零
And voila, balance zero.
因此 它似乎确实奏效了
So it does seem to work.
即使您在函数外部声明了一个在Python中的变量
Even if you declare a variable in Python outside of your functions,
看起来您可以访问它
it appears that you can access it.
即使在Main这样的函数中 也可以读取该变量的值
You can read the value of that variable even inside of a function like main.
好了 现在让我们来点冒险吧
Well, let's get a little more adventurous now.
因为这个计划真的没有解决任何人的问题
Because this program really isn't solving anyone's problems.
让我们继续实施更多的银行
Let's go ahead and implement more of a bank,
比如将钱存入银行的能力
like the ability to deposit money into the bank
并从银行取款
and to withdraw money from the bank.
从而为我提供了更多的函数 这些函数很可能
Thereby giving me some more functions that might very well
需要访问相同的变量
need to access that same variable.
让我在这里清除我的终端窗口
Let me clear my terminal window here.
现在让我先假装一下
And let me go ahead and pretend for the moment
我有能力存入 比如说 100美元或100个硬币
that I have the ability to deposit, say, $100 or 100 coins,
无论这里的货币单位是什么
whatever the unit of currency is here.
然后 也许我想直接退缩
And then, maybe I want to withdraw straight
拿走50个同样的美元或硬币
away 50 of those same dollars or coins.
现在 让我继续在Main的底部打印出来
And now, let me go ahead and just print out at the bottom of main
我的新平衡应该是什么 这样在一个理想的世界里
what my new balance should be so that in an ideal world,
一旦我存了100 然后取了50 从0开始
once I have deposited 100 then withdrawn 50, after starting at 0,
我认为我在第八行的新余额确实应该是50
I'd like to think that my new balance on line eight should indeed be 50.
好的
All right.
但我还没有实现这些功能
But I haven't implemented these functions yet.
所以让我们像过去一样做这件事
So let's do that as we've done in the past.
下面 我将继续定义另一个函数存款
Down here, I'm going to go ahead and define another function deposit.
我要说的是 对于一些硬币 需要一个名为n的参数
I'm going to say that it takes an argument called n for a number of coins
或美元或类似的东西
or dollars or the like.
我就是要这么做
And I'm just going to do this.
我要继续说 平衡加等于n
I'm going to go ahead and say, balance plus equals n,
从而改变n的值
thereby changing the value of n.
我可以说得更详细一些 Balance等于Balance+n
I could do it more verbosely, balance equals balance plus n.
但我将在这里使用较短的手写记法
But I'm going to use the shorter hand notation here instead.
现在 让我们来执行撤退
And now, let's implement withdraw.
因此 定义一个名为Retroke的函数
So define a function called withdraw.
它也将接受一个变量--一个参数
It too is going to take a variable-- an argument
N表示美元或硬币的数量
n for number of dollars or coins.
现在 我要继续从平衡中减去
And now, I'm going to go ahead and subtract from balance
使用负号也等于n
using minus equals n as well.
如果此文件的名称为Main 我仍将调用Main
And I'm still going to call main if the name of this file is main.
那么我做了什么呢？
So what have I done?
我刚才总共添加了三个函数 而不是一个 所有这些函数
I've just added not just one but three functions total, all of which
显然需要通过打印、递增来访问余额
apparently need to access balance by printing it, incrementing it,
或者减少它 就像我们在这里看到的
or decrementing it, as we've seen here.
好的
All right.
让我继续下去 在这里重点介绍这三个功能
Let me go ahead and focus on these three functions here.
让我返回到我的终端窗口 运行ban.py的Python并按Enter键
Let me go back to my terminal window and run Python of bank.py and hit Enter.
哇哦
And wow.
看起来我们在这里引入了一些问题
Seems like we've introduced some number of problems here.
这些问题是什么？
And what are these problems?
嗯 非绑定局部错误可能是我们第一次在这里看到这种错误
Well, unbound local error is perhaps the first time we've seen this one here.
赋值前引用的局部变量余额
Local variable balance referenced before assignment.
这有点误导 绝对令人困惑
And that's a bit misleading, definitely confusing.
因为我绝对在代码的顶端分配了值平衡
Because I absolutely assigned balance of value on the top of my code.
事实上 如果我向后滚动 那里没有任何变化或丢失
And indeed, if I scroll back up, nothing has changed or been lost up there.
它肯定是被赋予了价值
It's definitely been assigned to value.
现在在第12行 看起来 当存款被调用时
And now on line 12, it would seem, that when deposit is called
我只是想再次访问该变量
I'm just trying to access that variable again.
因此 直观地说 如何解释这个错误消息 未绑定的本地错误？
So intuitively, what might explain this error message, unbound local error?
在那里 Python告诉了我们什么 它可以或不可以
What is Python telling us there that Python can or can't
当涉及到这些所谓的全局变量时
do when it comes to these so-called global variables that
都在我文件的首位？
are at the top of my file?
学生：所以如果你想改变这个变量
STUDENT: So if you want to change this variable,
您应该编写一个内部Left函数Main
you should write an inside left function main.
和全局变量不变
And the global variable unchangeable.
大卫·J·马兰：是的
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah.
学生：[听不见]
STUDENT: [INAUDIBLE]
大卫·J·马兰：如果你想改变这个值
DAVID J. MALAN: So if you want to change the value,
它可能需要是函数的本地属性
it might need to be local to the function.
如果您试图在函数中更改全局变量
If you are trying to change a global variable though in a function,
这显然行不通
it clearly does not work.
因此 可以读取全局变量
So it's OK to read a global variable.
读意思、访问它、打印它等等
Read meaning access it and print it and so forth.
但显然 您不能以相同的方式写入全局变量
But apparently, you can't write to a global variable in the same way
在这些功能中的一个中
from within one of these functions.
好的
All right.
好吧 也许解决办法就是这么做
Well, maybe the fix is to do this.
让我清除终端窗口和错误
Let me clear my terminal window and that error.
也许我可以这么做
And maybe I could just do this.
让我们去掉全局变量
Let's get rid of the global variable.
让我们继续 例如 把它放在Main中
And let's go ahead and put it, for instance, inside of main.
这种做法现在可能奏效吗？
Might this now work?
好的 现在让我试试这个
Well, let me try this now.
Bank.py的蟒蛇回车
Python of Bank.py Enter.
仅凭这一点并不能解决问题
That alone did not solve it.
我仍然有一个未绑定的本地错误
I still have an unbound local error.
不过 这一次是出于不同的原因
This time though, it's for a different reason.
现在 根据定义 第二行上的余额是一个局部变量
It turns out now that balance on line two is by definition a local variable.
局部变量是存在于函数上下文中的变量 至少
A local variable is one that exists in the context of a function, at least
在这种情况下
in this case.
全局变量是相反的 不是这样的
A global variable is the opposite, one that does not,
例如 在我的文件顶部
for instance at the top of my file.
因此 这是在Python中的另一个区别
So here is another distinction in Python.
如果在函数中声明变量 如main
If you declare a variable in a function, like main,
就像我在二号线上做的平衡一样
just as I've done on line two with balance,
它确实是该功能的本地功能
it is indeed local to that function.
存款和取款不能访问相同变量
Deposit and withdraw do not have access to that same variable.
为什么？
Why?
因为它是从本地到美因河
Because it's local to main.
因此 你会认为我们现在有点陷入了这个恶性循环
And so, you would think now we're kind of stuck in this vicious cycle.
好吧 也许解决方案是在全球范围内转移平衡
Well, maybe the solution then is to move balance globally
因此 所有三个功能都可以访问它
so all three functions can access it.
但很明显 正如埃琳娜所指出的那样 我们不能因此改变它
But clearly, where we began, as Elena noted, we can't therefore change it.
因此 在Python中解决此问题的方法就是
So it turns out the solution to this problem in Python
具有讽刺意味的是 这里正是这个关键词
is ironically exactly this keyword here.
这有点不同 你可能会看到 如果你
It's a little different as you might have seen if you've
以前用其他语言编写的程序
programmed before in other languages.
但在Python语言中确实有一个关键词叫
But there's indeed a keyword in Python called
GLOBAL 允许您告诉函数 嘿 这
global that allows you to tell a function that, hey, this
不是您本地的变量
is not a variable that's local to you.
我的意思是它是一个全局变量 我想让你们编辑它
I mean it to be a global variable that I want you to edit.
因此 如果我返回到VS代码 清除我的终端
So if I go back to VS Code here, clearing my terminal
窗口来消除该错误
window to get rid of that error.
让我继续并撤消我刚刚所做的更改
Let me go ahead and undo the change I just made
把平衡放回我档案的首位
and put balance back at the top of my file.
但这一次 我要做的是
But this time, what I'm going to do is I'm
我将通知我的两个函数 它们需要更改余额的值
going to inform my two functions that need to change the value of balance,
它确实是全球性的 在这里再次输入Global Balance以及
that it is indeed global, by typing global balance again here as well as
这里
here.
全球平衡
Global balance.
我仍然在第13行和第18行保留相同的代码行 即
I still leave the same lines of code now on lines 13 and 18, that increment
和减量平衡
and decrement balance.
但是现在使用关键字GLOBAL有点像是在暗示
But this now use of keyword global is a little bit of a clue to Python that,
哦 好的
oh, OK.
这不是一个局部变量
It's not a local variable.
这不是您引入的错误
This is not a bug that you've introduced.
你的意思是让我在上面编辑这个变量
You mean for me to edit this variable up above.
现在 让我继续在我的终端窗口中运行BANK.PY的Python
So now, let me go ahead in my terminal window and run Python of bank.py.
我希望看到我的余额是0加100减50等于
I'm hoping to see that my balance is zero plus 100 minus 50 is 50.
事实上 现在就是这样
And indeed, it now is.
根据我在第五行的第一个打印语句 它从零开始
It starts off at zero per my first print statement on line five.
但最终结果是总共50美元 低于第八行的数字
But it ends up at 50 total at below that on line eight.
让我在这里暂停一下 看看现在是否有任何问题
Let me pause here to see if now there's any questions
在这些全局或局部变量上
on these global or local variables.
学生：当你全局声明一个变量 并且
STUDENT: What happens when you declare a variable globally, and as
在全局相同的变量中和在函数中？
in the same variable globally and in a function?
大卫·J·马兰：问得好
DAVID J. MALAN: A good question.
你总是在想所谓的角落案件
You're always thinking about the so-called corner cases.
因此 如果您全局声明一个变量 比如在文件的顶部
So if you declare a variable both globally, like at the top of your file,
然后是函数内部的同名变量 同名
and then an identically named variable inside of a function, same name,
可以说 后者将落后于前者
the latter will shadow, so to speak, the former.
也就是说 您将能够使用后者 即局部变量
That is, you'll be able to use the latter, that is the local variable.
但它不会对全球变量产生影响
But it will have no effect on the global variable.
暂时 Python将只知道局部变量的存在
Temporarily, Python will only know that the local variable exists.
因此 总的来说 经验法则是 不要那样做
So in general, the rule of thumb is, just don't do that.
它不仅可能在您的代码中产生错误
Not only might it create bugs in your code
因为你不会完全改变你想要改变的东西
because you don't quite change what you intend to change.
对于其他读者来说 这可能也不是显而易见的
It's also perhaps non-obvious to other readers as well.
关于全球人或本地人的其他问题？
Other questions on globals or locals?
学生：好的 如果我们决定增加平衡呢
STUDENT: OK, what if we decide to add balance
作为Main函数中的参数？
as an argument inside the main function?
大卫·J·马兰：是的 又是一种良好的直觉
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, another good instinct.
但在这种情况下 这也不会解决问题
But in this case, that also is not going to solve the problem.
因为如果将一个像Balance这样的变量传递给每个函数
Because if you pass in a variable like balance to each of the functions
然后在该函数中更改它 它
and then change it within that function, it's
实际上只会改变它的本地副本
only going to be changing in effect a local copy thereof.
它不会改变那些功能之外的东西
It's not going to be changing what's outside of those functions.
所以我认为我们需要一个更好的方法
So I think we actually need a better way altogether.
事实上 请允许我过渡到一个修改
And in fact, allow me to transition to perhaps a modification
同样的节目
of this same program.
回想一下 我们最近看到的
Recall that we looked most recently at this notion
面向对象的编程
of object-oriented programming.
因此你可以模拟真实世界的实体 比如银行
Whereby you can model real world entities, for instance a bank,
你可以建模和封装信息
and you can model and encapsulate information
关于现实世界中的实体 例如
about that real world entity, for instance,
比如某人的账户余额
like someone's account balance.
所以我建议我们真的这么做
So let me propose that we actually do this.
让我们从bank.py开始
Let me start from scratch with bank.py.
完全去掉全局变量
Get rid of the global variable altogether.
并实际使用一些面向对象的代码
And actually use some object-oriented code.
让我定义一个名为account的类来表示某人的银行帐户
Let me define a class called account to represent someone's bank account.
然后 让我继续使用init方法进行初始化
And then, let me go ahead and initialize with my init method, which
同样 按照惯例 它至少接受一个名为self的参数
again, takes by convention at least one argument called self.
我来初始化每个人的银行账户
Let me go ahead and initialize every person's bank account
变成零之类的值
to some value like zero.
我该怎么做？
Now, how can I do that?
好的 我继续做自我平衡等于零
Well, I'm going to go ahead and do self.balance equals zero.
从而给我一个名为
Thereby giving me an instance variable called
此帐户的余额初始化为零
balance initialized for this account to zero.
但我会积极地回忆起我们是如何
But I'm going to proactively remember how we also
引入了这种属性的概念
introduced this notion of properties which might otherwise
与我的实例变量名冲突
collide with the names of my instance variables.
所以按照惯例我会这么做
So just by convention I'm going to do this.
我要主动重命名这个实例变量
I'm going to rename this instance variable proactively
来强调平衡 以有效地表明它是私人的 甚至
to underscore balance to effectively indicate that it's private, even
尽管Python并没有强制这样做
though that's not enforced by Python.
这只是我的一个视觉线索
It's just a visual clue to myself that this
是我不应该 或者其他代码不应该触及的
is something that really I should not-- or other code should not touch,
在这个类中只有函数
just functions in this class.
现在 让我继续做这个
Now, let me go ahead and do this.
让我继续定义一个实际的函数
Let me go ahead and define an actual function
所谓的平衡 它实际上是一种财产
called balance that really is going to be a property whose purpose in life
就是恢复自我平衡
is just to return self.balance.
我要明确地说 这确实是
And I'm going to go explicitly and say this is indeed
这一类的财产
a property of this class.
现在 让我继续并重新实现另外两个功能
Now, let me go ahead and re-implement those other two functions,
存取款 但限于本课程的范围内
deposit and withdraw, but in the confines of this class.
所以我要说 定义存款
So I'm going to say, define deposit.
它将一如既往地接受自己的论点
It's going to take in an argument self as always,
但另加一元 要存入若干美元或硬币.
but an additional one n, a number of dollars or coins to deposit.
我现在该如何操纵这一点呢？
And how do I now manipulate this?
好的 我要做自己 _天平加等于n
Well, I'm going to do self._balance plus equals n.
现在在这里 我要做def取款 就像存款一样
And now down here, I'm going to do def withdraw self n, just like for deposit.
但在这里 我要做的是 平衡减去n
But here, I'm going to do self.balance minus equals n.
现在 如果我低于这门课 我就
And now, if I go down below this class, I'm
接下来 我将自己定义为一个主要功能
going to go ahead and define myself a main function
这样我现在就可以试一试了
just so I can try this now out.
接下来 我将通过调用Account创建一个Account对象
I'm going to go ahead and create an account object by calling the account
构造函数 它是带两个圆括号的类名
constructor, that is the name of the class with two parentheses
如果我没有向init传递任何参数
if I'm not passing in any arguments to init.
我现在要继续 像以前一样打印出我的帐户余额
I'm going to go ahead now and print out as before the balance of my account.
但要做到这一点 我将像这样访问该帐户的属性
But to do that, I'm going to access the property of that account like this.
我现在要继续说 再存100美元或硬币
And I'm going to go ahead now and say, deposit another $100 or coins
加100元押金
with deposit 100.
我将继续前进 像以前一样 现在也立即退出
And I'm going to go ahead, like before, and also now immediately withdraw
不管是什么原因 50个一样的
for whatever reason 50 of the same.
现在 我要最后一次打印
And now, I'm going to print one last time
Balance后跟Account Balance再次访问该属性
balance followed by account.balance, again, accessing that property.
当然 为了让这整件事起作用 我需要一个这样的
And for this whole thing to work, of course, I need one of these
如果名称等于等于下划线Main 则继续并调用Main
if name equals equals underscore main, then go ahead and call main.
现在 在我运行这个之前 您将看到它相当迅速地升级
Now, before I run this, you'll see that it rather escalated quickly.
我手头有一个非常简单的目标 那就是实现银行的概念
I had a very simple goal at hand to implement the notion of a bank.
我最终完美地实现了这一点
And I was able to implement that perfectly fine ultimately
通过声明BALANCE是全局的 但然后告诉我的每个函数
by declaring balance to be global but then to tell each of my functions
它确实是全球性的
that it is indeed global.
但这并不是我们可以使用的最好的封装形式
But that's not really the best form of encapsulation we have at our disposal
现在
now.
根据我们对面向对象编程的关注
Per our focus on object-oriented programming,
如果我们试图实现一些真实世界的实体 比如银行账户
if we're trying to implement some real world entity like an account at a bank,
这就是课程允许我们做的事情
that's what classes allow us to do.
它让我们可以解决同样的问题 也许只是一点点
And it allows us to solve that same problem perhaps a little
更干净 当然 如果我们要积累越来越多的函数
more cleanly, certainly if we're going to accumulate more and more functions
或随时间推移的方法
or methods over time.
所以 如果我在这里没有犯任何错误 如果我运行BANK.PY的Python并点击
So if I didn't make any mistakes here, if I run Python of bank.py and hit
现在进入 你会看到它工作得很好
Enter now, you'll see that it just works just fine.
因为在Python类的世界里
Because in the world of classes in Python,
根据定义 这些所谓的实例变量
these so-called instance variables are by definition
该类中的所有方法都可以访问
accessible to all of the methods in that class
因为我们都是通过这个特殊的参数本身访问它们
because we're accessing them all by way of that special parameter self.
那么 用哪种方式来做呢？
So which way to do it?
对于一个相当小的脚本 其中您只需
For a reasonably small script wherein you are simply
试图实现一个包含一些全局信息的脚本
trying to implement a script that has some global information,
就像你需要在别处操纵的账户余额一样
like an account balance that you then need to manipulate elsewhere,
GLOBAL关键字是该问题的一种解决方案
the global keyword is a solution to that problem.
但总的来说 在许多语言中
But generally speaking, in many languages,
在某种程度上 其中使用了全局变量
Python to some extent among them, using global variables
因为事情可能很快就会变得一团糟 所以人们往往会皱起眉头
tends to be frowned upon only because things can get messy quickly.
而且你的信息的确切位置很快就会变得不那么明显
And it can become less obvious quickly exactly where your information is
存储 如果有些在这里 有些在你的函数中
stored, if some of it's up here, some of it's in your function.
因此 一般来说 经验法则是谨慎使用全局变量
So generally, the rule of thumb is to use global variables sparingly.
尽管从技术上讲 在Python中 这些全局变量
Though technically speaking, in Python these global variables
从技术上讲 对于我们的模块来说是本地的 如果我们确实实现了
are technically local to our module if we were indeed implementing
一个图书馆 而不仅仅是一个程序
a library and not just a program.
因此 简而言之 尽量少用全局变量
So in short, try to use global variables sparingly.
但当你这样做的时候 同样的问题也有解决方案
But when you do, there is a solution to these same problems.
现在是关于全球化的问题 还是关于我们重新实施相同理念的问题
Questions now on globals or our reimplementation of the same idea
但是使用成熟的面向对象编程呢？
but using full-fledged object-oriented programming?
学生：我只是想问 这个属性是做什么的？
STUDENT: I just would like to ask, what this property does?
大卫·J·马兰：这处房产的用途
DAVID J. MALAN: What this property does.
所以如果我回到VS Code 你会看到
So if I go back to VS Code here, you'll see
这是我们在课上学到的一种技术
that this was a technique we looked at in our lecture
关于面向对象的编程
on object-oriented programming.
因此 属性是以某种方式保护的实例变量
Whereby a property is a instance variable that somehow protected.
它允许我控制它可以读写
It allows me to control it can be read and written.
所以在这种情况下 我只有通常所说的二传手
So in this case, I only have what's called generally a setter.
或者抱歉
And or sorry.
在这种情况下 我只有通常所说的获取器
In this case, I only have what's generally called a getter.
而且这里没有提到Getter这个词
And there's no mention of the word getter here.
这只是“财产手段”
This is just @property means.
这种功能平衡将允许我 回忆一下
That function balance will allow me, recall,
使用这样的语法 我可以假装
to use syntax like this, where I can pretend
好像Balance确实是不带下划线的实例变量
as though balance is indeed with no underscore an instance variable.
但我现在可以防止像我在Main中那样的代码试图改变平衡
But I can now prevent code like mine in main from trying to change balance.
因为我没有二传手 所以我不会
Because I do not have a setter, I would not
能够执行类似帐户余额等于1,000的操作
be able to do something like account balance equals 1,000
只给自己1000或硬币 因为我还没有定义二传手
to just give myself 1,000 or coins because I have not defined a setter.
因此 根据我们对面向对象编程的关注
So again, per our focus on object-oriented programming,
这些属性只是允许我进行一些更细粒度的控制
these properties just allow me some finer-grained control.
一些语言允许您定义变量 可以说
Some languages allow you to define variables that are, so to speak,
常量
constant.
也就是说 一旦您为它们设置了一个值
That is, once you have set a value to them,
您不能更改该变量的值
you cannot change the value of that variable.
这往往是一件好事 因为它
And that tends to be a good thing because it
允许您进行防御性编程
allows you to program defensively.
以防你不小心 或者其他人
Just in case you accidentally, or someone else,
意外地试图修改该变量的值
accidentally tries to modify the value of that variable,
如果您在某种语言中将其声明为常量 则不能更改它
if you have declared it in some language as a constant, it cannot be changed,
或者通常不费很大力气就不能改变
or usually cannot be changed without great effort.
不幸的是 在Python语言中 我们再次使用了这种荣誉系统
Unfortunately, in Python, we're again on the sort of honor system here.
我们有惯例来表明某件事
Where we have conventions to indicate that something
应该像对待常量一样对待
should be treated as though it's constant.
但这实际上并不是由语言强制执行的
But that's not actually enforced by the language.
举个例子 让我回到VS代码
So for instance, let me go back here to VS Code.
让我创建一个新文件 比如 名为meows.py
And let me create a new file, for instance, called meows.py.
让我们看看我们是否能实现猫在屏幕上喵喵叫的概念
And let's see if we can't implement the notion of a cat meowing on the screen.
所以我会用代码meows.py
So I'll do code of meows.py.
在meows.py中 让我举个例子
And in meows.py, let me go ahead for instance
然后实现一个非常简单的程序 让一只猫叫三次
and implement a very simple program that just has a cat meowing three times.
不如这样吧
So how about this.
对于i在3的范围内 继续并打印出来 引号内 喵
For i in the range of three, go ahead and print out, quote unquote, meow.
好吧
All right.
好吧 我们已经看到在过去我们如何可以清理这一点
Well, we've seen in the past how we can clean this up a little bit.
例如 如果我没有用i
For instance, if I'm not actually using i,
我还不如用Python的方法把它的名字
I might as well Pythonically just change the name
要加下划线的变量 尽管它没有函数
of that variable to underscore even though that has no functional
效果在这里
effect here.
但这里我们有三个随机硬编码的
But here we have this three randomly hardcoded, that is,
在我的代码中显式输入
typed explicitly into my code.
当你的代码只有两行时 这完全不是什么大不了的事情
And it's totally not a big deal when your code is only two lines.
但想象一下 这是一个更大的计划
But imagine that this is a much bigger program with dozens
或者甚至数百行
or even hundreds of lines.
想象一下其中一条线上有个3
And imagine that one of those lines just has a three in there somewhere.
你不会轻易找到那三个的
You're never going to find that three very easily.
这很容易被忽视
And it's going to be very easily overlooked
你或同事或其他人
by you or colleagues or others that you've
在你的代码里硬编码了一个像3这样的神奇值
hardcoded some magic value like a three right there in your code.
因此 这往往是最佳实践 不仅在Python中 而且在其他语言中
So it tends to be best practice, not just in Python but other languages
同样 任何时候你有一个常数
as well, any time you have what is essentially a constant,
就像永远不会改变的数字3
like a number three that shouldn't ever change,
是至少让它冒泡 把它放在代码的顶部
is to at least let it bubble up, surface it to the top of your code,
这样代码的常量值就很明显了
so that it's just obvious what your code's constant values are.
所以 我的意思是
And so, by that I mean this.
在这个文件的顶部 它可能会
At the top of this file, it would probably
明天对同事说清楚一点 坦白地说 对我来说
be a little clearer to colleagues, and frankly, me tomorrow
在我忘了今天做了什么之后
after I've forgotten what I did today, to define a variable like meows
并将其设置为3
and set it equal to three.
然后 不是在这里硬编码三个或更低
And then, instead of hardcoding three here or even lower
在一个更大的程序中 让我继续传递变量的值
in a much bigger program, let me just go ahead and pass in that variable's value
到我的循环
to my loop.
所以现在对我来说很明显
So that now it's just kind of obvious to me
猫咪叫的次数显然就是猫咪叫的次数
that meows is apparently the number of times to meow.
如果我想改变它 我唯一需要改变的代码
And if I ever want to change it, the only code I have to change
在我档案的最顶端
is at the very top of my file.
我不需要到处钓鱼 也不需要想着什么会坏掉
I don't need to go fishing around or figure out what's going to break,
我需要改变什么
what do I need to change.
我只知道我可以在顶部更改这些常量
I just know that I can change these constants up at the top.
不过 使用Python的问题在于 它实际上并不
The problem though with Python is that Python doesn't actually
使变量保持不变
make variables constant.
这在Python和其他一些语言中确实是一种约定
It's indeed a convention in Python and some other languages
当你想要向世界表明的时候 至少要把你的变量大写
to at least capitalize your variables when you want to indicate to the world
你不应该碰这个
that you should not touch this.
它是恒定不变的
It is constant.
但在我的代码中几乎没有任何东西阻止我说
But there is literally nothing in my code preventing me from saying,
你猜怎么着？
you know what?
今天 我感觉自己像是四只猫
Today I feel like four meows instead.
这会奏效的
That would work.
在其他语言中 虽然通常有
In other languages though there's typically
句法上的关键字或某些其他机制
a keyword or some other mechanism syntactically that
将允许您阻止当前执行第三行
would allow you to prevent line three currently from executing.
因此 当您尝试运行代码时 实际上会收到一条错误消息
So that when you try to run your code, you would actually get an error message
明确地说 你不能这样做
explicitly saying, you cannot do that.
所以 在荣誉体系上 Python又一次显得更加重要了
So Python, again, is a bit more on the honor system
相反 当涉及到这些约定时
when it comes to these conventions instead.
现在 事实证明还有其他类型的常量 引用不引用
Now, it turns out there's other types of constants, quote unquote,
这是巨蟒通常会表现出来的
that Python typically manifests.
事实上 让我继续下去 改变一下这一点
And in fact, let me go ahead and change this around a little bit.
让我删除这个版本的猫咪
Let me delete this version of meows.
让我再次介绍一下我们讨论过的一个班级
And let me introduce, again, a class from our discussion
面向对象编程的一部分 就像表示
of object-oriented programming, like a class representing
一只猫 另一个真实世界的实体
a cat, another real-world entity.
回想一下 在类中 您不仅可以拥有
Recall that within classes, you can have not just
实例变量和类变量
instance variables but class variables.
也就是说 类中的变量本身并不在自身内部
That is variables inside of the class that aren't inside of self, per se,
但是类中的所有方法都可以访问它们
but they're accessible to all of the methods inside of that class.
这里也是一样 有一个惯例 但没有强制执行
Here too, there's a convention but not enforced
通过拥有类常量的Python 从而在类内部
by Python of having class constants, whereby inside of the class,
您可能希望有一个应该、应该、不应该更改的变量
you might want to have a variable that should, should, should not be changed.
但您只是想通过将其名称大写来在视觉上表明这一点
But you just want to indicate that visually by capitalizing its name.
例如 如果一只猫的默认猫叫声数量
So for instance, if the default number of meows for a cat
应该是三个 我可以在我的班级里
is meant to be three, I can literally inside of my class
但在我定义的任何方法之外
but outside of any of my defined methods just
创建一个全部用相同的值大写的类变量
create a class variable all capitalized with that same value.
然后 如果我想创造一种方法 比如猫叫
And then, if I want to create a method, like meow,
例如 正如我们所知 作为一个实例方法 它可能会接受self
for instance, which as an instance method might take in self as we know.
然后 我可能会在这里用我的循环来下划线--
And then, I might have my loop here for underscore in the range of--
现在我需要访问这个
and now I need to access this.
约定将会说猫叫以表明
The convention would be to say cat.meows to make clear
我想要与名为cat的类相关联的猫叫声变量
that I want the meows variable that's associated with the class called cat.
然后 我将继续打印出其中一条猫咪叫声
Then I'm going to go ahead and print out one of these meows.
现在 在我的代码底部 在类之外 让我继续
And now, at the bottom of my code, outside of the class, let me go ahead
做这样的事情
and do something like this.
让我使用CAT构造函数实例化一只猫
Let me instantiate a cat using the cat constructor.
请注意这一点很重要
Notice this is important.
根据我们对OOP的讨论 这个类是按照约定大写的
Per our discussion of OOP, the class is capitalized by convention.
但这里的变量是小写的
But the variable over here is lowercase.
我可以称它为C或其他任何东西
And I could call it just C or anything else.
但我有点喜欢这里叫它小猫和大猫的对称性
But I kind of like the symmetry of calling it little cat here and big cat,
可以这么说 就在这里
so to speak, over here.
现在 如果我想让这只特别的猫叫
And now, if I want this particular cat to meow
默认的三次 我可以像这样做猫咪
that default number of three times, I can just do cat.meow like this.
该方法将在第五行中访问该类常量
And that method meow is going to, per line five, access that class constant.
但同样 它只是在事实中是不变的--
But again, it's constant only in the fact--
只是在你不应该碰它的意义上 并不是说它实际上
only in the sense that you should not touch that, not that it's actually
将由语言强制执行
going to be enforced by the language.
那么 让我继续使用Python of meows.py来运行它
Let me go ahead then and run this with Python of meows.py.
它就在那里 我们的三只猫叫 喵 喵
And there it is, three of our meows, meow, meow.
事实证明 Python是一种动态类型的语言
It turns out that Python is a dynamically typed language.
也就是说 它不是强类型的
That is to say, it's not strongly typed.
因此 当你想要一个整型的时候 你必须告诉程序
Whereby when you want an int, you have to tell the program
您使用的是一个整型
that you are using an int.
您不必告诉程序您正在使用字符串或浮点数
You don't have to tell the program that you are using a str, or a float,
或者一套 或者其他任何东西
or a set, or anything else.
一般来说 到目前为止 你和我 当我们创造变量时
Generally speaking, to date, you and I, when we're creating variables,
我们只需为变量命名即可
we just give a variable a name.
我们经常在等号中给它赋值
We frequently assign it using in the equal sign some other value.
老实说 Python只是一种动态
And honestly, Python just kind of dynamically
找出它是哪种类型的变量
figures out what type of variable it is.
如果是 引用单引号Hello world 变量将是一个str
If it's, quote unquote Hello, world, the variable is going to be a str.
如果它是50 那么变量的整数将是一个整型
If it's 50, the integer the variable is going to be an int.
现在 在其他语言中 包括C、C++和Java等
Now, in other languages, including C, and C++, and Java, and others,
程序员有时需要指定哪些类型
it's sometimes necessary for the programmer to specify what types
你想要的东西的变量
of variables you want something to be.
这样做的好处是它帮助您更容易地检测到错误
The upside of that is that it helps you detect bugs more readily.
因为如果您打算让变量存储字符串或整数
Because if you intend for a variable to store a string or an integer,
但是您不小心存储了一个整数或字符串 反之亦然
but you accidentally store an integer or a string, the opposite, or something
否则 您的语言可以为您检测到这种错误
else altogether, your language can detect that kind of mistake for you.
例如 当你去运行程序时
When you go, for instance, to run the program,
它可以说 不 你犯了一个错误
it can say, no, you've made a mistake.
您可以在您的实际用户检测到相同数量之前修复该问题
And you can fix that before your actual users detect as much.
在Python语言中也是如此 这是一个更友好的环境
In Python too here, it's again, more of a friendly environment
您可以在其中提供有关Python本身的提示
where you can provide hints to Python itself
关于变量应该是什么类型
as to what type a variable should be.
但语言本身并没有严格执行这些规定
But the language itself does not strongly enforce these.
相反 您可以使用一个工具来告诉您是否
Rather, you can use a tool that will tell you whether or not
您正确地使用了变量
you're using a variable correctly.
但它通常是一个以程序员的身份运行的工具
But it's typically a tool you would run as the programmer
在你真正向世界发布你的代码之前
before you actually release your code to the world.
或者 如果你有某种自动化的流程 你可以运行这种工具
Or if you have some kind of automated process, you can run this kind of tool
就像您可以使用其他程序重新格式化或链接到您的代码一样
just like you could reformat or link to your code with some other program
在你真正将其公之于众之前
before you actually release it to the world.
那么 我们应该如何使用这些所谓的类型提示呢？
So how might we go about using these so-called type hints?
好的 它们在Python自己的文档中的常见位置进行了记录
Well, they're documented in the usual place in Python's own documentation.
事实证明 有一个项目
And it turns out there's a program that's
非常流行的检查代码是否
pretty popular for checking whether or not your code is
坚持你自己的类型提示
adhering to your own type hints.
这个程序在这里被称为mypy
And that program here is called mypy.
这只是几个中的一个
And it's just one of several.
但这个特别受欢迎 可以很容易地安装
But this one is particularly popular and can be easily installed
以通常的方式使用pip安装mypy
in the usual way with pip install mypy.
它自己的文档在这里的URL上
And its own documentation is at this URL here.
但是我们将非常简单地使用它来检查我们的变量是否确实
But we'll use it quite simply to check whether or not our variables are indeed
使用正确的类型
using the right types.
那么 我们该如何着手做这件事呢？
So how can we go about doing this?
好了 让我回到VS代码 清除我的终端窗口
All right, let me go back here to VS Code, clear my terminal window,
事实上 删除当前的meows.py
and in fact erase meows.py as it currently was.
让我们实现一个不同版本的猫咪 非常简单
And let's implement a different version of meows that quite simply
有一个名为猫咪的功能 可以在屏幕上进行实际的猫咪叫声
has a function called meow that does the actual meowing on the screen.
然后 我将继续向下调用该函数
And then, I'm just going to go ahead and call that function down
接近底部
toward the bottom.
为了简单起见 我不打算费心使用main函数
I'm not going to bother with a main function just for simplicity
这样我们就可以一如既往地专注于新事物
so that we can focus as always only on what's new.
所以在这里 我们定义了一个名为meow的函数
So here we are defining a function called meow.
猫叫需要很多次 比如n代表数字
It's going to take a number of times to meow, for instance n for number.
在这个函数内部 我要做的是
And inside of this function, I'm going to do
我通常在n的范围内加下划线 继续打印 引用不引用
my usual for underscore in the range of n go ahead and print, quote unquote,
喵星人
meow.
因此 根据我们前面的代码 我认为这是正确的
So based on our earlier code, I think this is correct.
我没有费心将变量定义为I
I've not bothered defining the variable as i.
我改为使用下划线 因为我不会在任何地方使用它
I'm instead using the underscore because I'm not using it anywhere.
但我想我现在有了一个工作职能 它的人生目标
But I think I now have a working function whose purpose in life
就是猫叫0次、1次、2次、3次或更多次
is to meow zero, or one, or two, or three, or more times.
好的 让我们再次使用这个函数 不用担心main
Well, let's use this function, again, not bothering with main.
我只会把我的功能放在最上面 因为只有一个
I'm just going to keep my function at the very top because there's only one.
我将把我的代码写在第六行
And I'm going to write my code here on line six.
所以我要给自己--
So I'm going to give myself--
我要向用户索要一个号码
I'm going to ask the user for a number.
我将继续并提示他们
And I'm going to go ahead and prompt them
以惯常的方式猫叫那么多次
in the usual way for that number of times to meow.
现在 我要继续用这个号码叫猫咪
And now, I'm going to go ahead and call meow on that number.
现在 你们中的一些人可能会看到我已经做错了什么
Now, some of you might see what I've already done wrong.
但也许我自己并不这样认为
But perhaps I myself don't.
所以让我进入我的终端窗口并运行Python of meows.py
So let me go into my terminal window and run Python of meows.py,
这样做的目的是为了促使我
the goal being to prompt me.
这似乎奏效了
This seems to be working.
我要打三个字
I'm going to type in three.
我希望现在的猫咪功能会打印出三次猫咪
And I would expect now the meow function to print out meow three times.
进来吧
Enter.
但是没有
But no.
这里有某种类型的错误 无法解释字符串对象
There's some kind of type error here. str object cannot be interpreted
作为一个整数
as an integer.
为什么会这样呢？
Why might that be?
学生：因为输入函数返回的是字符串 而不是整数
STUDENT: Because the input function returns a string instead of an integer.
大卫·J·马兰：没错
DAVID J. MALAN: Exactly.
INPUT函数返回字符串或字符串 而不是整型
The input function returns a string or a str, not an int.
所以在过去 当然 我们对这个问题的解决方案
So in the past, of course, our solution to this problem
通过使用int函数将字符串转换为int
has just been to convert the string to an int by using the int function.
但现在 让我开始更有防御性的编程
But now, let me start programming more defensively
所以老实说 我根本没有发现自己处于这种情况
so that honestly, I don't even find myself in this situation at all.
让我继续做这件事
Let me go ahead and do this.
让我将所谓的类型提示添加到我的函数中
Let me add what's called a type hint to my function that
显式地为meow指定应该传递什么类型的变量
explicitly specifies for meow what type of variable should be passed in.
现在 我将继续更改代码的第一行
I'm going to go ahead now and change the very first line of my code
和我的函数来指定n冒号应该是整型
and my function to specify that n colon should be an int
这是一个类型提示 事实是我已经
and this is a type hint, the fact that I've
添加了冒号、空格 单词int没有创建
added a colon, a space, and the word int is not creating
另一个整型或类似的东西
another int or anything like that.
这只是一个提示 一个注解 对Python来说
It's just a hint, an annotation, so to speak to Python,
左边这个名为n的变量应该是一个整型
that this variable on the left called n should be an int.
不幸的是 Python本身并不关心这一点
Now, unfortunately, Python itself doesn't care.
因为同样 这些类型提示不是由语言强制执行的
Because again, these type hints are not enforced by the language.
这是经过精心设计的
And that's by design.
语言本身和社区更喜欢
The language itself and the community prefers
Python应该是动态类型的 而不是强类型的
that Python be dynamically typed, not so strongly typed
要求这些东西是真的
as to require these things to be true.
但是如果我运行meows.py 再次输入3 同样的错误仍然存在
But if I run meows.py, type in three again, the same error is there.
但是让我来试试这个mypy程序 一个程序的例子
But let me go about trying this mypy program, an example of a program that
理解类型提示
understands type hints.
如果我主动运行它 我自己就能在代码中找到这样的bug
And if I run it proactively myself can find bugs like this in my code
在我 或者更糟的是 一个用户 实际运行并遇到一些神秘的东西之前
before I, or worse, a user, actually runs and encounters something cryptic
比如这里的类型错误
like this type error here.
让我清除我的终端窗口 这次运行我的空间meows.py
Let me clear my terminal window and this time run mypy space meows.py.
所以我将在我的程序中运行mypy 但我不会运行Python本身
So I'm going to run mypy on my program, but I'm not running Python itself.
当我按回车键时 我们会看到这个
When I hit Enter, we'll see this.
好吧
All right.
我们现在看到我在第七行发现了一个明显的错误
We see now that mypy found apparently an error on line seven.
错误 meow的参数1具有不兼容的类型str（应为int）
Error, argument one to meow has incompatible type str expected int.
所以这仍然是一个错误消息
So it's still an error message.
但我的用户不会使用mypy
But mypy is not a program that my users would use.
这是一个你和我作为程序员都会使用的程序
This is a program that you and I as programmers would use.
因为我们已经运行了这段代码 例如
And because we have run this code now before we, for instance, released
我现在甚至可以在代码被调用或运行之前看到
this program to the world, I can now see even before the code is called or run,
哦 我好像用我的论点来喵错了
oh, I seem to be using my argument to meow wrong.
我最好想办法解决这个问题
I had better fix this somehow.
其实我可以给你一些提示
Well, I can actually go about in hints adding
类型提示 甚至是我自己的变量 以便以另一种方式捕获它
type hints even to my own variables here so as to catch this another way too.
如果我在第六行知道我已经创建了一个变量number
If I know on line six that I'm creating already a variable called number,
我已经知道我在给input的返回值赋值equal
and I know already that I'm assigning equal to the return value of input,
我可以给我的电脑和类似的工具另一个提示 然后说 你知道吗？
I could give mypy and tools like it another hint and say, you know what?
这个叫做number的变量也应该是一个int
This variable called number should also be an int.
也就是说 如果我现在开始养成注释的习惯
That is to say, if I now start getting into the habit of annotating
所有函数的变量和参数
all of my variables and arguments to functions,
也许我的电脑能帮我找到
maybe mypy can actually help me find things
在我开始运行Python之前 我也会很快地
quite quickly as well before I get to the point of running Python itself.
我们再来一次
Let's go ahead and try this again.
Mypy的meows.py和点击回车
Mypy of meows.py and hit Enter.
这一次 请注意mypy实际上找到了
And this time, notice that mypy actually found
犯错误的速度要快一点
the mistake a little more quickly.
请注意 这一次它在第六行发现 错误 不兼容的类型
Notice this time it found on line six that, error, incompatible types
赋值表达式的类型为str 变量的类型为int
and assignment expression has type str, variable has type int.
所以在我还没来得及叫猫咪之前
So before I even got to the point of calling meow,
第六行 通过此类型提示 在由mypy使用和分析时
line six, via this type hint, when used and analyzed by mypy
帮我找到了 哦 等一下
has helped me find, oh, wait a minute.
我不应该为输入的返回值赋值
I shouldn't be assigning the return value of input
添加到我的变量名为number的位置
to my variable called number in the first place.
为什么？
Why?
Mypy刚才向我指出 返回一个字符串
Mypy has just pointed out to me that one returns a str.
我正在等待一个整型
I'm expecting an int.
现在让我来解决这个问题吧
Let me fix this now instead.
因此 让我清除我的终端窗口
So let me clear my terminal window.
现在 让我来做你们大多数人可能会做的事情
And now, let me do what most of you were probably
在经历了这么多周之后 我想我一开始就应该这么做
thinking I should have done in the first place after all of these weeks.
但现在 让我们继续将输入的返回值转换为整数
But now, let me go ahead and convert the return value of input to an integer.
为了今天的目的 我不会尝试
For today's purposes, I'm not going to try
以捕捉任何异常或类似情况
to catch any exceptions or the like.
我们只需要假设用户正确地输入了这些内容
We're just going to assume that the user types this in properly.
现在 让我继续运行mypy of meows.py
And now, let me go ahead and run mypy of meows.py,
不仅向我的参数、函数添加了类型提示
having not only added to type hints to my argument, to my function,
赋给我的变量 在第六行
to my variable down here on line six.
我现在也解决了这个问题本身
And I've also now fixed the problem itself.
让我继续运行mypy
Let me go ahead and run mypy.
并且成功 在一个源文件中没有发现任何问题
And success, no issues found in one source file.
现在 对我来说更合理的是去经营一些
Now, it's more reasonable for me to go and run something
就像猫叫声中的巨蟒一样 至少当我输入三个字时 我会相信它
like Python of meows and just trust that when I type in three, at least
我不会遇到打字错误
I'm not going to get a type error.
也就是说 作为一名程序员 我没有搞砸
That is, I didn't mess up as a programmer with respect
我的变量的类型
to the types of my variables.
为什么？
Why?
因为我一开始写代码的时候
Because when I wrote the code in the first place,
我提供了这些注释 这些提示
I provided these annotations, these hints
告诉像mypy这样的工具我的意图最好是
that inform tools like mypy that my intention had better
与实际代码所做的事情保持一致
line up with what the actual code does.
让我在这里暂停一下 看看现在是否有关于类型提示或mypy的问题
Let me pause here and see if there's now any questions on type hints or mypy.
学生：这是常见的吗 或者这些被使用的有多常见？
STUDENT: Is it common or how common is it for those to be used?
或者只是它更多地用于更复杂的代码中
Or is it just that it's more used in more complex code
很难保证你真的
where it's more difficult to ensure that you're actually
使用正确的类型 就像使用变量一样
using the correct type in the way that you're using the variables?
大卫·J·马兰：这是个好问题
DAVID J. MALAN: It's a good question.
这是个见仁见智的问题
And it's rather a matter of opinion.
Python被设计得更通用和灵活
Python was designed to be a little more versatile and flexible when
其中一些细节 部分是为了可写性
it comes to some of these details, partly for writeability, to make
编写代码更容易、更快 部分原因是为了提高性能
it easier and faster to write code, partly for performance
这样像Python这样的程序
so that the program like Python doesn't have
去检查这些细节
to bother checking these kinds of details,
我们可以直接进入代码
we can just get right into the code.
然而 实际情况是
The reality, though, is that strong type checks
对你的代码的正确性来说是件好事
do tend to be a good thing for the correctness of your code.
为什么要这样？
Why?
因为像mypy这样的程序可以在你的代码运行之前
Because programs like mypy can find, before your code is even run,
如果已经知道有错误的话
if there's already known to be an error.
它往往有利于防御性编程
And it tends to be good for defensive programming.
因此 在Python生态系统中
So the situation essentially is that within the Python ecosystem,
你可以用这种方式来注释你的类型
you can annotate your types in this way.
您可以使用工具来使用这些类型提示
You can use tools to use those type hints.
但到目前为止 Python本身并没有强制执行
But to date, Python itself does not enforce
或期望执行这些公约
or expect to enforce these conventions.
在更大的代码库中 在专业代码库中
In larger code bases, in professional code bases,
商业代码库 可能取决于项目经理
commercial code bases, probably depending on the project manager
或者取决于工程团队
or depending on the engineering team they may very well
希望自己使用类型提示
want themselves to be using type hints.
为什么要这样？
Why?
如果它能减少漏洞的可能性
If it just decreases the probability of bugs.
事实上 让我现在提议 我--想象一个情况
In fact, let me propose now that I-- imagine a situation where
而不是期望meow打印meow meow meow一些次数
instead of expecting that meow prints meow, meow, meow some number of times,
假设我不小心假设meow函数
suppose that I accidentally assume that the meow function
只返回几次meow
just returns meow some number of times.
例如 我们在关注单元测试时看到
We saw, for instance when focusing on unit tests
有返回值的函数是件好事
that it tends to be a good thing to have functions that return values,
不管是int还是字符串
be it an int or a string, rather than just having some side effect
比如自己打印东西
like printing things out themselves.
所以 也许我仍然保持着这种心态
So perhaps I'm still in that mindset.
我只是一时误会了
And I've just assumed mistakenly for the moment
这种猫叫返回一个值 就像猫叫 猫叫 或者猫叫
that meow returns a value, like meow, or meow meow, or meow meow meow,
一大串猫咪 而不是自己打印出来的
a big string of some number of meows, rather than just printing it itself,
就像现在三号线上很明显的那样
as it clearly does at the moment on line three.
因此 假设我意外地做了这样的事情
And therefore, suppose that I accidentally did something like this.
假设我这样做了 而不是简单地获得数字并将其传递给猫咪
Rather than just getting the number and passing it to meow, suppose I did this.
假设我声明了一些--一个新的变量 叫做猫咪
Suppose I declared a number of-- a new variable called meows,
我认为其类型应该是str
the type of which I think should be str.
假设 再一次 我意外地假设
And suppose, again, I assume accidentally
那猫叫回传给我一连串的猫叫 所以我自己
that meow returns to me a string of those meows so that I myself
然后可以稍后打印它们
can then print them later.
可以说 这会更有利于测试我的猫咪功能
This would be a little more conducive, arguably, to testing my meow function.
为什么？
Why?
因为我可以预料到它还会叫 或者叫
Because I could expect that it's returning meow, or meow meow,
或者猫咪 用新的线隔开
or meow meow meow, separated by new lines,
返回一个字符串 然后我可以断言等于
returning a str that I could then assert equals
我希望它会出现在类似单元测试的东西中
what I expect it to be in something like a unit test.
我现在不会费心编写任何单元测试
I'm not going to bother writing any unit tests now.
但让我们假设这就是我现在的心态
But let's just suppose that's the mindset I'm now in.
所以 在第七行 我假设我
And so, on line seven I'm assuming that I
我想将meow的返回值赋给一个名为meow的新变量 该变量
want to assign the return value of meow to a new variable called meows which
我已经使用该类型提示将其注释为字符串
I've annotated with this type hint as being a str,
这样我们就能看到另一个变量
just so we can see another variable.
这不是int 而是一个str
This one is not an int but a str instead.
好 现在让我继续运行这段代码 meows.py的Python
Well, let me go ahead and run this code now, Python of meows.py,
回车 输入三个
Enter, typing in three.
你会看到一个奇怪的虫子
And you'll see a curious bug.
没有猫叫没有猫叫
Meow meow meow none.
好吧 为什么呢？
Well, why is that?
现在看来 我的猫咪功能只有一个副作用
Well, it turns out at the moment, my meow function only has a side effect.
它只是打印了几次猫咪
It just prints out meow some number of times.
它不会显式返回值 因为它
It doesn't explicitly return a value as it
如果那里真的有Return关键字 那就好了
would if there were literally the return keyword there.
那么 在默认情况下 当Python中的函数
By default then, when a function in Python
不显式返回值 它的隐式返回值
does not explicitly return a value, its implicit return value
实际上是没有的
is in effect none.
所以 我们在这里看到的是--在第八行
And so, what we're seeing here is this-- on line eight,
因为我正在为meow赋值 返回值为None
because I'm assigning the return value of meow, which is none,
对于我的猫咪变量 第三行是仍在打印猫咪的猫咪
to my meows variable, line three is what's still printing meow meow meow.
第八行现在错误地不打印任何内容
And line eight is what's now incorrectly printing none.
因为我意外地认为meow返回一个值 但它不是
Because I accidentally thought that meow returns a value, but it doesn't.
因此 它的返回值实际上是无
So its return value is effectively none.
所以我在底部奇怪地印上了“无”这个词
So I'm printing very weirdly the word none at the bottom.
那么 我怎样才能着手捕捉到这种错误呢？
So how could I go about catching this kind of mistake too?
我可能会犯这个错误
I might make this mistake.
但如果我养成了这个习惯 也许频率会更低
But maybe with less frequency if I'm in the habit
使用这个称为类型提示的新功能来注释我的代码
of annotating my code with this new feature called type hints.
你在这里能做的就是
What you can do here is this.
让我清理我的终端窗口来处理那个神器
Let me clear my terminal window to get rid of that artifact.
在这里 让我另外指定一些看起来很有趣的语法
And up here, let me additionally specify with some funny looking syntax
我的猫咪功能实际上是被设计成没有返回任何东西
that my meow function actually by design returns none.
所以你真的使用了这个箭头符号
So you literally use this arrow notation.
在Python中 当提示函数的返回值是什么时
In Python when hinting what the return value of a function is,
你会这么做的
you would do this.
括号后有空格、连字符、大于号、
After the parentheses, a space, a hyphen, a greater than symbol,
如箭头 然后是另一个空格 然后是返回值的类型
like an arrow, and then another space, and then the type of the return value.
就目前而言 它确实会--
For now, it's indeed going to--
[燕子]对不起 请不要退货
[SWALLOWS] excuse me, return none.
但现在 至少我可以像这样抓到它
But now, at least I can catch it like this.
如果我现在不是在我的代码上运行Python而是mypy 这将是一种习惯
If I now run not Python but mypy on my code, which would be a habit
我现在开始学习如何使用类型提示
I'm now getting into if using type hints.
在运行程序之前 请检查我是否正确使用了所有类型
Check that I'm using all of my types correctly before I even run my program.
我们会看到现在Mypy已经在网上找到了七个猫 引用引述
We'll see that now mypy has found online seven that meow, quote unquote,
不返回值
does not return a value.
Mypy知道这一点 因为我已经主动注释了我的猫咪功能
And mypy knows that because I have proactively annotated my meow function
作为其返回值为None
as having none as its return value.
所以现在 Mypy可以检测到这一点
So now, mypy can detect that.
我现在应该意识到 哦 等一下
I should now realize, oh, wait a minute.
我在这里太愚蠢了
I'm being foolish here.
显然 Meow不返回值
Meow clearly does not return a value.
我不应该像在7号线上那样对待它
I should not be treating it like it does on line seven.
现在让我开始实际解决这个问题
Let me go about actually fixing this now.
那么 我该如何着手解决这个问题呢？
So how do I go about fixing this?
那么 让我们练习一下我们在专注于单元测试时所宣扬的内容
Well, let's practice what we preached in our focus on unit tests,
拥有像猫咪这样的功能不会像打印本身一样产生副作用
having a function like meow not have side effects like printing itself.
但让我们让它返回实际的字符串
But let's have it return the actual string.
我实际上可以干净利落地做这件事
And I can actually do this kind of cleanly.
让我在这里清除终端窗口中的错误消息
Let me clear my error message in my terminal window here.
让我把这里的循环去掉
Let me get rid of the loop here.
让我说这一次 好的 好的 猫咪会回来的
Let me say this time that OK, fine, meow is going to return
值、实际字符串或字符串
a value, an actual str or string.
因此 我将None更改为str
So I've changed none to str.
现在 我可以用任何方式来实现这一点
And now, I can implement this in any number of ways,
甚至可以使用循环
maybe even using a loop.
但回想一下 我们在Python中有这样的语法 我认为
But recall that we have this syntax in Python, which will, I think,
为我们解决这个问题
solve this problem for us.
如果我想返回一个由n个猫咪组成的字符串 我实际上可以做的是
If I want to return a string of n meows, what I can actually do,
回想一下 这就是
recall, is this.
返回引号 反斜杠n 乘以那个数字n
Return quote unquote meow, backslash n, times that number n.
所以这是一个巧妙的俏皮话 避免了
So it's kind of a clever one-liner, avoids
需要一个for循环或更复杂的东西
the need for a for loop or something more involved than that,
简单地说 将猫咪的反斜杠n对自己乘三次 或n次
to just say, multiply meow backslash n against itself three times, or n times,
在这种情况下 一般来说 这样我就可以得到一大串零叫 一
in this case, in general, so that I get back a big string of zero meows, one,
取而代之的是更多的两声、三声或更多的叫声
two, three, or many more meows instead.
我想现在我在第六行的代码实际上是正确的
I think now my code on line six is actually correct.
现在我已经改变了猫咪的行为方式
Now I've changed meow to behave the way I was
假装它总是奏效
pretending to assume it always worked.
所以我存储了一个str类型的变量
So I'm storing in meows plural a variable that's of type str.
因为现在 meow确实有一个字符串类型本身的返回值
Because now, meow does have a return value of type str itself
根据此类型提示也是如此
per this type hint as well.
好的
All right.
现在让我继续打印猫咪
Let me go ahead now and print meows.
但因为我的每个猫咪都有一个尾随的新行 反斜杠n
But because each of my meows comes with a trailing new line, the backslash n,
我要主动修复一个小小的审美缺陷
I'm going to proactively fix what would be a minor aesthetic bug.
我只想避免输出额外的新行
And I'm just going to avoid outputting an extra new line
在这三个国家的末尾
at the end of those three.
所以如果我现在运行Python of meows.py 输入3 这就是我的喵喵喵
So if I run Python of meows.py now, type in three, there's my meow meow meow.
而现在 什么都不提了
And now, no mention of none.
现在关于类型提示的问题 以及mypy中的这些注释
Questions now on type hints, and these annotations in mypy,
并使用它们来防御性地编写代码 希望这些代码能够减少
and using them to defensively write code that just decreases hopefully
你自己感染病毒的可能性有多大？
the probability of your own bugs?
学生：返回的三组是带双引号的吗？
STUDENT: Is the return three set have double quotes that
有猫咪斜杠n 为什么程序不把它当作[？字符串？？]
have meow slash n, why the program don't take it as a [? string? ?]
大卫·J·马兰：为什么节目不把它当作一种--奇怪的东西？
DAVID J. MALAN: Why does the program not take it as a-- as strange?
学生：[听不见] 是的
STUDENT: [INAUDIBLE], yeah.
大卫·J·马兰：回想一下在这堂课的早期
DAVID J. MALAN: So recall that early on in the class
我们将加号视为连接运算符
we looked at plus as a concatenation operator that
允许您在左侧和右侧连接字符串
allows you to join a string on the left and the right.
乘法也是字符串的重载运算符
Multiplication is also an overloaded operator for strings.
因此 如果左边有一个字符串 右边有一个整型
Whereby if you have a string on the left and an int on the right,
可以说 它将通过连接或连接来乘以字符串
it will multiply the string, so to speak, by concatenating or joining
那么多的猫叫加在一起
that many meows all together.
因此 这是面向对象编程的一个特性
So this is a feature of object-oriented programming
和我们过去看到的操作符重载
and an operator overloading as we saw it in the past.
关于类型提示或输入的其他问题
Other questions on type hints or mypy.
学生：我们能不能不对这个变量数字的数据类型进行类型转换？
STUDENT: Can we not typecast this data type of this variable number?
大卫·J·马兰：没有
DAVID J. MALAN: No.
你还是--让我更正一下术语
You still-- and let me correct the terminology.
在这种情况下 它不会被称为类型转换 因为它不像C#
It wouldn't be called typecasting in this context because it's not like C
或者C++ 在这些类型之间存在等价性
or C++ where there's an equivalence between these types.
从技术上讲 您正在将第5行的a str转换为int
You're technically converting on line five a str to an int.
你还是得这么做
You do still have to do this.
例如 因为Mypy会对你大喊大叫
Because mypy, for instance, would yell at you
如果您试图将右侧的字符串赋给左侧的int
if you were trying to assign a str on the right to an int on the left.
您仍然必须使用int函数
You must still use the int function.
INT本身仍然是一个函数
Int itself is still a function.
这不是类型提示
It's not a type hint.
但在这些类型提示中 int一词现在被以另一种方式使用
But the word int is being used in another way now in these type hints.
因此 这个int仍然是一个函数调用 一如既往
So this int is still a function call as it always has been.
左侧的语法是关键字int的另一种用法
This syntax on the left is another use of the keyword int
而是以这些类型提示的形式
but in the form of these type hints.
因此 您仍然需要自己进行转换
So you still have to do the conversion yourself.
好的
All right.
让我建议我们过渡到Python的另一个有价值的功能
Let me propose that we transition to another feature of Python that's worth
知道 特别是因为它是你会在野外看到的
knowing, especially since it's one that you'll see in the wild
当你看到其他人编写的代码或库时
when you see code or libraries that other folks have written,
即被称为文档字符串或文档字符串的东西
namely something known as a doc string or document strings.
事实证明 在巨蟒的世界里
It turns out in the world of Python there
是一种标准化的方式 根据另一个PEP Python增强提案 这一个
is a standardized way per another pep, Python Enhancement Proposal, this one
257 这实质上标准化了您应该如何记录您的功能
257, that essentially standardizes how you should document your functions
以及代码的其他方面
among other aspects of your code.
因此 例如 让我回到我的meows.py文件
And so, for instance, let me go back to my meows.py file here.
让我建议我们现在开始记录这些代码
And let me propose that we now start documenting this code
也是为了让我知道猫叫函数的作用
too so that I know what the meow function does.
事实上 使用文档字符串表示法进行此操作的标准方法
And in fact, the standard way of doing this using doc string notation
将如下所示
would be as follows.
注释此函数 而不是在其上方 因为您
To comment this function, not above it, as you
通常可能有处理代码的习惯 但实际上是在代码内部
might be in the habit of doing with code in general, but actually inside of it.
但不是像这样用通常的散列评论符号来评论它
But instead of commenting it like this with the usual hash comment sign,
就像猫叫n次一样 结果是当你正式对接时--
like meow n times, it turns out that when you're formally docking--
当您正式记录像这种情况下的meow这样的函数时
when you're formally documenting a function like meow in this case,
可以说 您不使用常规的内联注释
you don't use regular inline comments, so to speak.
您可以改用此语法
You use this syntax instead.
您可以使用三引号 可以是双引号 也可以是单引号
You use triple quotation marks, either double or single.
然后你写下你的评论 喵n次
Then you write out your comment, meow n times.
然后你在最后再写一遍同样的内容
And then you write the same again at the end.
所以要么是开头和结尾的三个双引号
So either three double quotes at the start and the end
或者在开头和结尾加三个单引号
or three single quotes at the start and the end.
而Python已经在其中内置了某些工具
And Python has built into it certain tools
以及某些假设 如果它检测到有使用
and certain assumptions that if it detects that there is a comment using
此文档字符串的格式为左右三引号
this doc string format triple quotes on the left and the right,
它将假定这确实是该函数的文档
it will assume that that's indeed the documentation for that function.
事实证明 在Python生态系统中 有很多工具
And it turns out in the Python ecosystem, there's a lot of tools
然后可以用它来自动分析代码 提取
that you can then use to analyze your code automatically, extract
所有这些文档字符串 甚至生成
all of these document strings for you, and even generate
网页或PDF文档 用于您自己的功能
web pages or PDFs of documentation for your own function.
因此 如果你遵守这些惯例 就会有这些惯例
So there's these conventions via which if you adhere to them
您可以开始为其他人记录您的代码
you can start documenting your code as for other people
通过从您自己的代码自动生成文档
by generating automatically the documentation from your own code
而无需手动从头开始编写内容
without writing something up from scratch manually.
现在 结果是如果您的函数确实接受参数
Now, it turns out if your function does take arguments
也许做得更多 关于如何做有多种约定
and perhaps does a bit more, there are multiple conventions for how
您可以为人类程序员记录
you can document for the human programmers that
可能正在使用你的功能 无论是你 还是同事
might be using your function, whether it's you, or a colleague,
或互联网上的其他人 实际使用这些文档
or someone else on the internet, to actually use these docs
字符串来标准化其中的信息
strings to standardize the information therein.
所以你可能会看到这个
So you might see this instead.
现在使用上面和下面相同的三重引号
Using these same triple quotes above and below now,
你可能会看到你对这个功能的一句话解释 喵--
you might see your one-sentence explanation of the function, meows--
喵叫n次
meow n times.
有时根据款式和用途
Sometimes depending on the style and use,
它实际上可能仍然在第一行 但它下面有一个空行
it might actually still be on the first line but with a blank line below it.
但我会把每一件东西都统一缩进
But I'll keep everything uniformly indented.
这是一些流行的Python文档工具使用的约定
And this is a convention used by some popular Python documentation tools
也是
as well.
您可以这样说语法--param n冒号 然后描述什么是n
You would say syntax like this-- param n colon, and then a description of what n
就是 猫叫的次数
is, number of times to meow.
然后是冒号类型n冒号int 这只表示n的类型
Then colon type n colon int, which just indicates that the type of n
是一个整数
is an integer.
然后 如果此函数实际上可以引发异常
Then, if this function could actually raise an exception,
您也可以记录这一点
you can document that too.
事实上 这并不是真的--
And actually, it's not really--
好吧 这可以说是我的错误
well, it's arguably my mistake here.
如果n作为自变量进入 并且实际上不是整型
If n comes in as an argument and is not, in fact, an int,
也许它是一个浮点 或者一个字符串 或者其他什么东西
maybe it's a float, or a string, or something else,
这里的乘法符号不起作用
the multiplication sign here is not going to work.
它不会使字符串倍增
It's not going to multiply the string.
根据我的经验 它将触发一个类型错误
It's going to trigger what I know from experience to be a type error.
所以我将继续在我自己的文档中积极地说
So I'm going to go ahead and proactively say in my own documentation
从技术上讲 这个函数如果使用不当 可能会引发类型错误
that this function, technically, if you use it wrong could raise a type error,
尽管我在这里用这个注解来暗示
even though I'm hinting up here with this annotation
您应该传入一个int
that you should pass in an int.
同样 Python不会强制执行这一点
Again, Python doesn't enforce that.
所以如果你传递一个浮点数 这可能 事实上
So if you pass in a float, this might, in fact,
引发此函数的类型错误
raise this function a type error.
因此 如果n不是整型 就可能发生这种情况
And so, that might happen if n is not an int.
最后 为了让其他程序员明白起见 我可能会说
And then, lastly, I might say for clarity's sake for other programmers,
此函数返回一个由n个猫叫声组成的字符串 每行一个
this function returns a string of n meows, one per line.
该值的返回类型 r类型 将是字符串
And the return type of that value, r type, is going to be str.
现在 我在这里使用的所有语法本身并不是Python
Now, all of this syntax here as I've used it is not Python per se.
这是一种称为重组文本的约定 它
This is a convention known as restructured text, which
是一种类似于标记的语言 它
is a form of markdown-like language that's
用于文档、网站、博客 甚至更多
used for documentation, for websites, for blogs, and even more.
但这是在Python世界中流行的约定之一
But it's one of the popular conventions within the world of Python
来记录您自己的功能
to document your own functions.
因此 这基本上与类型提示没有任何关系
So this does not have anything to do fundamentally with type hints.
类型提示是Python的一项功能
Type hints are a feature of Python.
我在这里所做的只是遵守第三方惯例
What I'm doing here is just adhering to a third party convention
从一开始就在一个Python文档字符串之间插入
of putting in between a Python doc string from the start
最后是某种标准格式 以便这些第三方工具可以
to the end a certain standard format so that these third party tools can
从上到下 从左到右分析我的代码
analyze my code for me top to bottom, left to right,
理想的情况是为我生成文档
and ideally generate documentation for me.
它可以生成PDF、网页或其他内容
It can generate a PDF, a web page, or something else,
这样我或我的同事就不需要仅仅写
so that I or my colleagues don't need to not just only write
代码 而且还手动为我们的代码创建文档
code but also manually create documentation for our code.
我们可以将所有东西放在一起 并使用工具为我们生成相同的东西
We can keep everything together and use tools to generate the same for us.
现在对这些文档字符串有什么问题吗？
Any questions now on these doc strings, which
同样 还有一个惯例是经常记录您自己的代码
again are a convention of documenting your own code often
遵循一些标准语法吗？
following some standard syntax?
学生：是的
STUDENT: Yeah.
所以 当你说你会把它记录下来并放到PDF中时
So when you say you would document it and put it in a PDF,
这样做的目的是发布它并共享您的功能吗
is the purpose of doing this to publish it and share your function
这样其他用户就可以使用它了吗？
so other users can use it?
大卫·J·马兰：当然
DAVID J. MALAN: Absolutely.
过去我们在安装一些第三方库的时候 比如说
In the past, when we have installed some third party libraries, for instance,
就在几周前
cowsay a few weeks back.
回想一下 我向您展示了它的功能
Recall that I showed you what functions it had.
但如果你读了文档 你可能真的
But if you read the documentation, you might actually
确保该程序的作者为我们记录了这一点
see that it was documented for us by the author of that program.
现在 我不相信他们在使用这种特殊的语法
Now, I don't believe they were using this particular syntax.
但这对你我来说绝对是有用的
But it was definitely useful for you and me
能够阅读一些网页或PDF 告诉我们如何使用图书馆
to be able to read some web page or PDF telling us how to use the library
而不是浪费时间阅读别人的代码
rather than wasting time reading through someone else's code
并试图推断存在哪些功能以及如何使用它们
and trying to infer what functions exist and how to use them.
它只是倾向于对开发人员更友好
It just tends to be much more developer-friendly to have
我们自己的代码或库的适当文档也是如此
proper documentation for our own code or libraries as well.
还有其他问题吗？
Other questions?
学生：是的
STUDENT: Yeah.
当使用文档字符串时 当它被用来生成PDF或其他什么时
When with doc strings, when it's used to generate a PDF or whatever,
它包括任何代码吗？
does it include any of the code?
因此 如果你在评论中引用了
So if you're referencing in your comment,
如果您在注释本身中引用代码 并且
if you're referencing the code in the comment itself and
如果没有看到代码 可能就没有意义了
might not make sense without seeing the code.
它--这些包括它吗？
Does it-- do these include it?
大卫·J·马兰：简而言之 你可以做到
DAVID J. MALAN: Short answer, you can do that.
不是在我在这里使用的惯例中
Not in the convention I'm using here.
但实际上有一种聪明的方法可以在您的文档字符串中写入
But there's actually a clever way to write in your doc strings
函数的样例输入和函数的样例输出
sample inputs to your functions and sample outputs for your functions.
如果您使用的是我们没有讨论过的其他工具
And if you use a different tool that we've not discussed,
该工具将使用这些样例输入运行您的代码
that tool will run your code using those sample inputs.
它将检查您的输出是否与您的样本输出匹配
It will check that your outputs match your sample outputs.
如果没有 程序就会对你大喊大叫 说你在某个地方出了问题
And if not, the program will yell at you saying, you've got a bug somewhere.
所以这是另一种你可以
So this is just another way where you can
使用文档字符串不仅可以记录代码 甚至可以捕获代码中的错误
use doc strings to not only document but even catch errors in your code.
这件事已经很多了
This has been a lot.
而且还有更多的事情要做
And there's a bit more to go.
为什么我们不在这里休息五分钟呢？
Why don't we go ahead here and take a five-minute break.
当我们继续时 我们将看看Python的另一个功能
And when we resume, we'll take a look at yet another feature of Python, yet
另一个更快编写代码的库
another library to write code faster.
好的
All right.
假设我们想要修改这个meow程序以实际接受它的输入 而不是
Suppose we want to modify this meows program to actually take its input not
从闪烁提示符中的输入功能 但从命令行
from the input function in the blinking prompt but from the command line.
回想一下 在我们讨论库时 您可以使用一些
Recall in our discussion of libraries, that you could use something
像sys.argv一样获取命令行参数
like sys.argv to get at command line arguments
当你运行你的程序时 人类所提供的
that a human has provided when you're running your program.
所以我们为什么不制作一个版本的猫咪呢
So why don't we whip up a version of meow
它使用命令行参数 而不是同样的输入
that uses command line arguments instead of, again, input.
因此 我将继续删除我们到目前为止所做的工作
So I'm going to go ahead and delete what we've done here thus far.
让我建议我们像过去一样导入系统
And let me propose that we import sys as we've done in the past.
让我们开始行动吧
And let's do this.
如果用户不键入任何命令行参数 情况会怎样？
How about if the user does not type any command line arguments.
那么我的程序只会猫叫一次 这样它就会
Then my program will just meow once, just so that it
做一些视觉上有趣的事情
does something visually interesting.
否则 我们还为用户提供一个选项
Otherwise, let's also give the user an option
来指定我想让猫叫几次
to specify how many times I want the cat to meow.
所以 让我们从简单的开始
So let's start simple.
首先 让我们继续做这件事
Let's first of all go ahead and do this.
如果sys.argv的长度等于1
If the length of sys.argv equals equals one,
也就是说 用户只输入程序的名称 之后不输入其他内容
that is the user only typed the name of the program and nothing else after
那--
the--
在他们的指挥下 那么我们就像这样打印出一只猫叫
in their command, then let's go ahead and just print out one meow like this.
否则 现在 让我们继续打印出类似这样的东西
Else for now, let's go ahead and print out something like this.
否则继续打印 比方说 用法
Else go ahead and print out, let's say, usage
对于该程序 将使用meows.py
for the program, which will be usage of meows.py,
只是为了让用户知道程序本身名为meows.py
just so that the user knows that the program itself is called meows.py.
现在 让我转到我的终端窗口 开始输入Python of meows.py
Now let me go down to my terminal window and start to type Python of meows.py.
此时 请注意sys.argv的长度
And at this point, notice that the length of sys.argv
确实应该是其中之一
should indeed be one.
为什么？
Why?
嗯 这个名字根本不会出现在sys.argv中
Well, Python the name doesn't end up in sys.argv at all ever.
但是meows.py 文件的名称是这样的
But meows.py, the name of the file does.
它将以sys.argv为零
And it's going to go in sys.argv zero.
但这只是其中一个因素
But that's only one element.
所以这个东西的长度是1
So the length of this thing is one.
右边没有更多的东西了
There's nothing more to the right.
所以 当我现在按回车键时 我们应该会看到 确实 一声喵叫
So when I hit Enter now we should see, indeed, one meow.
如果我不合作 假设我做了类似猫咪三次进入的事情
If I don't cooperate, suppose I do something like meows three Enter.
然后我会看到一个提醒 这就是你使用程序的方式
Then I'm going to see a reminder that this is how you use the program.
这是一种常见的约定 逐字打印出来
And this is a common convention to literally print out
单词用法 冒号 然后是程序的名称
the word usage, a colon, then the name of the program,
也许还有一些关于如何使用它的解释
and maybe some explanation of how to use it.
所以我把它弄得很简单
So I'm keeping it very simple.
但让我们更花哨一点
But let's be a little fancier.
如果我真的想让用户输入的内容不是三个 而是一些
What if I really wanted the user to type in maybe not three, but something
更加老练
more sophisticated.
事实上 当从命令行控制程序时
And in fact, when controlling programs from the command line,
提供通常被称为开关或标志的东西是非常常见的
it's very common to provide what are often called switches or flags,
借此传入类似破折号n的内容 这在语义上意味着
whereby you pass in something like dash n, which semantically means
这个次数 然后通常是一个空格
this number of times, then often a space,
然后是类似数字3的东西
and then something like the number three.
这仍然允许我在命令行做其他事情 如果我想的话
This still allows me to do other things at the command line if I want.
但事实上我已经标准化了我提供命令行的方式
But the fact that I've standardized on how I'm providing command line
此程序的参数为破折号n 3
arguments to this program with dash n three
只是我的程序现在更可靠的方式
is just a more reliable way now of my program
知道这三个字是什么意思
knowing what does the three mean.
如果我只做meows.py space Three 就不那么明显了
It's a little less obvious if I just do meows.py space three.
那么 这三个词是什么意思？
Well, what does the three mean?
至少使用像破折号nThree这样的语法 尤其是
At least with syntax like dash n three, especially
如果您已经阅读了此程序的文档
if you've read the documentation for this program,
最终 哦 破折号n表示次数
ultimately, oh, dash n means number of times.
明白了
Got it.
这是一种传递两个额外参数的方式
It's a way of passing in two additional arguments
但这两者之间有一定的联系
but that have some relationship between them.
那么 我如何修改我的程序以理解破折号n3呢？
So how do I modify my program to understand dash n three?
嗯 如果我像这样使用sys 我可以这样做
Well, if I'm using sys like this, I could do this.
如果sys.argv的长度这次等于三
elif the length of sys.argv equals this time three.
因为请注意 在我的提示下 有一、二、三件事
Because notice, there's one, two, three things at my prompt.
因此 sys.argv是由空格分隔的0、1和2、3个元素
So sys.argv is zero, one, and two, three things total separated by spaces.
如果等于三--
If it equals three--
为了安全起见 sys.argv括号1等于破折号n
and let's be safe, and sys.argv bracket one equals equals dash n,
那么让我们继续做这件事
then let's go ahead and do this.
让我们继续并将2的sys.argv转换为整数
Let's go ahead and convert sys.argv of two to an integer
并将其赋给一个变量 例如 名为n的变量
and assign it to a variable, for instance, called n.
然后 让我们继续这样做
And then, let's go ahead and do this.
对于n范围内的下划线 让我们继续
For underscore in the range of n, let's go ahead
打印出其中的一些猫咪叫声
and print out some of these meows.
现在 也许还有机会巩固我的印刷线
Now, there's still an opportunity maybe to consolidate my print lines
用猫叫
with meow.
但就目前而言 我将把这些想法分开
But for now, I'm going to keep these ideas separate.
所以我将像以前一样处理缺省情况 这里没有参数
So I'm going to handle the default case with no arguments up here as before.
现在 更有趣的是 我要把这一点讲清楚
And now, more interestingly, I'm going to do this to be clear.
我将检查用户是否向我提供了三个命令行参数 即名称
I'm going to check if the user gave me three command line arguments, the name
程序的名称、破折号n和一个数字
of the program, dash n, and a number.
如果他们在sys.argv中给我的第二个东西确实等于破折号n
If indeed the second thing they gave me in sys.argv of 1 equals equals dash n,
然后我将假设接下来的事情 sys.argv of Two
then I'm going to assume that the next thing, sys.argv of two
将是一个整数
is going to be an integer.
我会把它转换成这样 并存储在这个变量n中
And I'll convert it to such and store it in this variable n.
现在 只要使用一个循环 我就会打印出这么多次的猫咪
And now, just using a loop, I'm going to print out meow that many times.
好的 这是我们之前对循环的关注的一种结合
All right, so it's kind of a combination of our earlier focus on loops,
我们之前的重点是命令行参数
our earlier focus on command line arguments,
我只是在创建一个程序 让我可以宣称
just creating a program that allow me to claim
代表了许多命令行程序的工作方式
is representative of how a lot of command line programs work,
尽管我们通常不会像这样使用太多
even though we've typically not used many like this.
但这是非常常见的配置一个程序 一个
But it's very common to configure a program, one,
您将在命令行中使用某些内容运行它
you're about to run it at the command line with something
就像这些命令行参数 如破折号n或其他破折号
like these command line arguments like dash n or dash something else.
现在 我将继续并按Enter键
Now, I'm going to go ahead and hit Enter.
我想我应该看到 确实 三只猫叫
And I think I should see, indeed, three meows.
相比之下 如果我在最后做两次 我应该会看到两声喵叫
By contrast, if I do two at the end, I should see two meows.
如果我做了一次 我应该会看到一只猫叫
If I do one, I should see one meow.
坦率地说 如果我完全忽略这一点
And frankly, if I just omit this altogether,
我也应该看到一个猫咪 因为这是我之前的默认情况
I should see one meow as well, because that was my default case earlier.
现在 让我们假设这个项目最终
And now, let me allow us to assume that this program eventually
变得更复杂了
gets more complicated.
让我们想象一个我不想只支持破折号n的世界
Let's imagine a world where I don't want to support just dash n.
也许我想支持破折号a 破折号b 破折号c
Maybe I want to support dash a, and dash b, and dash c,
和破折号d 还有很多其他的
and dash d, and a whole lot of others.
或者 在这一点上 我应该给他们一些话
Or heck, at that point, I should maybe give them words.
所以可能是个破折号 破折号 数字
So maybe it's a dash, dash, number.
这确实是计算中的一个惯例
It's indeed a convention in computing typically
使用单破折号和一个字母 如n 但使用双破折号
to use single dashes with a single letter, like n, but use double dashes
如果你真的用了一个完整的词比如数字
if you're actually using a whole word like number.
所以命令行参数可能是破折号n 或者
So the command line argument might be dash n, or maybe
是破折号 破折号号码
it's dash, dash number.
但你可以想象这段代码有多复杂
But you can imagine just how complicated the code gets
如果现在您想支持破折号n、破折号a、破折号b、破折号c等等
if now you want to support dash n, dash a, dash b, dash c, and so forth.
你得到处检查
You're going to have to be checking all over the place.
如果它们的顺序不一样呢？
And what if they come in a different order?
你得先检查破折号
You're going to have to check is dash n first,
还是第二第三还是第四
or is it second, or is it third, or is it's fourth?
我的意思是 这只是变得非常痛苦非常快
I mean, this just becomes very painful very quickly
只是做一些相对简单的事情 比如允许用户传递命令
just to do something relatively simple like allow the user to pass command
将参数行放入程序中
line arguments into your program.
这就是为什么图书馆总是存在
Well, this is why, as always, there exist libraries.
Python附带的另一个库
And another library that comes with Python
可能值得了解的是这个叫做argparse的
that's probably worth knowing something about is this one here called argparse.
事实上 我自己或CS50的团队用Python编写了很多工具
In fact, with a lot of the tools I myself or CS50's team writes in Python,
我们经常使用argparse
we very frequently use argparse whenever they
比我们的课堂演示要复杂得多
are more complicated than a lot of our class demos and a little more similar
我们希望允许用户传入配置选项
to this one where we want to allow the user to pass in configuration options
在命令行中
at the command line.
通过支持破折号N 破折号A 破折号B 破折号C
And by supporting things like dash n, or dash a, or dash b, or dash c,
argparse是一个库
argparse is a library that per its documentation
可以说 它只是处理所有这些解析 这些命令行分析
just handles all of this parsing so to speak, this analysis of command line
自动为您提供参数 以便您可以专注于
arguments for you automatically so you can focus
编写程序中有趣的部分 而不是命令行
on writing the interesting parts of your program, not the command line
论点部分
arguments part.
那么我们该如何使用它呢？
So how might we use this?
让我们回到VS Code
Well, let me go back to VS Code here.
我来清空终端窗口
Let me clear my terminal window.
我建议用not sys重写这个代码
And let me propose that I rewrite this using not sys
但实际上使用的是argparse
but actually using argparse.
我先从简单的开始 然后再逐步完善
And I'm going to start a little simple and then build back up.
现在让我把所有这些都扔掉 转而导入argparse
So let me throw all of this away for now and instead import argparse.
Argparse是argument parser的缩写
Argparse stands for argument parser.
解析的意思是阅读它 把它拆开来分析
To parse something means to read it, kind of pick it apart to analyze it.
所以这对我来说确实是这样
So this is indeed going to do just that for me.
现在 让我继续做这个
Now, let me go ahead and do this.
对于这个图书馆来说
And for this library, it's helpful to know
一点面向对象的编程就像我们现在做的一样
a little object-oriented programming like we all now do.
我将创建一个名为parser的变量
I'm going to create a variable called parser.
不过 我想怎么叫都行
Though I could call it anything I want.
我将把它设置为等于argparse.ArgumentParser的返回值
I'm going to set it equal to the return value of argparse.ArgumentParser,
有一个大写的A和一个大写的P. A构造函数
with a capital A and a capital P. A constructor
Python自带的一个名为argument parser的类
for a class called argument parser that comes with Python itself
在这个图书馆里
within this library here.
现在 我要配置这个参数解析器
Now, I'm going to configure this argument parser
了解特定的命令行参数
to know about the specific command line arguments
我想在我的项目中支持的项目
that I myself want to support in my program.
所以我会这样做 parser.add_argument
So I'm going to do this, parser.add_argument.
这显然是解析器对象中的一个方法
So that's apparently a method in the parser object.
我要加一个破折号n的参数
I'm going to add an argument of dash n.
很简单
Easy enough.
现在我将继续实际解析命令行参数
Now I'm going to go ahead and actually parse the command line arguments.
我将使用args 或者我可以将变量命名为任何值
I'm going to do args, or I could call the variable anything
我想要 解析器 解析器
I want, parser.parseargs.
默认情况下 parseargs会自动为我查找sys.argv
And by default, parseargs is going to automatically look at sys.argv for me.
我不需要自己导入sys
I don't need to import sys myself.
我可以留下参数解析器 它的代码来导入sys 看看sys.argv
I can leave the argument parser, its code to import sys, look at sys.argv,
找出破折号N或其他东西的实际位置
and figure out where dash n or anything else actually is.
好的是 这行代码
And what's nice now, because this line of code
这里导致解析器已经解析了所有的命令行参数
here results in the parser having parsed all of the command line arguments,
我现在在变量args中有了这个对象
I now have this object in this variable called args inside
其中所有的值都是这些命令的值
of which are all of the values of those command
行参数 不管它们以什么顺序出现
line arguments, no matter what order they appeared in.
当我只有一个的时候没什么大不了的 因为它只是
Not such a big deal when I've only got one because it's only
最后要去一个地方
going to go in one place at the end.
但如果我有破折号n 破折号a 破折号b 破折号c
But if I've got dash n, dash a, dash b, dash c,
你可以想象它们的顺序都不同
you could imagine them being in all different orders.
它们绝对不一定要按字母顺序排列
They definitely don't have to be alphabetical.
用户应该能够以他们想要的任何顺序键入它们
The user should be able to type them in any order they want.
这在可用性方面更好
That's better for usability.
Arg Parser将为我解决所有这些问题
Arg parser is going to figure all of that out for me.
我现在要做的就是这个
And all I have to do now is this.
如果我想迭代这么多数量的参数
If I want to iterate over that many numbers of arguments
更确切地说 这么多猫叫 我能做到
and that many meows rather, I can do this.
用于在args.n的int转换范围内加下划线
For underscore in the range of the int conversion of args.n.
因此 点是我们一直使用的访问内容的语法
So dot is the syntax we kept using to access things
就像对象内部的属性一样
like properties inside of an object.
这就是ARGS的含义
And that's what args is.
它是parse args函数为我返回的对象
It's the object returned by the parse args function for me.
我现在要继续 打印出来 引用引语 猫叫这么多次
I'm going to go ahead now and print out, quote unquote, meow this many times.
所以这并不是非常简单
So it's not super simple.
这是我需要编写并理解的三行新代码
These are three new lines of code I need to write and rather understand.
但它已经更简单、更紧凑了
But it's already a little simpler and more compact
而不是我的IF、ELIF、OR、AND 以及所有的布尔逻辑
than my if, and my elif, and my ors, and my ands, and all of that Boolean logic.
它为我处理了很多这样的事情
It's handling a lot of this for me.
因此 如果我没有犯任何错误 现在让我在meows.py Enter中运行Python
So if I didn't make any mistakes, let me run Python now of meows.py Enter.
我确实在这里犯了一个错误
And I did make a mistake here.
我确实犯了一个错误
I did make a mistake.
现在这里出什么问题了？
What's wrong here now?
怎么了？
What's wrong?
嗯 我绝对没有按照我想要的方式来经营
Well, I definitely didn't run it the way I intend.
因此 破折号n三次进入
So dash n three Enter.
所以它确实起作用了
So it does work.
但如果我不合作 这实际上似乎是一个更糟糕的版本
But if I don't cooperate, this actually seems to be a worse version.
如果我没有传入破折号n和一个数字 它只会因为输入错误而出错
If I don't pass in dash n and a number, it just errors with a type error.
Int必须是字符串
Int must be a string.
没有一个是得到回报的
None is what came back.
所以很明显这里有一个错误
So there's clearly an error here.
但图书馆更加灵活
But the library is more flexible.
实际上 我可以提供一些关于如何使用这个东西的文档
I can actually provide some documentation on how to use this thing.
那我怎么知道怎么用这个呢？
So how do I know how to use this?
嗯 通常在Python语言中是常规的
Well, typically it's conventional in Python
并在许多编程环境中运行程序
and in a lot of programming environments to run a program
带有特殊参数的破折号h或破折号帮助
with a special argument, dash h or dash dash help.
我几乎总是会说 到那时你会
And almost always I will claim you'll then
查看某种用法信息
see some kind of usage information.
事实上 这就是我现在看到的
And indeed, that's what I'm looking at now.
我刚刚运行了Python of meows.py空格破折号h
I just ran Python of meows.py space dash h.
我会再来一次
I'll do it again.
让我清除我的屏幕 这一次用英语做破折号帮助 回车
Let me clear my screen and this time do dash dash help in English, Enter.
我也看到了同样的事情
And I see the same thing.
目前它并不是很有用
It's not very useful at the moment.
它只是告诉我这里的用法是什么
It just shows me what the usage is up here.
这是一种有趣的现象
And this is kind of interesting.
这是计算中的标准语法
This is a standard syntax in computing.
我们以前在Python的文档中看到过这一点
And we've kind of seen it in Python's documentation before.
当然 这只是意味着程序的名称是meows.py
This just means that the program's name is, of course, meows.py.
方括号在文档中几乎总是这样 这意味着它是可选的
Square brackets as almost always in documentation means it's optional.
所以我不需要输入破折号h 但我可以
So I don't have to type dash h, but I can.
我不需要输入破折号n和另一个值 但我可以
I don't have to type dash n and another value, but I can.
然后 下面是对这些选项的一些解释
And then, down here is some explanation of these options,
更详细地告诉我 我也可以
and more verbosely showing me that I can also
DASH DASH帮助 而不是DASH
do dash dash help and not just dash h.
但这太普通了
But this is so generic.
这和我的计划无关
This has nothing to do with my program.
这不会对我的用户有所帮助 因为我实际上
This is not going to help my users when I actually
向全世界发布这款软件
release this software for the world.
因此 让我继续改进它
So let me go ahead and improve it.
让我在我的参数解析器中添加一个人类将会看到的描述
Let me add a description to my argument parser that the humans will see.
像猫一样叫 引述 将是这个名字的价值
Meow like a cat, quote unquote, is going to be the value of this named
参数称为Description
parameter called description.
我还可以在我的破折号n中添加一个帮助参数
And let me also add a help parameter to my dash n
这个论点只是解释了破折号n的意思 猫咪的次数
argument that just explains what dash n means, number of times to meow,
引用不引用
quote unquote.
我不会再做任何改变了
I'm not going to change anything else.
但我将返回到我的终端窗口 运行Python of Meow
But I am going to go back to my terminal window and run Python of meow.
我将运行Python of meows.py dash h 或者等效破折号Help
I'm going to run Python of meows.py dash h, or equivalently dash dash help.
现在请注意 这对用户更加友好
And now notice that this is a little more user friendly.
如果我向上滚动 我们仍然可以看到相同的用法
If I scroll up, we still see the same usage.
但是有一句简单的英语解释
But there's a quick sentence in English of explanation
这个程序的猫叫声就像猫一样
that this program meows like a cat.
如果我现在看看选项 哦 这就是n的意思
And if I look at the options now, oh, that's what n means.
这是猫咪叫的次数
It's the number of times to meow.
这个大写的N 一个心理变量 如果你愿意的话
And this capital N, a mental variable, if you will,
只是向我表明我需要按照惯例键入一个数字
is just indicating to me that I need to type a number by convention
在小写的破折号n之后
after the lower case dash n.
所以 尽管如此 还是很好的
So it would be nice though, all that said,
如果我的程序在没有任何命令行的情况下运行时仍然没有崩溃
if my program still didn't just break when I run it without any command line
争论
arguments.
理想情况下 我的程序会像处理我的手动版本一样处理这件事
Ideally, my program would handle this just like my manual version
当我自己使用sys.argv时就是这样
did when I used sys.argv myself.
因此 我们只需要向该库添加更多功能
So we just need to add a little more functionality to this library.
如果我阅读文档 我会看到Add参数
And if I read the documentation, I'll see that add argument
接受另一个命名参数
takes yet another named argument.
如果需要 可以为破折号n指定一个默认值 例如1
If you want, you can specify a default value for dash n, for instance, one.
我会在那里做的
And I'll do that there.
你可以进一步指定它必须是一个整型
And you can further specify that it's got to be an int.
这还能让我做些什么呢
And what this will additionally allow me to do
就是如果我告诉arg解析器确保破折号n的值是一个整数
is if I tell arg parser to make sure that the value of dash n is an int,
我不需要手动进行转换
I don't need to do the conversion manually.
我可以在7号线上相信 当
I can just trust down on line seven that when
我访问Args对象中名为n的属性
I access the property called n inside of my args object,
对我来说 这将自动成为一个整型
it's going to be automatically an int for me.
再说一次 这就是图书馆的价值
And again, this is the value of a library.
让它为你做所有的工作 这样你就可以回来了
Let it do all of the work for you so you can get back
专注于手头的有趣项目
to focusing on the interesting project at hand,
不管你要解决的是什么问题
whatever problem it is you're trying to solve.
在这种情况下 诚然 没有那么有趣 但像猫一样喵叫
In this case, granted, not that interesting, but meowing like a cat.
现在让我继续运行Python of meows.py并按Enter键
Let me go ahead now and run Python of meows.py and hit Enter.
这一次 没有争论
This time, no arguments.
现在它在猫咪叫
And now it meows.
为什么？
Why?
因为我指定如果我作为用户不指定破折号n
Because I specified that if I don't, as a user, specify dash n,
很明显 它的缺省值为1
it's going to have a default value of one apparently.
而且我不必将该值从字符串转换为整型
And I don't have to convert that value from a str to an int
因为我告诉Arg解析器 请为我设置一个整型
because I told arg parser please just make this an int for me.
现在有任何关于argparse的问题吗 或者实际上是关于这个原理的问题
Any questions now on argparse, or really this principle
只是外包商品的东西 每个人的程序
of just outsourcing the commodity stuff, the stuff that everyone's program
最终需要这样做 这样你才能专注于你自己最有趣的部分
eventually needs to do so that you can focus on the juicy part yourself.
学生：args.n包含什么？
STUDENT: What does args.n contain?
大卫·J·马兰：Ars.n包含什么？
DAVID J. MALAN: What does args.n contain?
它包含人类在破折号n后的空格后键入的整数
It contains the integer that the human typed after a space after dash n.
问得好
Good question.
还有其他问题吗？
Other questions?
学生：是的
STUDENT: Yeah.
当您指定参数的类型时
When you specify the type for the argument, what
如果--这是否基本上处理用户输入的异常
happens if-- does that basically handle the exception if the user inputs
在这种情况下是一根线吗？
a string in this case?
大卫·J·马兰：这是一个非常好的问题
DAVID J. MALAN: A really good question.
假设人类没有键入数字 因此也没有输入
Suppose that the human does not type a number and therefore not an in.
好吧 让我们看看会发生什么
Well, let's see what happens.
所以 巨蟒的meows.py破折号n狗 其中狗显然不是一个数字
So Python of meows.py dash n dog, where dog is obviously not a number.
进来吧
Enter.
看 我们看到一条自动生成的错误消息
And voila, we see an automatically generated error message.
诚然 这有点神秘
A little cryptic, admittedly.
但我看到了一个提醒 它的用法是什么
But I'm seeing a reminder of what the usage is
以及对这一点的无效之处的一个次要解释
and a minor explanation of what is invalid about this.
再一次 这是允许你 这是
And again, this is what allows you, this is
是什么让我能够专注于编写我们真正关心的代码
what allows me to focus on writing the actual code we care about
只是让图书馆为我们自动处理一些东西
and just letting the library automate some of this stuff for us.
好的
All right.
好吧 请允许我提议 现在我们来看看另一个特征
Well, allow me to propose now that we take a look at one other feature
我们以前见过的巨蟒
of Python that we've seen before.
但事实证明 随着我们的程序变得更加强大 我们可以更有效地使用它
But it turns out we can use it even more powerfully as our programs become
变得更加复杂 我们试图解决的问题就会变成
more sophisticated and the problems we're trying to solve themselves become
更多的参与
more involved.
让我继续前进 转到VS Code 结束meows.py
Let me go ahead and turn to VS Code, closing out meows.py,
例如 创建一个名为unpack.py的新文件
and creating a new file for instance, called unpack.py.
所以unpack.py的代码
So code of unpack.py.
让我来提醒我们 拆开行李是什么意思
And let me just remind us what we mean by unpacking.
因为这实际上是我们以前见过的Python的一个特性
Because this is actually a feature of Python that we've seen before.
例如 假设我编写了一个程序
For instance, suppose that I write a program that
提示用户输入他们的名字 如David space Malan
prompts the user for their name, like David space Malan.
如果我们可以拆分用户名不是很好吗
Wouldn't it be nice if we could split the user's name
变成两个独立的变量？
into two separate variables?
当我们在过去做到这一点时 我们用了几种不同的方式
And when we've done this in the past, we've done it in a few different ways.
但其中一项涉及拆解从那里返回的单一价值
But one of them involved unpacking a single value that comes back from that,
类似于列表或一些其他数据结构
like a list or some other data structure,
并立即将其转化为两个变量
and putting it immediately into two variables.
所以让我们在这里开始吧
So let's do this here.
让我们继续调用输入函数
Let me go ahead and call the input function,
问别人你叫什么名字 问号
asking someone what's your name, question mark.
然后 让我继续 只是在一个单独的空格上有点天真地分开
Then, let me go ahead and just split a little naively on a single space.
所以我假设目前唯一的用户
So I'm assuming that the only users at the moment
是不是像我这样的人 大卫·斯派克·马兰
are people like me, David space Malan.
没有中间名 没有多个名字
No middle names, no multiple names.
它只有一个和两个 这本身就可能对其他用户来说是错误的
It's just one and two, which itself could be buggy for other users.
但现在 我简单地说 只是为了提醒我们
But for now, I'm keeping it simple, just to remind us
我现在可以用类似于first这样代码来解包返回值
that I can now unpack that return value with something like first
最后一个下划线等于输入的返回值
underscore last equals the return value of input.
现在我可以继续做这样的事情
And now I can go ahead and do something like this,
就像用f字符串打印 Hello 逗号 然后用大括号括起来
like printing out with an f string, Hello, comma, and then in curly braces,
第一
first.
如果我只是想问候自己或任何其他用户 您好 大卫
If I just want to greet myself or any other user as, Hello, David,
没有姓氏
without the last name.
坦率地说 如果我不用姓
And frankly, if I'm not using the last name,
回想一下 一个Python约定只是将其命名为下划线 以表明
recall that a Python convention is just to name it underscore to make clear
你知道你没有使用那个值
that you know you're not using that value.
但它确实需要存在 因为您同时解包了两个值
But it does need to be there because you're unpacking two values at once.
因此 如果我运行这个程序 它不会那么陌生
So if I run this, it won't be all that unfamiliar.
我现在要运行的是unpack.py的Python
I'm just going to run now Python of unpack.py.
我将输入David Malan 它只有一个空格
I'll type in David Malan, which has a single space.
现在我们看到了 你好 逗号 大卫
And there we have it, Hello, comma, David.
好吧 事实证明 还有其他方法可以解开价值
Well, it turns out that there's other ways to unpack values.
此外 Python还提供了其他功能 尤其是
And there's other features that Python offers, especially
在定义和使用函数时
when it comes to defining and using functions.
这是稍微多一点的中间功能
And this is slightly more intermediate functionality,
如果你愿意 这是很有用的 因为你可以
if you will, that's useful, because you can
开始编写更优雅、更强大的代码 一旦您
start to write even more elegant and powerful code once you
熟悉这样的语法
get comfortable with syntax like this.
所以让我继续并建议我们不只是玩
So let me go ahead and propose that we not just play with,
你好的名字了 但相反 做一些也许
Hello names anymore, but instead do something maybe
又牵扯到毒品了
involving some coinage again.
所以也许不是美元和美分 但也许
So maybe not dollars and cents, but maybe,
又像过去一样 一些大帆船和镰刀
again, as in the past, some galleons, and sickles,
其中有一个数学关系
and knuts which among which there's a mathematical relationship as
魔法世界里有多少人是平等的
to how many of those in the wizarding world equal each other.
让我继续做这个
And let me go ahead and do this.
让我定义一个简单的函数total它告诉我
Let me define a simple function called total that just tells me
一个人在古灵阁的金库的总价值 巫师银行
the total value of someone's vault in Gringotts, the wizarding bank, based
他们有多少加隆 镰刀和坚果
on how many galleons, sickles, and knuts that they have,
这些都是魔法世界的货币
which again, are currencies from the wizarding world as opposed
我们真实的人类世界
to our actual human world.
所以这个total函数可能会接受一个像加隆和镰刀这样的变量
So this total function might take a variable like galleons and sickles
还有这样的坚果
and knuts like this.
然后 它会返回公式 我承认
And then, it's going to return the formula, which I admittedly
我自己也不得不抬头
had to look up myself.
事实证明 将加隆和镰刀
And it turns out that the formula for converting galleons and sickles
就是这个
to knuts would be this.
加隆乘以17再加上镰刀 再乘以29
Galleons times 17 plus sickles, then times all of that by 29 and then
添加单个knuts
add in the individual knuts.
不知道这在书或电影中有什么细节
Not sure in what detail this came up in the books or movies.
但我们有了官方公式
But here we have it, the official formula.
好吧
All right.
现在我们开始吧
Now let's go ahead and do this.
让我们继续 只使用一些样本输入来调用total函数
Let me go ahead and call the total function with just some sample inputs.
假设像哈利这样的人有100加隆、50镰刀和25克努特
Suppose that someone like Harry has 100 galleons, 50 sickles, and 25 knuts.
让我把它打印在屏幕上
Let me go ahead and print that out on the screen.
如果total返回一个整数 我认为这个算术表达式
Well, if total returns an integer, which I think this arithmetic expression
我会做的 让我继续存储 而是传递total的返回值
will do, let me go ahead and store, rather, pass the return value of total
打印.
to print.
为了清楚起见 让我在最后写上Knuts 所以呢？
And then just for clarity, let me write knuts at the end So?
我知道这里的度量单位确实是knuts总数
I know that the unit of measure here is indeed knuts in total.
现在 让我在终端窗口中
Now, let me go ahead in my terminal window
运行unpack.py的Python并按Enter键
and run Python of unpack.py and hit Enter.
从数学上看 如果我的数学是正确的
And it turns out mathematically that if I got my math correct,
100艘帆船加50把镰刀再加25克朗等于50,775克朗
100 galleons plus 50 sickles plus 25 knuts equals in total 50,775 knuts.
只是为了避免在这里使用我们自己的人类货币
Just avoiding having to use our own human currency here.
但至少到目前为止 我还没有做任何拆包的事情
But I'm not doing anything along the lines of unpacking at least just yet.
既然我这样做了 让我来求婚吧
Let me propose now that I do this.
为了便于讨论 让我提议
Just for the sake of discussion, let me propose
我让整个函数保持原样
that I leave the total function as is.
但让我继续下去 把我所有的硬币都存储在一个列表中
But let me go ahead and just store all of my coins in a list.
所以硬币按从左到右的顺序 100 50 25 它
So coins in order from left to right, 100, 50, 25, it
只是因为不管这个故事的目的是什么
just because for whatever purposes in this story
我把我所有的硬币都按这个顺序列在一张单子上
I have all of my coinage in a list in this order.
有点像钱包或钱包
Kind of a purse or wallet of sorts.
好吧 我怎么才能把这个传进去呢？
Well, how can I pass this in?
好吧 我不会两次硬编码相同的值
Well, I'm not going to hard-code the same values twice.
只是为了讨论 我怎么能
Just for the sake of discussion, how could I
是否将列表的各个元素传递给我的Total函数？
pass in the individual elements of a list to my total function?
当然 我可以一如既往地对待这份名单
Well, of course, I could treat this list as I always
使用数字索引 通过将硬币放在括号0中
do using numeric indices by doing coins bracket zero,
硬币括号一 硬币括号二
coins bracket one, coins bracket two.
所以这是老派的东西 有清单
So this is old-school stuff with lists.
如果我有一个名为Coins的清单 有三个元素
If I've got a list called coins and there's three elements,
这些元素的索引或索引分别为0、1和2
the indices or indexes of those elements are zero, one, and two respectively
从左到右
from left to right.
所以我现在要做的就是传入第一个元素
So all I'm doing here now is passing in the first element
从大帆船的名单中 第二个元素是镰刀
from that list as galleons, the second element of that list as sickles,
这张清单的第三个元素是我的坚果
and the third element of this list as my knuts.
当然 这与签名一致
And that lines up with, of course, the signature
这个函数 正如Total所期望的那样 我已经传递了这三个
of this function, which as total expects that I've passed in those three
事物按从左到右的顺序排列
things in that order left to right.
让我继续跑吧 只是为了确保我没有摔断
Let me go ahead and run, just to make sure I haven't broken
任何内容 解包.py并按Enter键
anything, unpack.py and hit Enter.
而且 算术仍然是正确的
And the math still checks out.
但这变得有点冗长了--
But this is getting a little verbose--
有点长篇大论
a little verbose.
如果我能把硬币清单递给你
And wouldn't it be nice if I could just pass the list of coins
到这个总的功能吗？
to this total function?
如果我能说点什么就好了 硬币
Wouldn't it be nice if I could just say something like this, coins.
但让我停下来问一下大家 为什么这实际上不能像现在这样工作？
But let me pause and ask the group, why would this not actually work as is?
从技术上讲 这三个都通过了
It technically is passing in all three.
但是为什么我运行这个的时候会出现错误呢？
But why would I get some kind of error when I run this?
埃里克？
Eric?
因为你要把一份名单交给大帆船
STUDENT: Because you are passing a list to galleons.
DAVID J. MALAN：是的
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah.
我给加隆发了一份名单 没有给镰刀和坚果的
I'm passing a list to galleons and nothing for sickles and knuts.
请注意 它们没有默认值
And notice, those don't have default values.
第一行没有等号
There's no equal signs on that first line
这意味着Python不会知道
of code, which means Python is not going to know
这里应该假定什么值
what value should be assumed there.
所以看起来好像是行不通的
So it just seems like it's not going to work.
另外 这是错误的类型 正如埃里克所指出的
Plus, it's the wrong type, as Eric notes.
它是一个列表 而不是之前的整数
It's a list and it's not an integer as it was before.
让我们运行这个错误的版本
So let's actually run this incorrect version,
Python of unpack.py Enter type error.
Python of unpack.py Enter, type error.
这可能是你所期望的
And that is probably what you might expect,
就像我把这里的人搞得一团糟
like I'm messing up with the types here.
我需要传入两个位置参数 sickles
And I am required to pass in two positional arguments, sickles
和knuts 甚至没有通过
and knuts, that were not even passed.
所以我肯定犯了错
So I've definitely erred here.
但如果唯一的解决办法
But it certainly seems unfortunate if the only solution to this
就是做我之前做的 索引到第一个元素 index
is to do what I previously did, which is index into the first element, index
索引到第三个元素
into the second element, index into the third.
你可以想象 有了更大的功能
You can imagine, with bigger fancier functions that
我会用更多的论证 这会变得非常冗长
take even more arguments, this is going to get very verbose and honestly
很容易受到错误的影响 我的错别字
very vulnerable, potentially, to just mistakes, typos on my part.
但这里也是你可以做已知的事情的地方
But here too is where you can do what's known, again,
在Python中解包一个值
as unpacking a value in Python.
现在 一个列表包含多个值
Right now, a list is packed with multiple values.
我当前的列表有这三个值 分别为100、50和25
My current list has these three values, 100, 50, and 25 respectively.
但它们都在这张单子上
But they're all packed up in this one list.
如果我能打开那张单子
Wouldn't it be nice if I could unpack that list,
就像我之前解包str类的拆分的返回值一样
just like I previously unpacked the return value of the str class's split
功能也有很多
function into multiple things too.
事实上 我可以做到
And indeed, I can do just that.
事实上 Python允许我传递的不是硬币 而是星币
Python actually allows me to pass in not coins but star coins.
因此 如果您在变量的开头使用单个星号
So if you use a single asterisk at the beginning of your variable,
这会把它拆开的
that will unpack it.
它将需要一个序列 在这里是三个大小的硬币
And it will take one sequence, in this case coins of size three,
如果你愿意的话 把它分解成三个单独的论点
and explode it, if you will, unpack it into three individual arguments.
不需要逗号
No commas are needed.
Python只会为您处理这一点
Python just handles this for you.
但传递星币的效果是
But the effect of passing in star coins is
传递该名单中的个别成员
to pass in the individual members of that list.
在这种情况下 它们将分别是100、50和25
Which in this case are going to be 100, 50, and 25 respectively.
这很完美 因为现在它将与大帆船排成一列
Which is perfect, because now it's going to line up with galleons,
分别是镰刀和坚果
sickles, knuts respectively.
所以现在 当我运行unpack.py的Python时 我们又回到了业务中
So now when I run Python of unpack.py, we're back in business
算术证明了这一点
and the math checks out.
但我已经通过引入这个新符号来清理我的代码 它
But I've cleaned up my code by just introducing this new symbol, which
当然 我们已经在乘法和类似的其他上下文中使用过
we've used, of course, in other contexts for multiplication and the like.
但现在 它也被用来以这种方式拆包
But now, it's also used for unpacking in this way.
对我们刚刚做的事有疑问吗？
Questions on what we've just done?
它是一个单一的运营商 但它已经相当强大了
It's a single operator, but it's already quite powerful.
因为它允许我们提取数据结构并将其解包
Because it allows us to take a data structure and unpack it
并逐一传递
and pass it in individually.
学生：这对元组、集合、字典、字典也适用吗？
STUDENT: Does that work for tuples, sets, dicts, dictionaries as well?
大卫·J·马兰：是的 Tuples
DAVID J. MALAN: Tuples, yes.
套装我不知道
Sets I don't know.
[?兰申？？]我不知道秩序是否得到了维护
[? Ranshin? ?] I don't know if order is preserved.
不是的
No.
哦 是不是没有 还是你在查？
Oh, is that no it does not, or you're checking?
秩序没有得到维护
Order's not preserved.
所以它不能和SET一起工作？
So it wouldn't work with set?
它不适用于SET
It does not work with set.
不适用于SET
Does not work with set.
抱歉 我在这里用语音搜索只是为了省去一些按键
Sorry, I'm verbally googling here just to save us some keystrokes.
因此 它适用于秩序确实保持不变的枚举
So it would work for enumerations that where order is indeed preserved.
稍后我们将看到另一个例子
And we'll see another example in a moment
它实际上可以在词典中以不同的方式使用
where it actually can be used in a different way for dictionaries,
它现在确实维持着秩序
which nowadays do preserve order.
关于用这种方式拆包还有什么问题吗？
Other questions on unpacking in this way?
学生：是的
STUDENT: Yes.
嗨
Hi.
大卫·J·马兰：你好
DAVID J. MALAN: Hello.
学生：你能用解包的方法得到值吗 比如10加50
STUDENT: Can you use unpacking to get the value, for example 10 plus 50
加25而不是for循环 然后结果加？
plus 25 instead of a for loop and then result plus?
大卫·J·马兰：简短的回答是否定的
DAVID J. MALAN: Short answer, no.
如果您想要单个值 您应该只对其进行索引 在本例中
If you want the individual values, you should be just indexing, in this case,
进入那些特定的地点
into those specific locations.
这将返回多个值 相当于逗号分隔的列表
This is returning multiple values, the equivalent of a comma separated list.
因此 如果您使用较早的方法
So you would use the earlier approach if you
关心各个地点
cared about the individual locations.
还有一个关于拆包的问题怎么样？
How about one other question on unpacking?
学生：如果我们宣布--
STUDENT: What if we have declared--
我们声明了一些缺省值
we declare some default values.
如果你用这个作为两个点 它会正确地出去 还是会跳过它？
And if you use this as two points, will it go out right, or will it skip it?
大卫·J·马兰：问得好
DAVID J. MALAN: Good question.
如果我没听错 比如
If I heard you right, what if, for instance,
该列表在这里有四个类似的值 而您仍在将其解包
the list has four values like this here and you're still unpacking it
当只有三个人的时候 这是意料之中的
when it's only three that's expected.
好吧 让我们试一试
Well, let's try it.
Python of unpack.py Enter
Python of unpack.py Enter.
另一个类型错误
Another type error.
这一次 它需要三个立场论点 但给出了四个
This time it takes three positional arguments but four were given.
因此 作为程序员 我们有责任在这种情况下不这样做
So the onus is on us as the programmer not to do that in this case.
所以可能很脆弱 但如果我是
So potentially fragile, but avoidable if I'm
控制此列表的内容
controlling the contents of this list.
事实上 让我提议现在我们来看看这个的另一个变种
In fact, let me propose now that we take a look at another variant of this.
因此 我们不仅使用位置论元
Whereby we use not just positional arguments,
我们相信第一种是帆船 第二种是镰刀
whereby we trust that the first is galleons, the second is sickles,
第三个是克努茨
the third is knuts.
假设我们实际上传递了名称 就像我们在Python中被允许做的那样
Suppose that we actually passed in the names as we're allowed to do in Python.
然后 从技术上讲 我们可以按任何顺序传递它们
And then, technically, we could pass them in in any order
而Python会使用命名参数来解决这个问题
and Python would figure it out using named parameters instead.
好吧 我该怎么做呢？
Well, how might I do this?
嗯 一开始会有一点倒退
Well, it's going to be a bit of a regression at first.
因此 让我在这里删除这个列表
So let me get rid of this list here.
现在让我将其更改为仅手动传递我关心的值
Let me change this now to just manually passing the values I care about.
大帆船 我想还是等于100
Galleons I want to still equal 100.
Sickles我想等于50
Sickles I want to equal 50.
和坚果 我想等于25
And knuts I want to equal 25.
所以这是老式的参数传递
So this is old-school parameter passing.
它不再是定位的
It's no longer positional.
我正在显式地指定这些参数的名称
I'm explicitly specifying the names of these arguments.
但这会奏效的 因为这是
But that's just going to work because that's
我的Total函数中这些参数的名称到底是什么
exactly what the names of these parameters are in my total function
和以前一样
as before.
尽管如此 让我们确保我没有打碎任何东西
Let's make sure I, nonetheless, did not break anything.
让我们运行unpack.py Enter的Python
Let's run Python of unpack.py Enter.
我们有了它 还有50775克朗
And there we have it, still 50,775 knuts.
好吧 一旦你开始给事物命名和取值 命名和取值
Well, once you start giving things names and values, names and values,
这可能会让人想起我们最通用的数据之一
that probably should bring to mind one of our most versatile data
结构 甚至是字典中的结构
structures in Python and even other languages, that of a dictionary.
请记住 字典只是键值对、名称的集合
Remember that a dictionary is just a collection of key value pairs, names
以及他们各自的价值观
and their respective values.
因此 这种方式打开了一个机会
So this kind of opens up an opportunity.
如果我这么做了呢
What if I did this.
如果由于某种原因 我的程序中确实有一个变量
What if I actually had for some reason in my program on a variable
和以前一样 它被称为硬币
as before called coins.
但不是像以前那样将其列为三个值的列表
But instead of making it a list of three values like before,
如果它是一本合适的词典呢？
what if it's a proper dictionary?
所以如果是大帆船 引用引号 其中100个是冒号100
So what if it's galleons, quote unquote, colon 100 for 100 of those,
Sickles引用了其中的50个 Knuts引用了其中的25个
sickles quote unquote and 50 of those, and knuts quote unquote 25 of those,
每一个都用冒号隔开
each of those separated by colons.
让我把我的方括号固定到这个时间
And let me fix my square brackets to this time
花括号 回想一下 这是我们在词典中使用的符号
be curly braces, which, recall, is the symbol we use for dictionaries
或在Python中对对象进行DICT
or dict objects in Python.
所以现在 我有一本叫Coins的词典
So now, I have a dictionary called coins.
不是一份名单
Not a list.
它是钥匙和价值的集合 三把钥匙 帆船 镰刀 坚果
It's a collection of keys and values, three keys, galleons, sickles, knuts,
和三个值 分别为100、50和25
and three values, 100, 50, and 25 respectively.
如果我现在将这些单独的值传递到我的总函数中
If I were to now pass these individual values into my total function,
我可以用我的词典一如既往地做这件事
I could do it as always with my dictionary.
所以我现在用老派的方式来做
So I'm doing it old-school now.
硬币是我词典的名字
Coins is the name of my dictionary.
我不像列表那样用数字来索引 而是用词来索引
I index into it not with numbers like with lists, but with words.
所以大帆船 像这样的弦 硬币 引号
So galleons, strings like this, coins, quote unquote,
那里有方括号里的镰刀
sickles in square brackets there.
最后是硬币 方括号 不引用 坚果
And then lastly, coins, square brackets, quote unquote, knuts.
所以它变得--它又是冗长的
So it's getting-- it's verbose again.
这可能不是最好的下坡路
This is not maybe the best road to go down.
但我们稍后会后退一步
But we'll backpedal in a moment.
这就是如何 如果你碰巧把所有的硬币都储存起来了
This is just how, if you happen to have all of your coins stored
在词典中 你可以把帆船、镰刀和坚果
in a dictionary, you could pass the galleons, sickles, and knuts
分别放入您的功能中
into your function respectively.
让我们确保我没有打碎任何东西
Let's make sure I didn't break anything.
让我们重新运行unpack.py的Python 我们仍然很好
Let's rerun Python of unpack.py, and we're still good.
现在 我们怎么会有这样的情况呢？
Now, how could we get to a situation like this?
好的 像往常一样 想象一下这个程序比这里的稍微长一点
Well, as always, imagine this program is a little longer than this one here.
不知何故 你在使用一本词典
And somehow you're using a dictionary maybe
只是为了跟踪某人的钱包或钱包
just to keep track of someone's purse or wallet,
比如他们每种类型的硬币有多少
like how many coins of each type that they have.
因此 使用词典是完全合理的
And as such, it's perfectly reasonable to use a dictionary.
但然后你想要打印出总数
But then you want to print out the total.
然后把它补上
And darn it.
如果Total函数不需要字典 因此您不能这样做
If that total function does not expect a dictionary so you cannot just do
一些好的和简单的东西 比如在硬币中传递
something nice and simple like pass in coins.
出于我们前面看到的原因 这将是一个类型错误
For reasons we saw earlier, that would be a type error.
Total需要三个参数 三个整数
Total expects three arguments, three integers.
你不能就这么传一本词典
You can't just pass in a dictionary.
但如果这就是你用来存储个人钱包的数据结构
But if that's the data structure you're using to store the person's purse
或者钱包 嗯 这是一种不幸
or wallet, well, it's kind of unfortunate
我们在这些数据类型之间存在这种冲突
that we have this clash between these data types.
好吧 这就是我们能做的
Well, here's what we can do.
我们不能把硬币放进去
We can't pass in coins.
因为请注意 如果我尝试这样做并运行unpack.py的Python
Because watch, if I try doing that and run Python of unpack.py,
我们收到另一个类型错误
we're getting another type error.
缺少两个必需的位置参数
Missing two required positional arguments.
镰刀和坚果 我必须通过三件事
Sickles and knuts, I have to pass in three things.
但是 令人惊叹的是 Python还允许您解开词典
But, wonderfully, Python allows you to unpack dictionaries as well.
对于词典来说 你不是使用一个星号 而是两个
For a dictionary, you don't use a single asterisk, you use two.
以及该语法的作用是什么
And what this syntax has the effect of doing
正在传递三个带名称的值
is passing in three values with names.
它的效果是传递等同于100个逗号的帆船
It has the effect of passing in galleons equals 100 comma,
镰刀等于50个逗号 坚果等于25个
sickles equals 50 comma, knuts equals 25.
因此 它具有类似于列表解包的效果
And so, it has the similar effect to the list unpacking.
但这只是传入的值 实际上是用逗号分隔的100、50、25
But that just passed in the values, 100, 50, 25 separated by commas in effect.
在解压缩词典时 它会传入键
When unpacking a dictionary, it passes in the keys
并且在概念上用等号分隔的值
and the values separated conceptually with equal signs
就像我们的函数所期望的那样
just like our function expects.
所以如果我现在再次运行unpack.py的Python 我们仍然是好的
So if I now run Python of unpack.py again, we're still good,
但我们又加强了代码
but we've tightened our code up again.
现在 我给了自己另一个选择
And now, I'm giving myself yet another option.
我可以把巫师的钱包或钱包放在他们的...
I can either store a wizard's purse or wallets in their--
就像我们之前做的那样
in a list as we did earlier.
或者我可以把它存储在一个更多功能的地方--甚至更多
Or I can store it in a little more versatility-- with even more
用字典来代替
specificity using a dictionary instead.
所以 说清楚点 让我倒回去
And so, to be clear, let me rewind.
星星硬币是一样的 如果我倒带
Star star coins is the same thing if I rewind
第一个命名参数的例子
a little bit to our first example of named arguments
和我在这里强调的是一样的
is equivalent to what I've highlighted here.
当你解压缩一个字典时 它会传入所有的键
When you unpack a dictionary, it passes in all of the keys
所有的值都和这里的语法一样
and all of the values much like the syntax here.
但让我把它收紧 回到我们离开的地方
But let me tighten it up and go to where we left off.
现在有什么问题吗？
Questions now on unpacking?
我们能不能在这本字典里
STUDENT: Can we have a-- in this dictionary,
我们能不能用一个常量名值对来代替
can we have instead of having a constant name value pair, can we have
名称值对的数量是可变的？
a variable number of name value pairs?
大卫·J·马兰：简短的回答 是的
DAVID J. MALAN: Short answer, yes.
你可以有三个以上的键值对 就像我在这里一样
You can have more than three key value pairs as I have here.
但是如果总函数是
But it's not going to work unpacking it if the total function is
预计只有三个
expecting only three.
所以如果我在这里添加一些东西 比如让我介绍便士
So if I were to add something here, like let me introduce pennies
魔法世界
to the wizarding world.
假设我有一便士 例如
And suppose I have one penny, for instance.
现在我运行同样的代码 unpack.py的Python 我们又回到了一个类型错误
And now I run this same code, Python of unpack.py, we're back to a type error
再
again.
当我得到一个意想不到的关键字参数便士
Whereby I got an unexpected keyword argument pennies,
因为这不是Total函数所期望的
because that is not expected by the total function.
我们马上就会看到 一个很好的解决方案
We will see in just a moment, wonderfully, a solution though to that.
但现在 它不起作用
But for now, it does not work.
关于用字典或清单拆包的其他问题？
Other questions on unpacking with dictionaries or lists?
在列表值中 我们给出了相同数量的参数
STUDENT: In list-- in list values, we gave the same number of arguments
我们在函数中声明了一个默认值
and we declared a default value in the function.
现在 如果你用这个星号 它会覆盖那个值吗
Now, if you use this asterisk, will it overwrite that value
还是跳过默认值
or will it skip that default value?
大卫·J·马兰：问得好
DAVID J. MALAN: A good question.
例如 如果我们在这里有缺省值
If we did have default values up here, for instance,
等于零 那就是好的一面
equals zero, equals zero, equals zero, the upside of that,
回想一下 从我们之前对函数的论点的讨论中
recall, from our discussion of arguments to functions a while back,
现在你不需要传递所有这些值了
is that now you don't have to pass in all of those values.
它们将默认为这些零
They will default to those zeros.
因此 您可以传递少于三个值
Therefore, you could pass in fewer than three values,
使用在此场景中未打包的列表或词典
either using a list or a dictionary that's unpacked in this scenario.
我故意不这么做是因为我想让我们
I deliberately did not do that because I wanted us to encounter
在这种情况下 这个特定的错误
this specific error in this case.
但你绝对可以回到过去 添加这些默认设置
But you could absolutely go back and add those defaults.
所以事实证明 这个单星号或这个双星号
So it turns out that this single asterisks or this double asterisk
不仅用于拆包的上下文中
is not only used in the context of unpacking.
在Python中 该语法实际上用作可视指示器
That same syntax is actually used as a visual indicator in Python
当在函数中时 它本身很可能
when in a function itself might very well
接受数量可变的参数
take a variable number of arguments.
也就是说 一个函数可以是可变的
That is to say, a function can be variadic.
这意味着它不一定需要 比如说
Which means that it doesn't necessarily have to take, say,
具体有三个论点
three arguments specifically.
即使它们有或没有缺省值
Even if they do or don't have default values,
它可能需要零个 或者一个 或者两个 或者三个
it can take maybe zero, or one, or two, or three.
事实证明 实现相同想法的语法是
And it turns out the syntax for implementing the same idea is
在精神上非常相似
quite similar in spirit.
事实上 让我回到VS代码这里
In fact, let me go back to VS Code here.
让我建议我们从这个代码开始
And let me propose that we start over with this code
摆脱我们对帆船、镰刀和坚果的概念
and get rid of our notion of galleons, and sickles, and knuts,
做一些更普通的事情 这样我们就可以
and do something just a little more generic just so that we've
我看到了这个的语法
seen the syntax for this.
假设我按如下方式定义一个函数
Suppose that I define a function as follows.
定义一个函数 我们称它为f
Define a function, let's call it f.
该函数不会接受特定数量的参数
And that function is not going to take a specific number of arguments
但它是一种可变的
but a variable one.
因此 我将继续在这里使用这个语法
And so, I'm going to go ahead and use this syntax here,
星形参数 这表明该函数确实是可变的
star args, which indicates that this function is indeed variadic.
它需要一些可变数量的位置参数
It takes some variable number of positional arguments.
位置 在这个意义上 它们通常从左到右
Positional in the sense that they go typically from left to right.
但我还不知道我想支持多少人
But I don't know how many just yet I want to support.
假设我还想支持
Suppose that I additionally want to support
一些关键字参数 即
some number of keyword arguments, that is,
可以选择调用的命名参数
named parameters that can be called optionally
每个人都用自己的名字
and individually by their own name.
嗯 从语法上讲 这里的惯例是
Well, the convention syntactically here would
就是用两颗星 然后用矮子
be to use two stars and then kwargs.
我可以叫args 或者kwargs 任何我想要的东西
I could call args, or kwargs, anything else that I want.
但是您会在Python自己的文档中经常看到这样一个约定
But a convention you'll frequently see in Python's own documentation
当你有像这样的占位符作为一些参数时
is that when you have placeholders like this for some number of arguments
和一些关键字参数 世界上倾向于使用args和kwargs
and some number of keyword arguments, the world tends to use args and kwargs.
好的 在这个函数内部 让我们暂时做一些非常简单的事情
Well, inside of this function, let's do something super simple just for now.
让我继续打印出字面上引用的位置
Let me go ahead and print out literally quote unquote positional,
只是为了告诉自己 同时我的脑海里围绕着
just to indicate to myself while wrapping my mind around what's
接下来是什么位置论点
going on here what the positional arguments are.
让我非常简单地打印出这些参数
And let me quite simply print out those args.
这不是您通常会做的事情
This is not something you would typically do.
你通常不会简单地接受这些论点
You don't typically just take in these arguments
然后打印出来 不管有多少
and print them, no matter how many there are.
我现在只是诊断性地做这件事 以向您展示语法是如何工作的
I'm just doing this diagnostically for now to show you how the syntax works.
现在 让我在我的文件的底部继续--
Now, let me go ahead at the bottom of my file--
这一次我不会费心使用主函数 这样我们就可以只专注于
and I won't bother with a main function this time so we can focus only
关于这个函数f
on this function f.
让我继续用三个参数来调用f
Let me go ahead and just call f with three arguments.
我将使用与前面相同的论点
I'll use the same arguments as before.
但我还没有费心给它们起名字 比如大帆船
But I didn't bother giving them names just yet, like galleons,
还有镰刀和坚果之类的东西
and sickles, and knuts, and the like.
那我有什么呢？
So what do I have?
无论什么调用此函数f的程序
A program that no matter what calls this function f,
但它首先在文件的顶部定义了f
but it first defines f at the top of the file.
它需要一些位置论据
It's taking some number of positional arguments,
一些命名参数
some number of named arguments.
目前 我只是打印出位置信息
And for the moment, I'm just printing out the positional ones.
让我继续在我的终端窗口中
Let me go ahead and in my terminal window
运行unpack.py的Python并按Enter键
run Python of unpack.py and hit Enter.
您将看到传入的位置参数
And you'll see that the positional arguments passed in
显然这是--
are apparently this--
一个序列 100 50 25
a sequence, 100, 50, 25.
但请注意这一点
But notice this.
如果我在那里清除我的终端窗口并传入其他内容
If I clear my terminal window there and pass in something else,
就像五个 第四个论点
like five, a fourth argument.
以前 如果我尝试更改参数的数量
Previously, if I tried to change the number of arguments
我正在传递我的总函数 它只被定义为取三个
I'm passing in to my total function, which was only defined as taking three,
我会得到一个打字错误 一些视觉提示
I would have gotten a type error, some visual indication
不 您不能传递更多或更少的参数
that, no, you can't pass in more or fewer arguments
而不是实际在函数定义中
than is actually in the function's definition.
但现在看吧
But now watch.
如果我运行unpack.py的Python 这一次
If I run Python of unpack.py, this time passing
在100 50 25和5中 第四个论点 所有四个
in 100, 50, 25, and 5, a fourth argument, all four of those
一切都很顺利
went through just fine.
我可以删除所有这些 例如 现在 重新运行我的程序
I can get rid of all of those but one, for instance now, rerun my program
在清除我的屏幕之后
after clearing my screen.
现在 我在这里只看到一个论点
And now, I'll see just one argument here.
即使后面有逗号 后面什么也没有
And even though there's a comma and nothing after it,
实际上 这是查看元组时的语法 因此
this is actually the syntax when seeing a tuple, in effect, whereby
逗号只是表示这确实是一个列表
the comma just indicates this is indeed a list,
但这里面只有一种元素
but there's only one element therein.
好吧 让我们也变得更好奇一点
Well, let's get a little more curious too.
让我继续倒带到我们
Let me go ahead and rewind here to where we
一开始只有这三个价值观
started with just those three values.
这一次 让我继续打印出我的命名论点 可以说
And this time, let me go ahead and print out my named argument, so to speak,
这不是args而是kwargs
which isn't args but kwargs.
同样 此语法中的位置参数排在第一位
Again, the positional args in this syntax come first.
被命名的论点 粗鲁人排在第二位
The named arguments, kwargs come second.
这是Python开出的药方
That's what Python prescribes.
所以现在 让我继续下去 不要只传递这些数字
So now, let me go ahead and not pass in just these numbers.
让我继续下去 传递实际命名的参数
Let me go ahead and pass in actually named arguments.
现在让我来做一些更具体的事情 比如帆船等于100
So let me do something now more specifically, like galleons equals 100,
镰刀等于50 坚果等于25
and sickles equals 50, and knuts equals 25.
我不会费心和道达尔做任何数学运算
I'm not going to bother doing any math with total.
我现在只想探讨一下这种功能
I just want to poke around right now at this functionality of having
可变数量的参数
a variable number of arguments.
现在的巧妙之处在于 如果我运行unpack.py的Python并按Enter 就没有问题了
And what's neat now is if I run Python of unpack.py and hit Enter, no problem.
kwargs是一个自动的字典
What kwargs is, is automatically a dictionary that
包含了所有传递给函数的命名参数
contains all of the named arguments that were passed to my function.
也就是说 在设计自己的函数时
Which is to say, when designing your own functions,
如果你想支持多个参数
if you want to support more than one argument,
也许多于两个 三个 四个 也许是可变数量的参数
maybe more than two, or three, or four, maybe a variable number of arguments,
实际上 您可以支持数量可变的位置参数
indeed, you can support both a variable number of positional arguments
值逗号值逗号值 或任何数量的命名
that are just value comma value comma value, or any number of named
arguments 实际上是将参数的名称
arguments, where you actually put the name of the parameter
等于值 然后可能是一个逗号和更多相同的东西
equals the value and then maybe a comma and some more of the same.
现在 我们已经在一些函数中看到过了
So now, it turns out we have seen this before in some of the functions
我们曾经约会过
we've used to date.
我们不一定会把它叫做args或者kwargs
We didn't necessarily see it called args or necessarily see it called kwargs.
但我们至少在野外看到了一个这样的例子
But we have seen at least one example of this in the wild.
回想一下我们的老朋友print 我们已经用了好几个星期了
Recall our old friend print, which we've been using now for weeks.
当我们第一次查看打印方式的文档时
And when we first looked at the documentation for print way
当时它看起来有点像这样
back when, it looked a little something like this.
要打印的第一个参数是对象
The first argument to print was objects.
我当时在星号处挥了挥手
And I waved my hand at the time at the asterisk that
在变量名的开头
was at the start of that variable name.
但是我们有separator 它的默认值是一个空格
But then we had sep for separator, the default value of which was a space.
我们有n 默认值是一个新行
We had n, the default value of which was a new line.
还有一些其他的名字的争论 我们挥手表示反对
And then some other names arguments that we waved our hands at then
现在我也会这么做
and I'll again do now.
但是你现在可以从我们的重点中推断出
But what you can now perhaps infer from our emphasis
在今天的这些十字架上 单星或双星
on these asterisks today, the single stars or the double stars,
你知道吗
is that you know what?
这是Python文档中的约定
This is the convention in Python's documentation
以指示print采用可变数量的参数
to indicate that print takes a variable number of arguments.
所以如果我们看看打印的实际实现
So if we were to look at the actual implementation of the print
Python自己的作者实现的函数
function implemented by Python's own authors,
它很可能看起来像这样
it might very well look something like this.
Def print 然后第一个我们的论点
Def print, and then the first our argument
将是星形对象 从而表明打印
would be star objects, thereby indicating that print
接受数量可变的参数
takes a variable number of arguments.
下一个可能是Sep等于QUOTE
The next one of which might be sep equals quote unquote
也可以使用双引号 也可以使用文档中的单引号
either using double quotes or as in the documentation single quotes too.
下一个可以是n 其缺省值是新行
The next one of which might be n, the default value of which is a new line.
然后还有一些其他的命名参数
And then some of those other named arguments
我们也没有看过
that we've not looked at as well.
然后 可能在打印函数内部
And then, maybe inside of the print function
可能是由Python的作者实现的
implemented by the authors of Python, maybe
在对象中有一个类似于for对象的for循环
there's a for loop like for object in objects
这允许他们迭代这些可变数量的对象中的每一个
that allows them to iterate over each of those variable number of objects
并逐一打印出来
and print each of them.
这就是为什么在过去的节目中 你和我
And this is why in programs past, you and I
我能做的只是打印左括号和右括号
have been able to do just print open parentheses close parenthesis
里面什么都没有
with nothing inside.
或者你和我已经能够打印出一些东西
Or you and I have been able to print out something
例如 Hello world 在这些括号中只有一个字符串
like, Hello, world, a single string inside of those parentheses.
或者你和我能够做一段单独的弦乐 你好
Or you and I have been able to do a single string, Hello,
然后是另一个不带引号的世界
and then another string quote unquote world,
从而传递两个或更多的参数
thereby passing in two arguments or even more.
所以我们很久以来就有能力使用各种函数
So we've long had this ability to use variadic functions,
因此 您可以传入数量可变的参数
whereby you can pass in a variable number of arguments.
您现在通过这个args和kwargs语法得到的是--
What you now have via this args and kwargs syntax--
但再说一次 它们不需要被称为--就是
but again, they do not need to be called that-- is
使用一颗或两颗星来实现这些类型功能能力
the ability using that star or two stars to implement those kinds of functions
你自己
yourself.
刚才我自己的f函数并没有做任何有趣的事情
My own f function a moment ago did not do anything all that interesting.
但它暗示了你如何 如果在未来
But it hints at how you could, if in the future
您有一个用于接受零个或一个或多个这两种类型的参数的用例
you have a use case, for taking zero or one or more of either type of argument.
现在对这些类型的争论有什么问题吗？
Any questions now on these types of arguments?
学生：如果你打印kwargs 而论点就像一个列表 会发生什么？
STUDENT: What will happen if you print kwargs and the argument is like a list?
大卫·J·马兰：啊
DAVID J. MALAN: Ah.
那么 如果像打印列表一样打印参数 会发生什么呢？
So what would happen if you print the argument like it's a list?
所以我认为我们看到了这一点
So I think we saw that.
如果我把我的历史倒回到我有f函数的时候
If I roll back in my history here to when I had that f function.
我把它命名为f只是为了非常普通
Which I called f just to be very generic just so
我们可以玩弄一下语法
we could play around with the syntax.
这就是我在这里所拥有的
This is what I had here.
所以这是一个--
So this is a--
我传入了100个逗号50个逗号25
I passed in 100 comma 50 comma 25.
它会自动存储在args中
That gets automatically stored in args.
当我运行它时 你实际上可以看到值的序列
And when I run it, you can actually see that sequence of values
通过运行unpack.py的Python
by running Python of unpack.py.
有一个序列都是以单一变量的形式出现的
There is that sequence all in the form of one single variable.
我把它打印出来只是为了诊断
I'm printing it just for diagnostic purposes.
这并不是一个真正有用或漂亮的程序
This is not really a useful or pretty program.
但它暗示了我们如何才能访问整个价值序列
But it hints at how we can access that whole sequence of values.
这里还有关于这种方法的其他问题吗？
Other questions on this approach here?
学生：我们能把Kwargs从一个函数传递到另一个函数吗？
STUDENT: Can we pass the kwargs from one function to another function?
大卫·J·马兰：当然
DAVID J. MALAN: Absolutely.
您可以将其中任何一个传递给另一个函数 该函数
You can pass either of those to another function, which
如果您想包装另一个函数 您可能需要这样做
you might want to do if you want to wrap another function,
提供一些附加功能 但仍
provide some additional functionality, but still
也将所有受支持的参数传递给基础函数
pass in all of the supported arguments to the underlying function as well.
好的
All right.
接下来这个怎么样
How about this next.
事实证明 我们可以将其他一些工具添加到您的工具包中
It turns out that a few other tools we can add to your tool kit
与Python支持的编程模型的类型相关
relate to the types of programming models that Python supports.
我们很久以前就开始专注于
We started out quite some time ago focusing really
关于在Python语言中的过程性编程
on procedural programming in Python.
由此我们从上到下、从左到右编写代码 定义一些函数
Whereby we wrote code top to bottom, left to right, defining some functions,
或者 如果你愿意 一路上的程序
or if you will, procedures along the way,
定义变量 并产生副作用
defining variables, and having side effects,
并根据需要赋值
and assigning values as needed.
但后来我们最终引入或真正揭示了
But we then eventually introduced or really revealed
该Python也是非常面向对象的
that Python is also very much object-oriented.
很多这样的变量 很多这样的类型
And a lot of those variables, a lot of those types
我们使用的所有时间实际上都是物体
that we were using all that time were in fact objects,
来自特定类的对象
objects that came from certain classes.
这些类是各种各样的模板 蓝图
And those classes were templates of sorts, blueprints,
通过它 您可以在其中封装数据和功能
via which you could encapsulate both data and functionality therein.
那么我们一路上也看到了一些提示
Well, we also saw along the way some hints
第三种编程范例 也就是Python
of a third paradigm of programming that Python also,
在某种程度上支持 这被称为函数式编程
to some extent, supports, which is known as functional programming.
其中的功能比以往任何时候都更加强大
Whereby functions are ever more powerful in that
它们往往不会有副作用 不会在全球范围内打印或改变状态
they tend not to have side effects, no printing or changing of state globally.
相反 它们是完全独立的
But rather, they're completely self-contained
并可以作为输入和返回值
and might take as inputs and return values.
这通常是我们开始整理东西时看到的一个范例
And that's generally a paradigm we saw when we started sorting things,
特别是使用像我们的排序函数这样的函数
particularly with functions like our sort function
或Lambda函数时传入该函数
or Lambda function when we passed in the function
早在很久以前 我们就想用来排序列表
we wanted to use to sort a list way back when.
好吧 事实证明 Python还具有其他功能
Well, it turns out Python has other functionality that
让人联想到函数式编程 而且确实是一种强大的方式
is reminiscent of functional programming and indeed is a powerful way
以更不同的方式解决问题
to solve problems a little more differently still.
让我提出这一点
Let me propose this.
让我提议我在VS代码中创建一个新程序
Let me propose that I whip up a new program here in VS Code
关闭我们的unpack.py 这一次创建另一个名为yell的程序
by closing our unpack.py and this time creating another program called yell.
假设手头的目标是实现某种程序 从而允许用户
Suppose the goal at hand is to implement some program that allows the user
来传递一个输入 然后它喊出响应
to pass an input, and then it yells the response
通过强制所有内容都大写
by forcing everything to uppercase.
我向那些戴着耳机的人道歉
My apologies to those with headphones there.
我会调整的
I'll modulate.
因此 让我继续运行yell.py的代码
So let me go ahead and run code of yell.py.
在yell.py中 让我们继续并实现
And within yell.py, let's go ahead and implement
一个真正做到这一点的程序
a program that really does just that.
让我们继续在这里定义一个主函数
Let's go ahead and define a main function up here.
让我们暂时假设这个Yell函数已经存在
And let's assume for the moment that this yell function already exists
然后喊出这样的话：这是CS50 大写正确 不是全部大写
and yell something like, This is CS50, properly capitalized, not in all caps.
现在 让我们继续使用def yell实现这个yell函数
Now, let's go ahead and implement this yell function with def yell.
目前 它将只需要一个单词或短语
It's going to take, for now, a single word or phrase.
让我们继续前进
And let's go ahead.
我把它叫做短语
And I'll call it phrase here.
接下来 我会打印出短语
And I'm going to go ahead and just print out the phrase.upper.
这就是说 UPPER将会把HOLE这个东西变成大写
So phrase.upper is going to force the hole thing to uppercase.
像往常一样 如果这个文件的名称等于
And as usual, down here if the name of this file equals
等于引号不加引号的main 那么让我们像往常一样继续 并调用main
equals quote unquote main, then let's go ahead, as always, and call main.
所以让我们来运行这个
So let's just run this.
但在很大程度上 这应该是相当简单的
But for the most part, it should be fairly straightforward.
当我运行yell.py的Python时 屏幕上显示的是CS50
When I run Python of yell.py, THIS IS CS50 is yelled on the screen.
好的 那很好
All right, that's nice.
但是 Yell只期待一个短语 这并不是很好
But it's not great that yell only expects a single phrase.
如果我可以 就像印刷品一样 不是很好吗
Wouldn't it be nice, like print, if I could
一般情况下 传入一个短语、两个、三个或多个单词
pass in one phrase, or two, or three, or really multiple words more generally
而是作为单独的词语本身
but as individual words themselves.
所以让我稍微调整一下 把大喊大叫改为不是一个短语
So let me retool this a little bit and change yell to take in not a phrase
但是 像单词列表这样的东西怎么样？
but how about something like a list of words.
所以最终 我可以像这样喊喊叫
So that ultimately, I can call yell like this.
引用不引用 这个在列表中 引用不引用 这个在列表中
Quote unquote, this inside of a list, quote unquote, "This" inside of a list,
并且 在列表中引用不引号的“CS50”
and, quote unquote, "CS50" inside of a list.
现在我不打算费心讨论类型提示或注释
I'm not going to bother with type hints or annotations for now.
但我只是假设Yell现在已经被定义为接受一系列单词
But I'll just assume that yell has been defined now as taking a list of words
就像这里定义的那样
as defined here.
但现在我想强迫他们全部使用小写字母
But now I want to force them all to lowercase.
所以我不太想做这么简单的事情
So I don't quite want to do something as simple as this.
就像单词中的单词一样 例如 我可以打印给定的单词
Like for word in words, I could, for instance, print that given word
也许现在就以一无所有结束这条线
and maybe end the line with nothing right now.
但我认为如果我这样做 yell.py的巨蟒 不 这是不对的
But I think if I do this, Python of yell.py, no, that's not right.
我没有强迫任何东西大写
I haven't forced anything to uppercase.
所以让我们来解决这个问题
So let's fix this.
那么 让我们继续执行以下操作
Well, let's go ahead and do the following.
让我继续并按如下方式累积大写单词
Let me go ahead and accumulate the uppercase words as follows.
让我创建一个名为UPERCASE的变量
Let me create a variable called uppercase
并使用方括号或我们的更多
and initialize it to an empty list using square brackets or our more
详细列表语法
verbose list syntax.
现在 让我继续重复这些单词中的每一个
And now, let me go ahead and iterate over each of those words in words.
对于它们中的每一个 让我们进入上面的大小写列表 附加到它
And for each of them, let's go into our upper cased list, append to it
当前单词的大写版本
the current words uppercase version.
这是一种创建名为大写的新列表的方法
So this is a way of creating a new list called uppercase
这只是附加、附加、附加到该列表
that is just appending, appending, appending to that list
循环中的每个当前单词 但改为提升评级
each of the current words in the loop but uppercased instead.
现在 让我继续打印出评价较高的榜单
And now, just let me go ahead and print out the uppercased list.
这不太对
This isn't quite right.
让我们看看这里会发生什么
Let's see what happens here.
Yell.py的蟒蛇 好的
Python of yell.py, OK.
这不太对 因为我觉得我不想
It's not quite right, because I don't think I want
那些引号或那些方括号
those quotes or those square brackets.
我看到的是什么？
What am I seeing?
我实际上是在打印一份清单
I'm actually printing a list.
但是 现在我们的一些解包语法可以派上用场
But, but, but, here's where some of our unpacking syntax now can be useful.
我不需要改变我解决这个问题的方法
I don't have to change my approach to this problem.
我只需添加一个星号就可以解开大写字母
I can just unpack uppercase by adding a single star.
现在 让我继续并重新运行yell.py的Python
And now, let me go ahead and rerun Python of yell.py.
现在 它实际上只是一种英语
And now, it's actually just English.
没有像引号那样残留的Python语法
There's no remnants of Python syntax like the quotes,
还有逗号和方括号
and the commas, and the square brackets.
我现在解开了 这是CS50 作为三个单独的参数打印出来
I've now unpacked, this is CS50 as three separate arguments to print.
因此 现在这种拆包技术似乎已经很有用了
So already now, this unpacking technique would seem to be useful.
嗯 有点不幸的是 我现在
Well, it's a little unfortunate that I now
不过 我需要以这种方式调用带有值列表的Yell
need to call yell though with a list of values in this way.
这根本不是常态
This is just not the norm.
或者至少 它的用户界面不太友好
Or it's at least, it's not nearly as user-friendly
类似于打印函数 其中
as something like the print function where
我可以传入零个、一个、两个、三个或任意数量的参数
I can pass in zero, or one, or two, or three, or any number of arguments.
为什么你要让我为你的喊叫功能只传递一个列表？
Why are you making me for your yell function pass in only a list?
嗯 我们可以做得更好
Well, we can do better.
让我们采用我们学到的一些新惯例
Let's adopt some of the new conventions we've learned.
让我们继续 通过去掉方括号来删除列表
And let's go ahead and get rid of the list by removing the square brackets.
让我们来传递三个论点
And let's just pass yell three arguments.
现在 我不想做一些事情 比如改变单词的定义
Now, I don't want to do something like change the definition of words
第一个单词 第二个单词
to take in word one, word two.
这不会扩大规模 也不会
That's not going to scale and it's not going
处理不同数量的单词
to handle different number of words.
但我们现在有一种技术
But we have a technique now.
我们可以使用STAR ARGS 这将允许YELL功能
We can say star args, which will allow the yell function
可以接受任意数量的参数
to accept any number of arguments.
为了具体起见 我们不要泛泛地称它为ARGS
And just for specificity, let's not call it generically args.
让我们给它起个更不言自明的名字吧 就像明星词一样
Let's name it something a little more self explanatory like star words.
这只是意味着我传入的单词数量是可变的
This just means I have a variable number of words being passed in.
现在 我想 我已经取得了些许进步
Now, I think, I've made a marginal improvement.
让我再运行一次 yell.py的Python
Let me run this again, Python of yell.py.
这是全部大写的CS50
This is CS50 is in all caps.
但这只是好一点而已
But it's just a little better.
因为现在我可以像对待印刷品一样对待大喊大叫
Because now I can treat yell just like I've long treated print,
你想传多少东西就传多少 印刷品会处理的
pass in as many things as you want, and print will deal with it.
现在 我的大喊大叫功能看起来就像它看起来一样强大
Now, my yell function is just as powerful it would seem.
更好的是 它还迫使所有内容都大写
And better still, it also forces everything to uppercase.
事实证明 Python附带了一个名为
Well, it turns out Python comes with this function called
地图 它的生活目的是让你地图 也就是应用
map, whose purpose in life is to allow you to map, that is, apply
某些函数作用于某个序列中的每个元素 如列表
some function to every element of some sequence like a list.
例如 如果我们想强制每个单词都大写
So for instance, if we want to force to uppercase each of the words,
这是传入的单词列表中的CS50
this is CS50 in the list of words that's been passed in, well,
我们实际上希望将大写函数映射到这些值中的每一个
we essentially want to map the upper case function to each of those values.
那么 在Python中使用map可以做到这一点吗？
So using map in Python can I do just that?
让我回到这里来VS Code
Let me go back here to VS Code.
现在让我提议我重新实现这一点 如下所示
And let me propose now that I re-implement this as follows.
我去掉了这三行代码 去掉了那个循环
I get rid of all three of these lines here, getting rid of that loop
尤其是
in particular.
让我仍然声明一个名为upperase的变量
Let me still declare a variable called uppercased.
但让我将其设置为等于这个名为map的新函数的返回值
But let me set it equal to the return value of this new function called map.
MAP在这里有两个参数
Map takes two arguments here.
在本例中 是我想要
In this case, the name of a function that I want to
映射到一系列值
map on to a sequence of values.
那么 我想对传入的每个单词应用什么函数呢？
Well, what function do I want to apply to every word that's been passed in?
嗯 事实证明 多亏了我的知识
Well, it turns out, thanks to my knowledge
现在谈到面向对象编程 我知道在str类中
now of object-oriented programming, I know that in the str class
有一个名为UPPER的函数
there is a function called upper.
我们通常使用字符串的名称来调用它
We've usually called it by using the name of a string
可变的 上开的帕伦关闭帕伦
variable.upper open paren close paren.
但是如果您阅读了str类的文档
But if you read the documentation for the str class,
您将看到该函数实际上被描述为str.upper
you'll see that the function is described indeed as str.upper.
我没有在str.upper的末尾使用圆括号 也就是打开和关闭
I'm not using parentheses, open and close, at the end of str.upper.
因为我现在不想宣布
Because I don't want to call it now.
我想把这个函数传递给map函数
I want to pass this function to the map function,
因此映射可以以某种方式添加这些括号 可以这么说 并将其命名为
so that map can somehow add those parentheses, so to speak, and call it
这些单词中的每一个
on every one of these words.
这就是MAP非常强大的功能
And this is what map does quite powerfully,
并且确实是函数式编程的一个实例
and is an instance, indeed, of functional programming.
因此 我将另一个函数传递给这个map函数
Whereby I'm passing to this map function another function.
不是说了算
Not calling it.
我只是通过某种形式的参考来传递它
I'm just passing it in by a reference of sorts.
而MAP要为我做的就是重复这些单词
And what map is going to do for me is iterate over each of those words,
对这些单词中的每一个调用str.Upper 然后返回
call str.upper on each of those words, and return
对我来说 一个全新的列表将所有这些结果都包含在一个列表中
to me a brand new list containing all of those results together in one list.
它完全不需要我更加手动地使用
It completely obviates the need for me to do this more manually using
那份名单
that list.
我仍然会使用星号大写来打印整个内容
I'm still going to print the whole thing using star uppercase.
所以如果我拿回一个包含三个大写单词的列表
So that if I get back a list of three uppercase words,
我要把它们拆开 全部打印出来
I'm going to unpack them and print them all out.
所以让我们再来一次
So let's run this again.
Yell.py的Python回车
Python of yell.py Enter.
瞧 它还在工作
And voila, it's still working.
但现在的密码更紧了--
But the code now is even more tight--
比以前更紧了
even tighter than before.
所以事实证明我们还有另一种方法
So it turns out there's another way we can
以一种更好的方式解决这个问题
solve this problem in a way that's even more
毕德式的 或者至少是相当普遍的
Pythonic, or at least quite common.
这是使用一种被称为列表理解的功能
And that's using a feature known as a list comprehension.
如果你愿意的话 这是一个很重要的短语
And it's a big phrase, if you will.
但它指的是使用Python为您提供的功能
But it refers to the ability in Python for you
为了非常容易地在不使用循环的情况下构建列表
to very easily construct a list on the fly without using a loop,
而不调用Append和Append 而是执行所有操作
without calling append and append, but to do everything
总之 大胆地说 优雅的俏皮话
in one, daresay, elegant one-liner.
那么 我该如何使用这个列表理解的概念呢？
So how can I go about using this notion of a list comprehension?
好吧 让我继续做这件事
Well, let me go ahead and do this.
在yell.py中 在VS代码中 让我继续
In yell.py, in VS Code here, let me go ahead
并按如下方式改变我的方法
and change my approach as follows.
与其使用地图 这是非常好和正确的这种方式
Instead of using map, which is perfectly fine and correct in this way,
让我来给你们展示一下另一种方式
let me just show you this other way as well.
列表理解是创建这样一个列表的机会
A list comprehension is the opportunity to create a list like this,
使用这样的方括号
using square brackets like this.
但是在这些方括号中编写一个Python表达式
But inside of those square brackets to write a Python expression,
这实际上将为您动态生成一个全新的列表
that in effect is going to dynamically generate a brand new list for you
使用你写的一些逻辑
using some logic you've written.
我在这里可能采取的方法是这样的
And the approach I might take here is this.
如果我想在这个列表中存储每个单词的大写版本
If I want to store in this list the uppercase version of every word
在单词列表中 我可以这样做--
in that words list, I can do this--
一字不差 一字不差
word.upper for word in words.
现在 这是一个很大的问题
Now, this is a mouthful.
但我敢说 Python程序员喜欢这种功能
But I dare say Python programmers love this capability
能够在运行中定义其中的列表
of being able to define on the fly a list inside of which
是任何数量的值 你通常会这样做 至少我们已经做到了
is any number of values that you would ordinarily, at least as we've done it,
使用循环构造 然后再次调用Append、Append和Append
construct with a loop and again calling append, and append, and append.
但这通常需要两行、三行、四行或更多行
But that usually takes two, three, four or more lines.
我在这里强调的这个清单理解
This list comprehension that I've highlighted here
现在是创造完全相同的东西的另一种方式--
is now an alternative way to create the exact same thing--
一张清单里面有一大堆被看好的词
a list inside of which are a whole bunch of uppercased words.
哪几个词？
Which words?
对于传递给Yell的单词列表中的每个单词
For each word in the words list that was passed into yell
就会出现在这张清单上
is what ends up in this list.
这里有关于这个语法的问题吗？
Questions on this syntax here?
这肯定需要一点时间来适应
It definitely takes a little bit of getting used to.
因为左边有这个值 所以这个函数在这里调用
Because you've got this value on the left, this function call here.
你在方括号里有这个循环
You've got this loop inside of the square brackets.
但是 如果您习惯于以这种方式从左侧阅读代码
But if you become accustomed to reading the code in this way from left
向右 这意味着给我大写版本
to right, this means give me the uppercase version
在我的单词列表中 每个单词对应的单词
of the word for each word in my words list.
关于列表理解的问题在这里？
Questions here on list comprehensions?
学生：嗨
STUDENT: Hi.
你能像If Else一样做条件句 或者组合If、Elif、Else吗？
Can you do conditionals also, like if else, or combine if, elif, else?
大卫·J·马兰：的确 你可以
DAVID J. MALAN: Indeed, you can.
让我回到那个问题上来 在那里我们将看到一个机会
And let me come back to that, where we'll see an opportunity
有条件地做某事
to do things conditionally.
但现在 我只是将列表中的每个单词都放在上面
But for now, I'm just uppercasing every word in the list.
问得好
Good question.
还有其他问题吗？
Other questions?
学生：是的
STUDENT: Yeah.
这是函数式编程吗？
Is this functional programming?
或者我的意思是 这个特殊的东西 我们用单词 单词中的一个单词？
Or I mean, this particular thing, we are using words.upper for a word in words?
大卫·J·马兰：不一定
DAVID J. MALAN: Not necessarily.
我想说 这更多的是一种Python的特性
This is more of a feature of Python, I would say.
学生：好的
STUDENT: OK.
大卫·J·马兰：是的
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah.
MAP是我们使用Lambda的一个非常具体的化身
Map was one very specific incarnation of thereof our use of Lambda
并将其作为键属性传递给排序函数
and passing it in as a key attribute to the sort function,
不久前的排序函数就是一个例子
sorted function a while back was an example.
我们马上就要见面了
And we're about to see one other.
所以我们甚至可以使用这些列表理解
So we can even use these list comprehension
筛选结果列表中的值或从中筛选出的值
to filter values in or out of our resulting list.
事实上 在VS代码中 让我关闭yell.py并关闭我的终端
So in fact, in VS Code here, let me close yell.py and close my terminal
窗户
window.
让我在这里创建一个新的项目 它的人生目标是
And let me create a new program here whose purpose in life
也许是用一张和以前一样的学生名单和一个更短的版本
maybe is to take a same list of students as before with a shorter version
只需过滤掉格兰芬多的所有学生
thereof, and just filter out all of the students in Gryffindor.
因此 让我继续创建一个名为Gryffindors.py的文件
So let me go ahead and create a file called Gryffindors.py.
我要继续复制我的学生名单之前的粘贴
I'm going to go ahead and copy paste from before really my list of students,
至少从一开始就是赫敏、哈利、罗恩和德拉科
at least Hermione, Harry, Ron, and Draco from the start
在这里 只是为了让我能专注于一个学生
here, just so that I can focus on one student who
碰巧不是斯莱特林的
happens not to be from Slytherin.
我现在要做的是 如果我想
And what I'm going to do here now, if I want
为了只过滤掉格兰芬多的学生 让我继续这样做
to filter out only the Gryffindor students, let me go ahead and do this.
让我创建另一个名为Gryffindors的变量 它
Let me create another variable called Gryffindors, which
将等同于下面的列表
is going to equal the following list.
而这将是一条更长的队伍
And this is going to be a bit of a longer line.
所以我要主动移动我的方括号
So I'm going to proactively move my square brackets
放在两条不同的线上
onto two separate lines.
现在 我将创建一个列表理解
And I'm going to create now a list comprehension.
我想做这个
I want to do this.
我希望这份名为格兰芬多的新名单包含每个学生的名字
I want this new list called Gryffindors to contain every student's name
对于学生名单中的每个学生
for each student in the student's list.
但是 如果学生的房子等于引号格兰芬多
But, but, but, if the student's house equals equals quote unquote Gryffindor.
所以这在精神上和我之前做的几乎是一样的
So this is nearly identical in spirit to what I just did earlier
根据传递的每个单词创建一个理解列表
to create a list comprehension out of each of the words passed
我的喊叫功能
to my yell function.
但在这里 我这样做是有条件的
But here, I'm doing so conditionally.
因此 我从我们对循环的关注中汲取灵感
And so, I'm borrowing inspiration from our focus on loops,
从我们对条件句的关注中得到一些启发
borrowing some inspiration from our focus on conditionals,
将其合并到相同的方括号符号中
combining that into this same square bracket notation.
因此 格兰芬多最终是零个或多个学生的名字
So that what Gryffindors ultimately is, is zero or more students' names.
其中包含的名字就是结果
And the names that are included are the result
迭代这些学生中的每一个 并且只包括在最终结果中
of iterating over each of those students and only including in the final result
房子碰巧是格兰芬多的学生
the students whose house happens to be Gryffindor.
因此 当我继续使用Gryffindors.py的Python运行这段代码时
So when I go ahead and run this with Python of Gryffindors.py
然后按回车键 你就会看到 嗯 这里实际上什么都没有发生
and hit Enter, you'll see, huh, nothing actually happened here.
嗯 那是因为我没有完成节目
Well, that's because I didn't finish the program.
让我继续 用这个来结束这个程序
Let me go ahead and actually finish the program with this.
格兰芬多复数中的每一个格兰芬多--
How about for each Gryffindor in Gryffindors plural--
更好的是 所以我提前做了所有这些工作是明智的
and better yet, so that it's sensible that I did all of this work in advance,
让我继续对所有这些名字进行分类
let me go ahead and sort all of those names
使用我们熟悉的排序函数
with our familiar sorted function.
现在让我们继续打印这些格兰芬多的每一个
Let's go ahead now and print out each of these Gryffindors.
所以现在 注意 如果熟悉书和电影
So now, notice, if familiar with the books and the movies,
你会知道这四个学生中只有三个
you'll know that only three of these four students
实际上是在格兰芬多
are actually in Gryffindor.
如果我运行Gryffindor.py的巨蟒 我们会看到哈利、赫敏和罗恩
And if I run Python of Gryffindor.py, there we see Harry, Hermione, and Ron,
但现在也是按顺序排列的
but now in sorted order as well.
所以这只是我们解决同样问题的一种方法 而不仅仅是使用列表
So that's just one way we can solve this same problem using not just a list
理解 而是一种列表理解 其中包含这个条件
comprehension but a list comprehension that has this conditional therein.
但也有其他方法来解决这个同样的问题
But there's yet other ways to solve this same problem too.
然后我们回到Python的一些功能特性上来
And we come back to some functional features of Python.
除了地图等功能外 还有
In addition to functions like map, there's
还有这个叫做滤镜 可以用来达到同样的效果
also this one called filter that can be used to achieve the same effect,
但如果你愿意的话 用一种更实用的方法
but with a more functional approach, if you will.
让我回到这里的VS代码
Let me go back to VS Code here.
在相同的例子中 让我这样做
And with the same example, let me do this.
让我像以前一样留下上面的原始名单 包括德拉科
Let me leave the original list of above as before, including Draco,
他其实不是格兰芬多人
who's not in fact from Gryffindor.
让我暂时定义一个名为
And let me temporarily define a function called
格兰芬多 它接受了某种价值 就像学生S
is Gryffindor that takes in as a value something like a student S.
然后 让我们开始吧
And then, let's do this.
让我们继续说 如果S引用的房子等于格兰芬多
Let's go ahead and say if s quote unquote house equals equals Gryffindor,
然后继续前进 返回True
then go ahead and return true.
否则 继续并返回FALSE
Otherwise, go ahead and return false.
现在 我们以前见过像这样的条件句
Now, we've seen before conditionals like this
这些都是不必要的冗长
that are a bit unnecessarily verbose.
我不需要有条件 如果我已经
I don't need to have a conditional if I'm already
在这里问一个布尔问题
asking a Boolean question up here.
所以我实际上可以像我们过去做的那样收紧它
So I can actually tighten this up as we've done in the past
那么 学生的房子等于格兰芬多吗？
and just return does the student's house equal equal Gryffindor?
要么它是真的 要么不是 它是假的
Either it does and it's true, or it doesn't in it's false.
我不需要显式返回True或False
I don't need to explicitly return true or false.
我可以只返回那个布尔值
I can just return the value of that Boolean.
让我们现在就去做这件事
Let's go ahead now and do this.
和前面一样 我将创建一个变量
I'm going to create, as before, a variable
格兰芬多 这是我所有格兰芬多学生的名单
called Gryffindors, a list for all of my Gryffindor students
这一次等于调用Filter的结果
that equals to, this time, the result of calling filter.
筛选器在这里至少接受两个参数
Filter takes at least two arguments here,
其中之一是要调用的函数的名称是Gryffindor
one of which is the name of a function to call is Gryffindor.
我将把这个函数应用到这个序列的每个元素上
And I'm going to apply that function to each of the elements of this sequence
这里
here.
在本质上与地图如此相似 我传入了一个函数
So similar in spirit to map, I'm passing in a function
这将应用于序列中的每个元素
that's going to be applied to each of the elements in the sequence.
但是map为序列中的每个元素返回一个值
But map returns one value for each element in the sequence.
这就是我们强制所有单词都大写的方式
That's how we forced all of the words to uppercase.
但如果我想有条件地把一个学生包括在我的结果格兰芬多
But if I want to conditionally include a student in my resulting Gryffindors
列表中 我可以改用过滤器
list, I can use filter instead.
Filter期望它的第一个函数不是类似于str.upper的函数
Filter expects its first function to be not something like str.upper,
而是返回True或False的函数
but a function that returns true or false.
告诉我是否应该包括当前的学生
Tell me whether or not I should include or not include the current student
从最终名单中选出
from the final list.
问题是 他们住在格兰芬多吗？
And the question being asked is, do they live in Gryffindor?
我们正在查字典里的房门钥匙 寻找答案
We're checking the dictionary's house key for that answer.
因此 最终 我认为我们会得到非常相似的东西
And so, ultimately, I think we'll be left with something quite similar.
对于排序版本中的格兰芬多--我们来看看格兰芬多中的格兰芬多
For Gryffindor in the sorted version-- let's do for Gryffindor in Gryffindors,
那么让我们继续打印出现在的学生 格兰芬多的名字
let's go ahead then and print out the current students, Gryffindor name.
它现在还不会被解决
It's not going to be sorted just yet.
但是当我在这里运行这个版本的Python的Gryffindors.py并点击Enter时
But when I run this version here Python of Gryffindors.py and hit Enter,
我们又可以继续做生意了
we're back in business.
还没分类
It's unsorted.
但我们有赫敏、哈利和罗恩 但没有德拉科
But we have Hermione, Harry, and Ron, but not Draco.
如果你回想一下几周前 如果我们
And if you recall from a few weeks back, if we
如果你想要一个字典列表 我们也可以这样做
want to even a list of dictionaries, we can still do that too.
我可以把格兰芬多称为复数
I can call sorted on Gryffindors plural.
我可以传递一个密钥
And I can pass in a key.
这个密钥可以有一个匿名函数 也就是
And that key can have a anonymous function, a.k.a.
一个Lambda函数 它接受一个学生作为输入
A Lambda function, that takes in a student as input,
调用它 然后返回值的引号名称 如果我的目标是
call it s, and then returns the value s quote unquote name, if my goal is
根据学生自己的名字进行排序
to sort by, indeed, students own names.
如果我继续运行Gryffindors.py的Python
If I go ahead now and run Python of Gryffindors.py,
我看到了同样的学生名单
I see the same list of students.
但这一次 它的排序
But this time, it's sorted.
我们看到了两种解决这个问题的方法
So here we've seen two approaches to this particular problem
格兰芬多的学生
of Gryffindor students.
因此我们可以使用类似列表理解的东西
Whereby we can either use something like a list comprehension,
在这个列表理解中做一些过滤
and inside of that list comprehension do a bit of filtration,
包括一个if条件句
including an if conditional as I did.
或者我们可以采取更实用的方法
Or we can take a more functional approach
只需要使用这个过滤器函数
by just using this filter function, passing into it the function
我想为自己做这些决定
that I want to make these decisions for me,
然后只包括那些返回true的人
and then include only those for whom true is returned.
对这两种方法有什么问题吗？
Any questions on either of these two approaches?
是的
STUDENT: Yeah.
我只是有个问题如果我们写一个代码
I just had a question, that if we write a code
就像在以前的版本中 所有内容都被塞进一行
like in the previous version, where everything is stuffed into one line,
不会--
won't the--
如果我们检查代码的样式 那么它不会有问题吗？
if we check for the style of the code, then won't it have a problem with it
因为它的可读性更低
because it's less readable?
DAVID J. MALAN：像black这样的格式化程序也是如此
DAVID J. MALAN: So would a formatter like black
对这段代码的风格有问题吗
have a problem with the style of some of this code?
上一个 所有的东西都塞在一条线上
STUDENT: The previous one, where the everything was tucked into one line.
[插话的声音]
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
大卫·J·马兰：哦 一个好问题
DAVID J. MALAN: Oh, a good question.
像布莱克这样的人会对这段代码有意见吗？
Would something like Black have a problem with this code?
好吧 让我回到那个版本
Well, let me rewind to that version, which
使用了更长的列表理解
was using the somewhat longer list comprehension, which
看起来像是 如果我们回到足够远的地方 再给我几个解锁
looked like, if we go far enough back, give me a few more undoes,
它最终看起来是这样的
which looked like this ultimately.
让我继续在Gryffindors.py上运行Black
Let me go ahead and run Black on Gryffindors.py.
你会看到我实际上--它稍微重新格式化了一下
And you'll see that I actually-- it reformatted ever so slightly.
但我自己会主动解决这个问题
But I proactively fix this myself.
如果我这么做了 而且只用了一行
Had I done this and done it on just one line,
但我知道布莱克可能不喜欢这样 它会为我解决这个问题的
but I knew that Black might not like that, it would have fixed it for me.
因此 我只是在自己编写代码之前主动修复了它
So I just proactively fixed it before writing the code myself.
关于Gryffindors.py上的另一个问题怎么样？
How about time for one other question on Gryffindors.py
那么这种使用列表理解或过滤的方法呢？
and this approach of using a list comprehension or filter?
学生：是的
STUDENT: Yeah.
使用Filter时 不是调用Gryffindor函数
When using filter, instead of calling the function is Gryffindor,
你能把它放在滤镜里面吗？
can you use it right there inside filter?
大卫·J·马兰：你能用格兰芬多的功能吗？
DAVID J. MALAN: Can you use the function is Gryffindor?
所以你不会想这样称呼它的
So you don't want to call it like this.
因为你不会想要这样做的
Because you don't want to call it then.
您希望Filter为您调用函数 如果您是这个意思的话
You want filter to call the function for you, if that's what you mean.
所以我只用它的名字来传递它
So I pass it in only by its name instead.
学生：不 我的意思是 如果你能把报税表写成房子等于
STUDENT: No, I mean, if you can write the return as house equals
等于格兰芬多内线[INAUDIBLE]
equals Gryffindor inside [INAUDIBLE].
大卫·J·马兰：是的 确实如此
DAVID J. MALAN: Yes, indeed.
事实上 回想一下 我们以前确实使用过这些Lambda函数
In fact, so recall that we indeed used these Lambda functions way back
当我们想匿名传递一个又快又脏的函数时
when we wanted to pass in a quick and dirty function anonymously
以允许按词典的不同键进行筛选
to allow sorted to filter by a different key of a dictionary.
我们可以在这里这样做
We can do that here.
我实际上可以把它的本质理解为格兰芬多函数
I can actually take the essence of this is Gryffindor function.
我可以在筛选器调用中更改此函数的名称
I can change the name of this function in my filter call
作为另一个Lambda函数 像S一样传入参数
to be another Lambda function, passing in an argument like s,
就是这么回事
and returning exactly that.
我现在可以一起删除我的is Gryffindor函数
I can now delete my is Gryffindor function all together.
现在 当我运行Gryffindors.py的Python时
And now, when I run Python of Gryffindors.py,
我还是得到了同样的答案
I still get the same answer.
我并没有费心定义一个函数 只是为了使用它
And I've not bothered defining a function only to then use it
在一个且只有一个地方
in one and only one place.
好吧 让我也提议我们给你装备
Well, let me propose too that we equip you
使用另一个工具包工具 即词典
with one other tool for your toolkit, namely dictionary
理解也是如此
comprehensions as well.
诚然 语法开始变得更加奇怪
And admittedly, the syntax is starting to get even weirder.
但随着你对所有这些基本类型和其他类型越来越熟悉
But as you get more comfortable with all of these primitives and others,
这些只是您可以选择使用的工具 但也可能是强有力的工具
these are just tools that you can optionally but perhaps powerfully use
来解决未来的问题
to solve future problems down the road.
有了词典的理解 我们就有能力在飞行中创造
And with a dictionary comprehension, we have the ability to create on the fly
有键和一些值的词典 但没有
a dictionary with keys and some values without having
要做到这一点 需要创建一个空词典 并创建一个for循环
to do it old-school by creating an empty dictionary, and creating a for loop,
遍历该循环 并插入越来越多的键
and iterating over that loop, and inserting more and more keys
和值输入到字典中
and values into the dictionary.
我们宁可一次做完这一切
We can rather do it all at once.
所以事实上 让我回到VS代码这里
So in fact, let me go back to VS Code here.
现在让我向你求婚 我要这么做
And let me propose now that I do this.
让我继续 在这里以老式的方式开始 如下所示
Let me go ahead and initially do it the old-fashioned way here as follows.
让我继续 简化并处理掉这些房子
Let me go ahead and simplify and get rid of the houses
这样我们现在就可以把注意力集中在学生名单上了
all together so that we can focus for now just on a list of students' names.
我将继续运行学生
I'm going to go ahead and run students.
我将继续写学生等于引用 赫敏 引用
I'm going to go ahead and write students equals quote unquote Hermione, quote
引用哈里的话 这一次我们会把它缩短
unquote Harry, and we'll keep it even shorter this time,
引用罗恩的话 只有格兰芬多的那三个学生
quote unquote Ron, only those three students in Gryffindor.
我现在要像过去一样积极主动地
I'm going to now proactively as we've done in the past
给自己开一张空单 这样我就有东西可以积累了
give myself an empty list, so that I have something to accumulate
中提供了这个问题的一些答案
some answers to this problem in.
现在 我要做这样的事情
And now, I'm going to do something like this.
对于学生和学生 所以我可以迭代他们每一个人
For students and students, so I can iterate over each of them,
让我们继续 看看格兰芬多的名单
Let's go ahead and with the Gryffindors list
在它后面加上学生的名字
append to it the name of the student.
所以引用不带引号的名字 然后是学生 这
So quote unquote name and then student, which
确实是他们在名单上的名字
is indeed their name from that list.
现在 让我们继续 把这些学生都放在格兰芬多
And now, let's go ahead and just put these students all in Gryffindor.
我知道这三个学生在格兰芬多
I know these three students are in Gryffindor.
所以假设手头的问题是我
So suppose that the problem at hand is that I
我想建立一个只包含格兰芬多的词典列表
want to build up a list of dictionaries that only contains the Gryffindor
学生们
students.
因此 它在某种程度上是对以前版本的一种倒退
So it's sort of a step back from the previous version
在那里我已经有了名字和房子
where I already had the names and the houses.
现在 假设问题是我知道他们所有人的名字
For now, just assume that the problem is I have all of their names,
但我还没有学生词典本身
but I don't yet have the student dictionaries themselves.
因此 我正在重建我之前认为理所当然的同一结构
So I'm rebuilding that same structure that I previously took for granted.
现在 让我们继续 只是为了讨论
Now, let's go ahead and just for the sake of discussion just
把这些格兰芬多打印出来 这样我们就能看到我们建造了什么
print out these Gryffindors so we can see what we've built.
如果我在提示符中运行Gryffindors.py的Python
If I run Python of Gryffindors.py in my prompt,
我看到了一些隐晦的语法
I see a bit of a cryptic syntax.
但是 再说一次 寻找我们的小提示
But again, look for our little hints.
我在末尾有一个方括号 在开头有一个方括号
I've got a square bracket at the end and a square bracket at the beginning.
这表明 一如既往 这是一份名单
And that indicates, as always, this is a list.
然后我就有了一大堆花括号
I then have a whole bunch of curly braces
有一大堆被引用的钥匙
with a whole bunch of quoted keys.
按照惯例 它们碰巧是单引号
They happen to be single quotes by convention
在词典上使用打印时
when using print on a dictionary.
但这只是一个视觉指标 表明这是我的关键
But that's just a visual indicator that that is my key.
第一个值是赫敏
And the first value thereof is Hermione.
第二把钥匙是房子
Second key is a house.
这个值就是格兰芬多
This value thereof is Gryffindor.
然后是逗号 它将一个DICT对象与下一个DICT对象隔开
Then there's a comma, which separates one dict object from the next.
如果我们抛开哈利和格兰芬多
And if we look past Harry and Gryffindor,
哈利和格兰芬多和罗恩之间还有第二个逗号
there's a second comma which separates Harry and Gryffindor from Ron
格兰芬多也是
and Gryffindor as well.
因此 简而言之 以下是一些代码 通过这些代码我可以相当手动地
So in short, here is some code whereby I fairly manually
在原本为空的列表中使用for循环构建
built up with a for loop in an otherwise initially empty list
与之前相同的数据结构 只是为格兰芬多学生减去了Draco
the same data structure as before minus Draco just for Gryffindor students.
但这也是词典释义的地方
But here's where, again, with dictionary comprehensions
或者真的先列出理解 我们可以更简洁地做这件事吗？
or really list comprehensions first, can we do this a little more succinctly?
让我清除我的终端窗口
Let me clear my terminal window.
让我们去掉这个最初为空的列表和这个for循环
Let's get rid of this initially empty list and this for loop
添加 添加 添加到它上面
that appends, appends, appends to it.
我们就这么做吧
And let's just do this.
Gryffindors变量将等于下面的列表理解
A Gryffindors variable will equal the following list comprehension.
在这个列表里 我想要一本结构化的词典
Inside of that list, I want a dictionary structured
写着某人的名字和他们的名字
with someone's name and their name.
某个人的房子 只是现在 格兰芬多
Someone's house and only for now Gryffindor.
就是这样
And that's it.
但我想要这些花括号里的一个Dict对象
But I want one of these dict objects here in these curly braces
对于每一个学生来说 在学生中
for each student in students.
所以这里也是 在我用方括号列出的理解中
So here too, inside of my list comprehension with my square brackets,
我想要一个标明的物体--
I want an object as indicate--
我想要一本花括号标明的词典
I want a dictionary as indicated by the curly braces.
我希望每本词典都有两把钥匙--
I want each of those dictionaries to have two keys--
姓名和房屋 其值
name and house respectively, the values thereof
是学生的名字 这里只有Gryffindor
are the student's name from earlier here and Gryffindor only.
我想从哪些学生那里创建这些词典对象？
Which students do I want to create those dict objects from?
嗯 对于学生中的学生来说
Well, for student in students.
所以 再一次 在左边 我在最终列表中得到了我想要的东西
So again, on the left I have what I want in the final list.
在右边 我有一个循环 这一次 是无条件的
And on the right, I have a loop, and this time, no conditional.
我想把格兰芬多的这些学生都当作他们的家
I want all of these students in Gryffindor as their house.
现在 让我们再次打印这段代码 即Python of Gryffindors.py并按Enter键
Now, let's print this again, Python of Gryffindors.py and hit Enter.
现在 我们有了完全相同的产量
And now, we have the exact same output.
所以不是三行 而是一行
So instead of three lines it's just one.
乍一看 这本书有点神秘
It's a little more cryptic to read at first glance.
但一旦熟悉了列表理解和这类语法
But once familiar with list comprehensions and this sort of syntax,
这只是解决同样问题的另一种方式
it's just another way of solving that same problem.
如果我想要改变这一点并简化该怎么办？
What if I want to change this and simplify?
如果我不想要我现在有的词典列表 那该怎么办？
What if I don't want a list of dictionaries, which I now have.
同样 根据方括号 我这里有一个包含三个DICT对象的列表
Again, per the square brackets I have a list of three dict objects here.
如果我只想要一本更大的词典呢？
What if I just want one bigger dictionary
里面是一把钥匙 像赫敏冒号格兰芬多 哈里冒号
inside of which is a key like Hermione colon Gryffindor, Harry colon
格兰芬多 罗恩·科隆·格兰芬多
Gryffindor, Ron colon Gryffindor.
我不需要名单
I don't need a list.
我不需要每个学生单独使用物品
I don't need separate objects per student.
我只想要一本大词典
I just want instead one big dictionary where
钥匙是学生的名字和他们房子的价值
the keys are the students' names and the values of their house.
我想现在没有人会有
And I'm assuming for now no one's going to have
在这个世界上有一个相同的名字
the same first name in this world.
好吧 我能做到的
Well, I can do this.
让我在这里摆脱这一点 不是创建一个列表理解 但再次
Let me get rid of this here and not create a list comprehension, but again,
这就是所谓的词典理解
this thing known as a dictionary comprehension.
这里的视觉指示或差异
And the visual indicator or difference here
这一次 我们不再把它放在方括号里
is that instead of being square brackets on the very outside, this time
它会变成花括号
it's going to be curly braces instead.
在这些花括号里 我希望每个键都是什么？
So inside of these curly braces, what do I want every key to be?
我希望每个键都是学生的名字
I want every key to be the student's name.
我希望现在所有的价值都是格兰芬多的
I want every value for now to be Gryffindor.
我想为每一个学生做这些
And I want to do this for each student in students.
现在 事情变得非常有趣
And now, things are getting really interesting.
这是Python的另一种表现形式
And this is another manifestation of Python in some views being
从左到右都很清晰
very readable from left to right.
绝对需要练习和舒适
Absolutely takes practice and comfort.
但这是在创造一个名为格兰芬多的变量
But this is creating a variable called Gryffindor
这是一个字典 每个花括号都有一个
which is going to be a dictionary per these curly braces.
每个键都是某个学生的名字
Every key is going to be the name of some student.
每个值都将是格兰芬多
Every value is going to be Gryffindor.
什么学生的名字？
What names of what students?
好吧 这本字典的理解将是
Well, this dictionary comprehension will be
从学生名单中一次一个地构建
constructed from the list of students one at a time.
所以当我现在打印这个的时候 语法看起来会有点不同
So when I print this now, the syntax will look a little different
因为它不是字典对象的列表
because it's not a list of dictionary objects.
它本身只是一个更大的字典对象
It's just one bigger dictionary object itself.
但现在打印格兰芬多的人给了我赫敏·科隆格兰芬多 哈利·科隆
But now printing Gryffindors gives me Hermione colon Gryffindor, Harry colon
格兰芬多 还有罗恩·科隆·格兰芬多
Gryffindor, and Ron colon Gryffindor as well.
对于我们所说的字典解析 还有什么问题吗？
Any questions now on what we've called dictionary comprehensions as well?
有什么问题吗？
Any questions on here?
没有吗？
No?
好吧 让我们从Python的工具箱中介绍另一个函数
Well, let's introduce one other function from Python's toolkit followed
最后一个特点和繁荣
by one final feature and flourish.
然后你就可以走了
And then you're off on your way.
好吧 让我们继续回想一下
Well, let's go ahead and think back to this.
回想一下 我们之前有一个简单的学生名单
Recall some time ago that we had just a simple list of students
就像我们这里的赫敏哈利和罗恩
as we have here, Hermione, Harry, and Ron.
举个例子 很久以前 我们想要打印出来
And for instance, way back when, we wanted to print out,
比如说排名从一 二 三
for instance, their ranking from one, to two, to three.
不幸的是 当你为学生中的学生做这样的事情时
Unfortunately, when you do something like this for student in students,
你可以很容易地打印出学生的名字
you can print out the student's name quite easily.
当然 如果我使用Python的Gryffindors.py
Of course, if I do Python of Gryffindors.py,
我把赫敏、哈里、罗恩按同样的顺序排列
I get Hermione, Harry, Ron in that same order.
但我看不到任何数字排名
But I don't see any numerical rank.
我看不到一号、二号或三号
I see no number one, two, or three.
所以我也许可以用一种不同类型的for循环来做这件事
So I could maybe do this with maybe a different type of for loop.
与其这样 不如我试试这个吧？
Instead of this, why don't I try this?
所以也许我可以在学生名单的长度范围内--
So maybe I could do for i in the range of the length of the students list--
我们以前也做过类似的事情
and we've done something like this before.
然后我可以打印出我 我可以打印出学生的名字
And then I could print out i, and I could print out the student's name
通过在位置i处索引到该列表
by indexing into that list at location i.
好吧 这看起来像什么？
Well, what does this look like?
如果我运行Gryffindors.py的Python 它就很接近了
If I run Python of Gryffindors.py it's close.
但这些人不是程序员
But these aren't programmers.
他们不一定认为自己是零指数
They don't necessarily think of themselves as zero-indexed.
赫敏 他可能想成为第一个 而不是零
Hermione he probably wants to be first not zero.
那么我们怎么才能解决这个问题呢？
So how can we fix this?
井
Well.
只是一点算术
Just a little bit of arithmetic.
当然 我可以打印出来 再加上一个 然后是学生的名字
I could print out i plus one, of course, and then the student's name.
因此 如果我清除我的终端窗口并运行Gryffindors.py门禁的Python
So if I clear my terminal window and run Python of Gryffindors.py doorstop
再一次 现在我们有了这个枚举 一 二
once more, now we have this enumeration, one, two,
这些学生每人三个
three of each of these students.
但事实证明 Python实际上有
But it turns out that Python actually has
一直以来我都有另一个内置功能
had all this time another built-in function
你现在可能会觉得有用
that you might now find useful.
那就是列举
That is namely enumerate.
和枚举允许您解决这类问题
And enumerate allows you to solve this kind of problem
更简单地通过迭代某个序列
much more simply by iterating over some sequence
但并不是一次一个地找出每个值
but finding out not each value one at a time,
而是一次一个值和它的指数
but both the value one at a time and the index thereof.
它会同时返回两个答案
It gives you back two answers at once.
因此 如果我现在返回到VS代码 并采用这种方法
So if I go back to VS Code here now and take this approach,
我不需要做这个复杂的范围和长度
I don't need to do this complicated range, and length,
然后我就到处跑了.
and then i all over the place.
我可以更简洁地做到这一点
I can more succinctly do this.
我可以说我在枚举返回中逗号学生
I can say for i comma student in the enumerate return
重视学生的传授
value passing in students.
所以这给我返回了一个枚举 如果你愿意的话
So this gives me back an enumeration, if you will.
现在 我可以像以前一样打印i加1
And now, I can go about printing i plus 1 as before.
我可以把学生的照片打印出来
And I can print out the student.
因此 我不需要使用方括号I表示法来索引列表
So I don't need to index into the list with bracket i notation.
我不需要给Range打电话
I don't need to call range.
我不需要说长度
I don't need to call length.
同样 枚举采用像这些学生一样的一系列值
Again, enumerate takes a sequence of values like these students,
它允许我得到当前的索引0 1 2
and it allows me to get back the current index zero, one, two,
和现值分别为赫敏、哈里、罗恩
and the current value Hermione, Harry, Ron respectively.
所以现在 只要进一步收紧就行了
So now, just tighten things up further.
事实上 这一直是我们在这里的主题
And indeed, that's been our theme here.
我们能解决几周来一直在解决的问题吗？
Can we solve the same problems as we've been solving for weeks
但是 仅仅使用更多的这个工具包就可以收紧事情了吗？
but tighten things up using just more of this toolkit?
请允许我们为您的工具包配备最后一个工具
Allow us to equip you with one final tool for your tool kit,
也就是说 这种从函数生成Python值的能力
namely this ability to generate values in Python from functions.
这不是我们以前一定会遇到的问题
This is not a problem that we've necessarily encountered before.
但事实证明 如果您正在编写一个读取或生成
But it turns out, if you're writing a function that reads or generates
大量数据 你的函数 你的程序
lots of data, your function, your program,
您的计算机很可能会耗尽内存
your computer might very well run out of memory.
并且您的程序可能无法继续运行
And your program might not be able to run any further.
但事实证明这个问题有一个解决方案 那就是
But it turns out there's a solution to this problem that's
你的后口袋里可能有一些东西
something you might have in your back pocket,
尤其是如果你在这门课结束后开始计算相当多的数字
particularly if after this course you start crunching quite a few numbers
并分析更多的数据
and analyzing all the more data.
事实上 让我们回到这里的VS代码
In fact, let's go back to VS Code here.
让我们继续创建一个程序 它是
And let's go ahead and create a program that's
也许在一天中的这个时候很及时 特别是
perhaps timely at this time of day, particularly
根据你所在时区的不同 你可能会感到更加困倦
depending on your time zone, you might be feeling all the more sleepy.
但在美国 这是很常见的
But here in the US, it's quite common to be
在你挣扎的时候昏昏欲睡
lulled to sleep when you're struggling otherwise
通过在你的脑海中数羊
by counting sheep in your head.
通常 就像卡通中描述的那样 你
And typically, as depicted in cartoons, you
你可能会在脑海中看到一只羊跳过栅栏 然后是两只
might see in your mind's eye one sheep jumping over a fence, and then two,
然后是三只羊 然后是四只
and then three sheep, and then four.
然后 最终 你可能会觉得很无聊
And then, eventually, you presumably get so bored
数着这些绵羊 你真的睡着了
counting these sheep you actually do fall asleep.
因此 在VS代码中 让我们创建一个名为sleep.py的程序
So in VS Code here, let's create a program called sleep.py
这样我就可以打印出一些绵羊的数量
that allows me to print out some number of sheep
就像我在脑海里数着它们
as though I'm counting them in my mind's eye.
通过这个项目 让我们做到这一点
And via this program, let's do this.
让我们提示用户输入变量n 设置
Let's prompt the user for a variable n, setting
等于输入返回值的整数转换
it equal to the integer conversion of the return value of input,
询问用户n是什么？
asking the user what's n?
他们想试着数一下有多少只羊？
For how many sheep do they want to try counting?
然后 让我们在这里做一个熟悉的for循环
And then, let's do a familiar for loop here.
我们将一如既往地从零开始计数
And we'll start counting from zero as always.
所以我们首先会有零只羊 然后是一只羊 然后是两只羊
So we'll first have zero sheep, then one sheep, then two sheep, and so
对于该值n的范围内的i 为ON
on for i in the range of that value n.
继续打印出来吧
Go ahead and print out.
我会在这里粘贴一个代表一只羊乘以I的表情符号
And I'll paste here an emoji representing a sheep times i.
所以在第一次迭代中 我会看到零只绵羊
So the first iteration I'll see zero sheep.
在第二次迭代中 您将看到一个 然后是两个 然后是多少个
The second iteration you'll see one, and then two, and then however many
由n指定 最终减去1
specified by n ultimately minus one.
让我们在这里进入我的终端窗口 并运行sleep.py的Python
Let's go down into my terminal window here and run Python of sleep.py.
我应该看到 确实 在输入 比方说 三
And I should see, indeed, after typing in, say, three
对于我的n值 没有羊 然后是一只羊 然后是两只羊 依此类推
for my value of n, zero sheep, then one sheep, then two sheep, and so forth.
如果我把我的终端窗口做得更大
And if I make my terminal window even bigger here,
当然 我们可以做更多的事情 例如 输入10
we can, of course, do many more than this, typing in, for instance, 10.
你会看到随着时间的推移 我们会得到越来越多的羊
And you'll see that we get more and more sheep as time passes,
想必在我脑海中的想象会变得更加乏味
presumably becoming all the more tedious to envision in my mind's eye.
现在让我们继续练习我们所学到的东西
So let's now go ahead and practice what we've
当谈到这个程序的设计时 我一直在说教
been preaching when it comes to the design of this program
看看我们是否以及什么时候真的会遇到问题
and see if and when we actually run into a problem.
现在让我继续进行 并将所有这些放在一个主函数中
Let me go ahead here now and put all of this in a main function
通过在这里一如既往地定义Main
by defining main up here as always.
让我继续在这里缩进所有这些代码
Let me go ahead and indent all of this code here.
然后 让我像往常一样有条件地这样做
And then, let me just do this conditionally as always,
如果此文件的名称等于引号 则让我们继续
if the name of this file equals equals quote unquote main, let's go ahead
然后给Main打电话
and call main.
让我们确保我还没有打碎任何东西 尽管从功能上讲
Let's make sure I didn't break anything just yet, even though functionally this
应该是差不多的
should be nearly the same.
如果我输入三 我仍然是零 然后是一
And if I type in three, I still have zero, then one,
然后屏幕上出现了两只羊
then two sheep on the screen.
但我们一直习惯于创建助手函数
But we've been in the habit of course of creating helper functions
为了我们自己
for ourselves.
也就是说 将我们的代码分解为
That is, factoring our code in a way that
允许我们抽象出某些功能 比如生成
allows us to abstract away certain functionality, like generating
将一些绵羊分成不同的功能
some number of sheep into separate functions.
所以 第一 他们确实是抽象的
So that, one, they're indeed abstracted.
我们不再需要考虑它们是如何实施的
And we no longer have to think about how they're implemented.
我们甚至可以在项目中重复使用它们 就像在库中一样
And we can even reuse them in projects as in libraries.
但我们现在也有测试这些功能的习惯
But we've also been in the habit too of now testing those functions
与单元测试一样
as with unit tests.
所以我可能不应该把我所有的逻辑都放在Main里
So I probably shouldn't keep all of my logic anyway in main.
让我们把其中的一些因素考虑在内
And let's factor some of this out.
例如 如果我可以调用一个SHEEP函数 那不是很好吗
Wouldn't it be nice if I could, for instance, just call a sheep function
就像这里的这行代码一样
as by taking this line of code here.
与其只在这里打印 不如让我们打印
And instead of just printing it here, let's print
新函数的返回值为
out the return value of a new function called
告诉函数要打印多少个绵羊的绵羊 在本例中是我
sheep that tells the function how many sheep to print, i in this case.
让我们像往常一样在这里创建另一个名为SHEEP的函数
Let's go down as always and create another function here called sheep.
SHEEP函数现在将接受一个参数n 该参数指定
The sheep function now will take a parameter n that specifies
你想还几只羊？
how many sheep do you want to return.
因此 我们可以像单元测试一样进行测试
And so, that we can test this as with a unit test,
虽然我们不会在这里这样做 但让我继续 不打印绵羊的数量
though we won't do that here, let me go ahead and not print the number of sheep
就像通过副作用
as via a side effect.
但让我继续下去 让我把其中的一只羊
But let me go ahead and return one of those sheep times n
这样用户就可以得到一整串羊 这是
so that the user gets back a whole string of sheep that's
要打印的适当数字
the appropriate number to print.
所以从功能上来说 我认为我们还没有
So here too functionally, I don't think we've
从根本上改变了一切
changed anything too fundamentally.
Pyep.py类型3的Python仍然为我们提供了
Python of sleep.py typing three still gives us
零 然后是一只 然后是两只羊
zero, then one, and then two sheep.
但现在 我们至少有了一个专注于实施的框架
But now, we at least have a framework for focusing on the implementation
这种绵羊的功能
of this sheep function.
但现在它还是主要功能 所以有点不雅观
But it's a little inelegant now that it's still up to the main function
来完成这个迭代
to do this iteration.
我们在过去的第0周看到过
We've seen in the past way back in week zero,
定义一个真正处理
wouldn't it be nice to define a function that actually handles
返回整个字符串的过程
the process of returning the entire string
我们想要的 而不是一次只有一排羊
that we want rather than just one row of sheep at a time.
好吧 我想我们可以做到的
Well, I think we can do this.
为什么不让我按照下面的方法去换羊呢？
Why don't I go ahead and change sheep as follows.
让我继续这里 首先创建一群一开始是空的羊
Let me go ahead here and first create a flock of sheep that's initially empty
使用空列表
using an empty list.
那么对于n范围内的i 让我们继续并附加到该群中
Then for i in the range of n, let's go ahead and append to that flock,
例如 一只羊乘以I 所以I
for instance, one sheep times i, so that I
继续添加零只羊 然后是一只羊 然后是两只羊 然后
keep adding to this list zero sheep, then one sheep, then two sheep, then
三个 以此类推
three, and so forth.
然后 最终 我要把整群羊
And then, ultimately, I'm going to return the whole flock of sheep
立刻
at once.
所以这将返回相当于所有
So this is going to return the equivalent of all
这样 啊 Main就可以处理它们的印刷了
of those strings of sheep so that, ah, main can handle the printing thereof.
回到美因河畔 让我们开始吧
So back up here in main, let's do this.
每只羊怎么样 我就叫它S 因为是羊
How about for each sheep, I'll call it s since sheep
既是单数也是复数 对于S来说 n的绵羊 它再次返回
is both singular and plural, for s in sheep of n, which again returns
给我一份所有绵羊的名单 整个羊群 让我们打印出来
to me a list of all of the sheep, the whole flock, let's just print
S 每只羊一只一只地出来
out each sheep, s, one at a time.
所以 到目前为止 我认为这里一切都很好
So, so far so good here, I think.
让我继续运行leep.py的Python并按Enter键
Let me go ahead and run Python of sleep.py and hit Enter.
什么是n3
What's n three.
而且 这似乎仍然运作得很好
And that's still seems to work just fine.
但让我在这里有一点创意 看看
But let me get a little creative here and see
不只是我屏幕上的三只羊 可能还有10排羊
not just three sheep on my screen but maybe 10 rows of sheep.
而且 这似乎也很管用
And that too seems to work fine.
让我来点冒险 输入大概100只羊
Let me get a little more adventurous and type in maybe 100 sheep.
公平地说 它开始看起来很难看
And it's starting to look ugly, to be fair,
但它们都打印得很快
but they're all printing out pretty fast.
让我继续尝试 屏幕上可能有1000只羊
Let me go ahead and try again with maybe 1,000 sheep on the screen.
它们飞得很快
And they flew by pretty fast.
它仍然很凌乱
It's still pretty messy.
但他们都在那里
But they're all there.
我们可以把它们都加起来
We could count them all up.
不只是1000只羊 而是1万只羊怎么样？
How about not just 1,000 but 10,000 sheep?
嗯 这看起来也没问题
Well, that too seems OK.
它花了大约10倍的时间
It's taking like 10 times as long.
这就是为什么你会在屏幕上看到这个闪烁
And that's why you see this flickering on the screen.
所有的羊都还在印刷
All of the sheep are still printing.
但是 打印了大量的数据
But, but, but, it's a lot of data being printed.
如果我再坚持下去 我们就有希望
If I hang in there a little longer, hopefully we'll
看着一万只羊都过来了
see all 10,000 sheep coming to pass.
这是在这里的视频中 我们将加快时间 一个真正的在线
This is here in the video where we will speed up time, a real online.
天啊
Oh my God.
这是很多羊
This is a lot of sheep.
好了
There we go.
好的.
OK.
现在我所有的羊都被打印出来了
And now all of my sheep have been printed.
所以它看起来工作得很好
So it seems to be working just fine.
好吧 让我再大胆一点
Well, let me just be even more adventurous
好吧 让我试试运气
and, OK, let me try my luck.
让我试试 这次一百万只羊 按回车键怎么样？
Let me try, how about one million sheep this time and hit Enter?
Ha.
有什么东西坏了
Something's no longer working.
在我们等待剧透的同时 有没有人
While we wait for a spoiler here, does anyone
有没有直觉告诉我为什么我的程序突然停止打印绵羊了？
have any intuition for why my program suddenly stopped printing sheep?
这个版本出了什么问题 我在这里生成
What is going wrong in this version, wherein I'm generating
一大群羊吗
this really big flock of sheep?
我们可能已经耗尽了内存或计算能力
STUDENT: We might have run out of memory or computation power.
DAVID J. MALAN：是的
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah.
也许我们真的在挑战我的Mac的极限
So maybe we're actually pushing the limits of my Mac,
我的PC 我的云服务器的内存或CPU 计算机的大脑
my PCs, my cloud server's memory or CPU, the brains of the computer's
因为它只是试图产生
capabilities because it's just trying to generate
数量巨大的羊的名单 一百万只
massive, massive, massive lists of sheep, one million
每一排都有很多羊
of those rows of sheep, each of which has a huge number of sheep.
看起来我的电脑真的很难用
And it seems that my computer here is honestly just really struggling.
现在这真的很不幸
And this is really unfortunate now.
因为看起来即使这个项目很明显
Because it would seem that even though this program clearly
对1,000只羊来说效果很好 1万只羊 一次
works pretty well for 1,000 sheep, 10,000 sheep, once
你跨过了某个门槛 它就完全停止工作了
you cross some threshold, it just stops working altogether.
或者它只是需要太长的时间 该程序是有用的了
Or it just takes way too long for the program to be useful anymore.
但这似乎有点傻 因为理论上 我绝对应该
But this seems a little silly, because theoretically, I should absolutely
如果我只打印一只羊
be able to print all of these same sheep if I just printed one
然后马上印两张 然后印三张 四张 五张
right away, then print two right away, then print three, then four, then five.
看起来这个问题的本质 如果我回到我的代码
It seems that the essence of this problem, if I go back to my code,
是根据我的最佳实践 我试图实践我所宣扬的
is that per my best practices that I'm trying to practice what I'm preaching,
似乎最根本的问题是
it seems that the fundamental problem is that I've
通过创建一个叫做sheep的辅助函数
modularized my code by creating this helper function called sheep,
他一生的目的就是做一代一代的绵羊
whose purpose in life is to do all of the generation of sheep
然后一次把它们全部送回来
and then return all of them at once.
这不是更好吗？
Wouldn't it be better--
我真的能听到我的风扇现在就开着
and I can actually hear my fan turning on now even just
试图生出这些绵羊--
trying to generate these sheep--
把羊印成1 2 3 不是更好吗？
wouldn't it be better then to just print the sheep one, two, three,
一次四个？
four at a time?
嗯 我们可以这么做
Well, we could do that.
但这确实是一种倒退
But that's really a step backwards.
这与过去几周吸取的所有教训相矛盾
That rather contradicts all of the lessons learned of the past few weeks.
通常情况下 不把所有东西都放在Main中是一件好事
Where generally not putting everything in main is a good thing.
通常有一个附加功能 然后可以单独测试
Generally having an additional function that you can then test separately
使用单元测试是一件好事
with unit tests is a good thing.
我们真的需要放弃所有这些最佳实践吗
Do we really need to give up all of those best practices just
打印出一些绵羊 然后在这里睡着？
to print out some sheep and here fall asleep?
嗯 事实证明这个问题是有解决方案的
Well, it turns out there's a solution to this problem,
也就是以这些生成器的形式出现在Python中
and namely in the form of these generators in Python.
您可以将函数定义为生成器
You can define a function as a generator,
因此 它仍然可以为您的用户生成海量数据
whereby it can still generate a massive amount of data for your users.
但您可以让它一次只返回其中的一小部分数据
But you can have it return just a little bit of that data at a time.
您自己也可以用几乎相同的方式实现代码
And you yourself can implement the code in almost the same way.
但你不必担心太多的东西会一下子被退回
But you don't have to worry about too much getting returned all at once.
与Python的所有功能一样 这两个功能都有文档记录
These two, like all features of Python, are documented
在其中的官方文件中
in the official documentation therein.
但你最终会发现 这一切归根结底都是这个关键字
But what you'll find, ultimately, that it all boils down to this keyword here,
投降
yield.
到目前为止 我们一直在制作函数
Up until now, when we've been making functions,
我们一直在定义返回值的函数 如果有的话
we have been defining functions that return values, if at all,
使用关键字Return
using the keyword return.
事实上 如果我们回到我们这里的代码
And indeed, if we go back to our code here,
这正是我一直在等待的
that's exactly what I've been waiting for.
我一直在等着马上把整个鸟群送回来
I've been waiting to return the whole flock at once.
不幸的是 如果你等得太久 而我们已经得到了
Unfortunately, if you wait too long, and here we have it,
我的节目被引用了被扼杀了
my program was quote unquote killed.
也就是说 我的计算机已经厌倦了有多少内存和CPU
That is to say, my computer got so fed up with how much memory and CPU
它试图使用它 只是说 不 你根本不会跑
it was trying to use it just said, nope, you're not going to run at all.
这是不幸的
And that's unfortunate.
现在我的程序不再适用于大量数字
Now my program no longer works for large numbers
睡眠--绵羊 如果我真的有麻烦 那就不好了
of sleeps-- sheeps, which is not good if I'm really having trouble
某天晚上睡着了
falling asleep some night.
那么 我该如何使用Year来解决这个问题呢？
So how can I use yield to solve this problem instead?
好吧 那就让我来吧
Well, let me do this.
与其在这个名为羊群的大名单上建立这个庞大的绵羊名单
Instead of building up this massive list of sheep in this big list called flock,
让我们就这样做吧
let's just do this instead.
让我继续下去 简化整个函数
Let me go ahead and simplify this whole function
如下所示 由此我对n的范围内的i进行迭代
as follows, whereby I iterate for i in the range of n.
然后在每一次迭代中 在过去 我
And then on each iteration, in the past I
可能倾向于使用Return和Return
might have been inclined to use return and return
就像一只羊乘以我
something like one sheep times i.
但这在这里行不通
But this won't work here.
因为如果你想要一百万只羊而你
Because if you want a million sheep and you
开始一个for循环 表示i在一百万的范围内
start a for loop saying for i in the range of a million,
您将立即返回意外的零只绵羊
you're going to return accidentally zero sheep right away.
然后 这个功能基本上是无用的
And then this function is essentially useless.
您不应该在这样的循环中间返回值
You shouldn't return a value in the middle of a loop like this
因为你不会得到这些后续迭代中的任何一个
because you're not going to get to any of these subsequent iterations
循环中的
of the loop.
它会迭代一次 然后砰的一声 你就会返回
It's going to iterate once, and boom, you return.
但多亏了Python中的另一个关键字
But thanks to this other keyword in Python
名为Year 您可以告诉Python实际上只返回一个
called yield, you can tell Python to effectively return just one
从该循环中一次取值
value at a time from this loop.
所以如果我回到我的代码的这个版本
So if I go back to this version of my code here.
我说不是回报 而是收益 这就像是说一次返回一个值
And I say not return but yield, this is like saying return one value at a time,
一次返回一个值 一次返回一个值
return one value at a time, return one value at a time.
For循环将继续工作 我将
The for loop will keep working and I will
继续从零到一 到二 一直到一百万
keep counting from zero, to one, to two, all the way up toward one million.
但每一次 这个函数都会给你
But each time, the function is just going to hand you
回溯一小段数据
back a little piece of data.
可以说 它只会产生一小部分数据
It's going to generate, so to speak, just a little bit of that data,
并不是所有的数据一次都有
not all of the data at once.
这很好
And that's good.
因为我的计算机有相当大的内存 当然足够容纳
Because my computer has a decent amount of RAM, certainly enough to fit
一排羊
one row of sheep.
显然 它没有足够的内存来容纳它
It just doesn't have enough memory to fit, apparently,
一百万排这么多的羊
one million rows of so many sheep.
所以现在 如果我在终端窗口运行sleep.py的Python
So now, if I go to my terminal window and run Python of sleep.py and hit
输入 n是什么？
Enter, what's n?
三个也行 零个 一个 两个.
Three would still work-- zero, then one, and then two.
让我继续增加这个的大小 然后运行Python的sleep. py
Let me go ahead and increase the size of this here and run Python of sleep.py.
让我们像以前一样尝试一百万 然后按Enter键
Let's try one million as before and hit Enter.
现在我马上看到了结果
And now I immediately see results.
我不认为我们会等到所有这些羊
I don't think we'll wait for all of these sheep
打印出来 因为那样的话 我们就都睡着了
to be printed, because then we will literally all be asleep.
但是你会注意到现在程序没有挂起
But what you'll notice happening now is the program is not hanging,
可以这么说
so to speak.
不是等待 等待 思考 思考
It's not waiting, and waiting, and thinking, and thinking,
并试图一次产生整个群体
and trying to generate the entire flock at once.
它只是一次产生一排羊
It's just generating one row of sheep at a time.
它在屏幕上闪烁 因为它们太多了
And it's flickering on the screen because there are so many of them.
这都要归功于屈服
And that's all thanks to yield.
它一次生成一点数据 而不是一次生成全部数据
It's generating a little bit of data at a time, not all at once.
现在对这个叫做发电机的功能有什么问题吗？
Any questions now on this feature called generators?
有什么问题吗？
Any questions at all?
再加一个术语到这个混合体中 只是为了让你听到它
To add one more piece of terminology to the mix, just so you've heard it.
这里的相同功能是返回我们现在在技术上称为迭代器的东西
This same feature here is returning what we'll technically now call an iterator.
Yield返回一个迭代器
Yield is returning an iterator that allows
你自己的代码 你自己的for循环
your own code, your own for loop in main to iterate over these generated values
一次一个
one at a time.
问：这个收益率实际上是如何在引擎盖下工作的？
STUDENT: How does this yield actually works under the hood?
我的意思是 它使用多线程吗？
I mean, is it using multithreading?
DAVID J. MALAN：你可以把它的实现
DAVID J. MALAN: You can think of the implementation
在这个意义上是异步的
as being asynchronous in this sense.
函数立即返回一个值
Whereby the function is returning a value immediately and then
然后再还给你一个
subsequently giving you back another one as well.
在引擎盖下面 到底发生了什么
Underneath the hood, what's really happening
发电机只是为你保留状态
is the generator is just retaining state for you.
它不会从上到下运行整个循环
It does not going to run the entire loop from top to bottom
然后返回一个值
and then return a value.
它将进行一次迭代并产生一个结果
It's going to do one iteration and yield a result.
如果你愿意的话 Python会暂停这个函数
And the Python for you is going to suspend the function, if you will,
但请记住它是在什么迭代上
but remember on what iteration it was.
所以当你下一次迭代它的时候
So the next time you iterate over it, as is
在Main中的for循环中会反复发生
going to happen again and again in this for loop in main,
你一次又一次地得到另一个值
you get back another value again and again.
所以产生回报 实际上 这个东西叫做迭代器
So yield returns, indeed, this thing called an iterator.
该迭代器可以像在循环中一样一次一个元素地跳过
And that iterator can be stepped over as in a loop one element at a time.
但在语言方面 Python会为您处理所有这些
But the language, Python handles all of that for you
这样你就不需要自己做所有底层的管道工作了
so that you don't need to do all of the underlying plumbing yourself.
关于这些生成器和积分器的另一个问题如何？
How about time for one other question on these generators and integrators
当我们的羊继续飞过的时候？
as our sheep continue to fly by?
学生：所以如果每一次迭代 程序
STUDENT: So if every iteration, the program
是否会将内存归还给系统 这样程序就不会崩溃？
will return the memory to the system so the program will not crash?
大卫·J·马兰：正确
DAVID J. MALAN: Correct.
在每次迭代中 它只返回一个绵羊字符串 即
On each iteration, it's only returning the one string of sheep that's
适用于i的当前值
appropriate for the current value of i.
它并不是试图返回相同的所有100万行
It is not trying to return all million rows of the same.
因此 它使用的内存量只有百万分之一
And therefore, it uses really one millionth the amount of memory,
尽管这有点过于简单化了
although that's a bit of an oversimplification.
好的
All right.
当这些绵羊继续飞过
As these sheep continue to fly across the,
现在让我继续 打断一下
screen let me now go ahead and interrupt this,
过去 您可能不得不在自己的代码中使用无限循环
as you might have had to in the past with infinite loops in your own code.
尽管这不是无限的 但它真的很长--控制
Even though this isn't infinite, it's just really long-- control
C会用你的键盘中断那个程序 给我
C will interrupt with your keyboard that program, giving me
控制我的电脑
back control of my computer.
好了 我们现在是在CS50的结尾 S介绍
Well, here we are at the end of CS50's Introduction
到使用Python语言编程
to Programming with Python.
如果今天 特别是所有的日子 感觉像是真正的升级
And if today in particular of all days felt like a real escalation
很快 我就会意识到这些真的--
real quickly, realize that these are really--
这些只是工具包中的附加工具 或许是可选工具
these are just additional perhaps optional tools in your toolkit
你可以在过去学到的所有教训上再加一笔
that you can add to all of the past lessons learned.
因此 当您退出本课程并处理其他课程或项目时
So that as you exit from this course and tackle other courses or projects
你自己 你有更多的心理模型
of your own, you have all the more of a mental model
更像是一个工具箱 用来解决同样的问题
and all the more of a toolbox with which to solve those same problems.
如果我们现在回想一下就在几周前
If we think back now just a few weeks ago,
这可能是我们重点关注的函数和变量
it was probably in our focus on functions and variables
你刚开始挣扎的时候
that you first started struggling.
但现在回想起来 如果你回顾这些问题
But now in retrospect, if you look back at those problems
而那些相同的问题集 几率也是相同的问题
and those same problems sets, odds are those same problems
现在对你来说太容易了
would come all too easily to you now.
条件句是这门课的下一步 其中
Conditionals was the next step in the class, wherein
我们给了你提问和获得答案的能力
we gave you the ability to ask questions and get answers
因此在您的代码中有条件地执行操作
and therefore do things conditionally in your code.
我们今天又绕了一圈
We came full circle today.
你可以看到 你现在可以使用相同类型的条件句
And you can see that you can now use those same kinds of conditionals
现在用清单理解和词典来做一些更花哨的事情
now to do fancier things with list comprehension and dictionary
理解和类似的东西
comprehensions and the like.
当然 几个星期以来 循环已经无处不在 包括今天
Loops, of course, have been omnipresent now for weeks, including today
当我们建造那些相同的结构时
as we built up those same structures.
当然 有些事情可能会出错
And of course, something can go wrong.
异常和异常处理是我们的机制
And exceptions and exception handling was our mechanism
不仅用于捕获代码中的错误 还用于引发您自己的异常
for not only catching errors in code but also raising your own exception.
因此 如果您正在为其他人编写代码奠定基础
So that if you're laying the foundation to write code for other people,
就像在库的形式中一样 您也可以这样做
as in the form of libraries, you can do that too.
当然 库不仅可以使用 而且现在还可以自己编写
Libraries, of course, are things you can not only use but now write on your own,
它可以是一个小模块或整个代码包
be it a small module or whole package of code
你想与世界各地的人分享的东西
that you want to share with others around the world.
更好的是 你能为你自己的代码 你的库
And even better, can you write tests for your own code, for your libraries,
对于其他人的代码也是如此
for other's code as well.
所以最终 你可以更有信心
So that ultimately, you can be all the more confident
今天不仅你的代码是正确的
that not only your code is correct today.
但如果您明天对代码进行更改
But if you make a change to your code tomorrow,
你没有打碎任何东西 至少根据你的测试
you haven't broken anything, at least according to your tests
如果他们继续通过的话
if they continue to pass.
与此同时 文件I/O是现在存储的一种方式
File I/O though, meanwhile, was a way of now storing
数据不仅存在于计算机内存中 就像所有这些绵羊一样
data not just in the computer's memory like all of these sheep,
但实际上是将东西持久地、长期地存储到磁盘上
but actually storing things persistently, longer term to disk,
在CSV或更像二进制文件(如图像)中
being in a CSV or something more like a binary file like an image.
使用正则表达式 您就可以
With regular expressions, you then had the ability
表示模式并实际验证数据或提取数据
to express patterns and actually validate data or extract data
从信息中
from information.
如今 当世界上如此多的人
All the more of a useful technique nowadays when so much of the world
正在尝试分析和处理大规模的数据 其中一些
is trying to analyze and process data at scale, some of which
可能实际上从一开始就相当混乱
might in fact be quite messy from the get-go.
然后 当然 最近的面向对象编程
And then, of course, most recently, object-oriented programming,
解决同类问题的机会
an opportunity to solve the same kinds of problems
但以一种略有不同的视角 一种
but with a slightly different perspective, a way
来封装和表示真实世界的实体 这一次是在代码中
to encapsulate and to represent real world entities, this time in code.
今天 当然 还有很多其他的工具
And today, of course, et cetera with so many other tools
你可以补充说 它不一定属于之前的任何一项
that you can add that didn't necessarily fall under any of those earlier
但雨伞是有用的功能和数据类型
umbrellas but are useful functions, and data types,
和技术 再一次 在你的后口袋里
and techniques just to have, again, in your back pocket
还有其他解决问题的机制
as yet other mechanisms for solving problems as well.
不仅让每个人都睡着了 我还想了另一种方式来结束
Not just putting everyone to sleep, but I thought another way to end
试着一起写最后一个程序可能会更有说服力
might be a little more vocally to try writing one final program together,
这一次使用了我们过去见过的库 也使用了其他库
this one using a library we've seen in the past, as well as one other.
我擅自在我的电脑上安装了一个文本到语音库
I've taken the liberty of installing a text to speech library on my computer
这里
here.
接下来 我可能会打开一个名为say.py的新文件
And I'm going to go ahead, perhaps, and open a new file here called say.py
在VS代码中
in VS Code.
接下来 我要先介绍一下我们自己的朋友 进口牛仔
And I'm going to go ahead here and first import our own friend, import cowsay.
我将在这里导入这个新的库 导入pyttsx3
And I'm going to import this new library here, import pyttsx3,
Python文本到语音库
the Python text to speech library.
现在 根据我事先读过的文件
And now, per its documentation, which I read in advance,
我将在这里为自己创建一个变量
I'm going to go ahead and create a variable for myself here,
引擎等于pyttsx3 init以初始化用于文本到语音的库
engine equals pyttsx3 init to initialize that library for text to speech.
然后 我将询问用户 我希望听到什么？
I'm going to then ask the user, well, what do I want to hear spoken?
我可能会做这样的事
And I might do something like this.
名为this的变量等于INPUT的返回值
A variable called this equals the return value of input.
这将是我简单的问题
What's this shall be my simple question.
这一次 我将把它作为一根弦
And I'm going to keep it this time as a string.
我们已经看到了如何使用牛仔
We've seen how to use cowsay.
我们可以做牛仔 牛的这个
We can do cowsay.cow of this.
原来这个新的库可以让我使用自己的引擎
Turns out this new library can allow me to use its own engine
我也是这么说的
to say this as well.
但是 最终 我将不得不运行引擎 运行和等待
But then, ultimately, I'm going to have to run the engine.runAndWait,
以防它是一个很长的短语或句子要说
just in case it's a long phrase or sentence to be said.
但仅此而已
But that's it.
在短短八行代码中 我不仅显然将拥有一头牛
In just eight lines of code, not only am I apparently going to have a cow
出现在屏幕上 关闭我们现在 但也一些合成的文本
appear on the screen to close us out now but also some synthesized text.
最终 我们希望通过这门课程 您不仅学习了Python
Ultimately then we hope with this course that you've not only learned Python,
你不仅学会了编程
that you've not only learned programming,
但你真的学会了如何解决问题
but you've really learned how to solve problems,
以及最终如何自学新的语言
and ultimately how to teach yourself new languages.
有趣的是 我自己也是几年前才学会的
Funny enough, I myself only learned Python just a few years ago.
尽管我确实查阅了一些正式的文件和资源
And even though I certainly went through some formal documentation and resources
在网上 我主要学到了我现在知道的甚至是
online, I mostly learned what I know now and even what
我不得不通过问很多问题来再次学习今天的课程
I had to learn again for today by just asking lots of questions,
无论是谷歌的朋友 还是比我更精通这门语言的朋友们
be it of Google, or friends, who are more versed in this language than I.
因此 拥有这种本能 拥有这种词汇[INAUDIBLE]
And so, having that instinct, having that vocabulary [INAUDIBLE]
向其他人提问以搜索问题的答案
which to ask questions of others to search for answers to questions,
现在 您完全有了足够的Python基础
you absolutely now have enough of a foundation in Python
和编程让你自己离开并站立起来
and programming to go off and stand on your own.
所以你当然可以--我们欢迎并鼓励你去
So you can certainly-- and you're welcome and encouraged to go
上并学习其他课程 特别是关于Python和编程的课程
on and take other courses in Python and programming specifically.
但更好的是 越快越好
But better still, as quickly as you can, is
去找一些个人感兴趣的项目
to find some project that's personally of interest that
使用Python或其他某种语言
uses Python or some other language.
因为至少从我自己的经验来看 我往往学得最好
Because at least from my own experience, I tend to learn best
我希望你也能通过实际应用这些技能来实现
and I hope you might too by actually applying these skills.
不是针对课堂上的问题 而是真的
Not to problems in the classroom, but really truly
真实世界中的问题
to problems in the real world.
请允许我在这里查看我的全屏终端窗口
Allow me with all that said to look at my full screen terminal window here.
运行Say.py的Python 最后一次祈祷
Run Python of say.py, crossing my fingers one final time in
希望我没有犯任何错误或错误
hopes that I've not made any mistakes or bugs.
现在我们开始吧
And here we go.
Pay.py的巨蟒提示我 这是什么？
Python of say.py prompting me, what's this?
我们就在这里结束吧
How about we end on this note here.
电脑：这是CS50
COMPUTER: This was CS50.